Changes to the PM Act FAQ
Date of refresh: 23/27/2012
.accordion-toggle {cursor: pointer; margin: 0;} .accordion-content {display: none;} .accordion-content.default {display: block;} 1. What kind of non-profit units will be able to reduce the calculated taxable profit from the tax year 2019? Under Article 463 of the Criminal Code Part 1 Non-profit units for the tax year 2019 and subsequent tax periods calculated in Article 11 of the LPC ...
07/27/2012
Changes to LIPM Laws FAQ
Date of refresh: 23/27/2012
.accordion-toggle {cursor: pointer; margin: 0;} .accordion-content {display: none;} .accordion-content.default {display: block;} 1. In which cases, persons from 2019 1 January will not be able to obtain the beneficiary's status or will it be possible to remove him from the beneficiaries? Persons who do not comply with Article 401 of the MAA. set the minimum criterion for a reliable taxpayer from 2019 1 January will not be able to obtain the beneficiary's status, and ...
07/27/2012
Klaipėda Tourist Information Center organizes the competition
Date of refresh: 22/08/2012
Type II of the Control Division II of the Audit Department of Legal Personnel, Chief Specialist Level A, Level 11, Level A: E-mail: (via the VATIS Selection Module) Telephone: (8 46) 469 319 E- mail: inga.vanceviciute@vmi.lt
Changes to GPM Laws FAQ
Date of refresh: 2018-07-20
.accordion-toggle {cursor: pointer; margin: 0;} .accordion-content {display: none;} .accordion-content.default {display: block;} 1. What is the income tax rate applicable to wages? 20 percent - salary (with bonuses, bonuses), the annual amount of which does not exceed 120 VUU (2019), 84 VMU (2020) - 60 VUU (2021) 27% - for the salary part exceeding 120 VMU (2019), 84 VMU (2020) -...
2018-07-20
Showing 1 - 5 of 3 389 results.
Items on page 5
First Prev Next End
Date of update: 2015-03-25
Registration number KD-5358
Pension funds established in accordance with the Law on the reform of the pension system of the Republic of Lithuania, the Law on Pension Accumulation of the Republic of Lithuania and the Law on the Supplementary Voluntary Pension Accumulation of the Republic of Lithuania; investment funds established in accordance with the Law on Collective Investment Undertakings of the Republic of Lithuania are non-taxable units, therefore these funds for securities ) Dividends received from a pension or investment fund invested are not subject to corporate income tax.
Therefore, a Lithuanian unit, paying dividends (or other distributed profits) to a pension fund or an investment fund which are not taxable units, from the income tax on such dividends shall be entered into pursuant to Article 33 of the Commercial Code. in accordance with the established procedure, can not be deducted and paid into the budget, but declared in the income tax return in Annex E of PLN 204.
Similarly, a pension accumulation company or management company from dividends received from a pension fund or investment fund from foreign units should not calculate and pay the corporate income tax and provide a dividend income tax return (FR0640).
However, if from a mutual fund that is not a taxable person, dividends are paid out to its participants (units) in accordance with the rules of this fund, in which case the investment fund's management company (or the fund's depositary through which the profit is allocated) as a person deducting the tax from Dividends paid to the participants in the investment fund (units) must deduct and pay the income tax in accordance with the procedure set out in Articles 33 and 34 of the LCI and submit a declaration of dividend income tax.
The deducted dividends paid to the participants in the investment fund (units) and the amount of corporation tax paid to the budget can not be reduced by the income tax payable by the management company during the tax period of Article 33 of the Commercial Register. In accordance with paragraph 3.
Important Dividends received from investment companies with variable capital operating under the Law on Collective Investment Undertakings of the Republic of Lithuania are taxed from the tax period commenced in 2004, irrespective of whether their management of assets has been transferred or transferred to the management company.
Legislation
Article 32 of the LRS PMI
Article 33 of the LRS PMI
Article 34 of the LRS PMI
Law of the Republic of Latvia on Pension System Reform
LRS Pension Accumulation Act
LRS Supplementary Voluntary Pension Accumulation Act
Law on Collective Investment Undertakings