2017-05-02 16:36:00
Mindaugas Samkus, BNS
Text Size:
Print
Jonava Fertilizer Producer Achema, managed by Achema Group, one of the largest concern in Lithuania, will pay 17 million euros of dividends this year.
The company announced on its website that on April 14 the shareholders decided to pay EUR 25.9 per share. Last year Achema paid out 30 million euros for dividends.
In the 2016 activity report submitted to the Center of Registers, Achema points out last year's net profit of 5.269 million euros - 12.4 times less than in 2015 (65.221 million euros), its revenue amounted to 359.253 million euros - 36.1 per cent. less (562,583 million euros). Achema plans to reach 411 million euros this year, and will invest 12 million euros.
100 percent Fertilizer producer shares are managed by the Achema Group. The main shareholder of the concern, Lyda Lubienė, with her daughter, Victoria, manages more than 52 percent. shares. 11.6 percent owned by Jurati Zadeikiene, 7% - Jonai Sirvydys and Marija Kaminskienė, 4.75 per cent. - Arunas Laurinaitis, 0.5% - Adam Jadeika.


Ads
Notify me of updates to
news
Portal
guest
Ask
a specialist
Discussions
weather
TV
the program
Dating
Games
Horoscopes
Novelty
RSS feed
Facebook
Twitter