To improve the quality of browsing, we use cookies on this site. If you agree, click "I agree", otherwise go ahead and browse. You can cancel your consent at any time by changing your browser settings and deleting saved cookies. Learn more about our cookie policy here.
30 April 2018
INVL Baltic Real Estate earned a net profit of 0.7 million euros in the first quarter
The consolidated net profit of real estate investment company INVL Baltic Real Estate during the first quarter of this year was 0.7 million euros and, compared to the corresponding period of 2017, increased by 95%. The consolidated equity value of the company at the end of March amounted to EUR 32.85 million. The equity value per share was EUR 2.50 and, compared with the end of the first quarter of last year, increased by 12.6%. (At the end of the first quarter of 2017, the equity value per share was EUR 2.39, as well as the assessed dividends paid).
2018-04-23
INVL Baltic Real Estate will invest in commercial real estate in May
Investing in real estate company INVL Baltic Real Estate will open a public offering on May 2. According to the public offering prospectus of the company announced today, the distribution of shares will take place in three stages, and in total until 13 December, investors will be offered to acquire up to 22%. or 2.893 million shares of the company currently owned by Invalda INVL. The bonds of the public offering of INVL Baltic Real Estate were approved by the Bank of Lithuania on April 23.
April 4, 2018
A higher loan limit will allow INVL Baltic Real Estate to balance its capital structure
Investments in real estate company INVL Baltic Real Estate signed an agreement with Šiaulių bankas on increasing the loan limit from EUR 18.2 to EUR 24 million and more favorable loan terms.
2018-03-26
INVL Baltic Real Estate for 2017 will pay 1.71 million euros in dividends
Investments in real estate company INVL Baltic Real Estate for 2017 will give shareholders a dividend of 1.71 million euros or 0.13 euros per share. Today's General Meeting of Shareholders approved this decision. Dividends will be paid within a month from this decision, and will be available to investors who will be INVAL Baltic Real Estate shareholders at the end of April 10 this year.
03/22/2012
"INVL Baltic Real Estate" in 2017 earned a net profit of 3.58 million euros
The consolidated net profit of real estate investment company INVL Baltic Real Estate in 2017 amounted to 3.58 million euros and was 20.6%. lower than in the corresponding period in 2016. The consolidated equity value of the Company in 2017. At the end of December, it amounted to 33.86 million euros. The equity value per share (recalculated according to the current number of shares and nominal value of the share) was EUR 2.57 and grew by 11% per year. (At the end of 2016, the equity value per share was EUR 2.36, as well as the payment of dividends of EUR 0.06 per share).
24/01/2012
Trading in INVL Baltic Real Estate shares is updated
Upon completion of the procedures for changing the nominal value of the shares, the sale of real estate investment in the shares of the company INVL Baltic Real Estate is renewed from January 25. Trading in shares was suspended by changing the company's Articles of Association and the nominal value of the INVL Baltic Real Estate share provided by them and the number of shares issued by the company.
29 January 2017
INVL Baltic Real Estate increased its dividend by 2.2 times
The real estate investment company has raised its dividend dividend policy by more than two times, from 0.012 to 0.026 euros per share, in the company INVL Baltic Real Estate. It was also decided that, if the decision was approved by the Bank of Lithuania, five times - to increase the nominal value of the company to 1.45 euros, this decision would come into force with the approval of the Bank of Lithuania. These decisions were approved today by the company's shareholders' meeting.
2017-12-21
INVL Baltic Real Estate forecasts a rapid increase in net rental income
Investments in real estate company INVL Baltic Real Estate have announced forecasts for net operating income of € 2.57 million in 2017, which will be 28%. higher than in 2016. Meanwhile, compared to the 2017 forecast, it is estimated that in the year 2018, the net rental income of the company will increase by 43%. and will amount to 3.69 million euros. These forecasts were verified by PricewaterhouseCoopers, a business consulting firm.
07/01/2012
INVL Baltic Real Estate dividends offer more than two times
Investments in real estate company dividend policy of INVL Baltic Real Estate offer to increase dividends more than two times - from 0.012 to 0.026 euros per share. This and other decisions will be submitted for approval to the company's shareholders' meeting which will take place on December 29 this year.
30-30-2017
INVL Baltic Real Estate has earned a net profit of 3.1 mln euros for three quartersThe consolidated net profit of real estate investment company INVL Baltic Real Estate during the three quarters of this year amounted to 2.1 million euros and was more than 2.3 times higher than in the same period last year. The Company's consolidated equity value per share increased by 19.5% per annum. and in 2017 At the end of September, the equity value of the share was 0.42 euros (at the end of September 2016, and the dividends paid to the 0.012 euro share were assessed).
08/16/2012
The net profit of INVL Baltic Real Estate for the first half-year is 1.5 million euros
Real estate investment in the company INVL Baltic Real Estate consolidated net profit in the first half of this year reached 1.5 million euros and was more than 2.5 times higher than in 2016. January-June. The Company's consolidated equity value per share increased by 20% per annum. and in 2017 At the end of June, the share amounted to 0.48 euros (at the end of June 2016 it was 0.41 euros per share, as well as to pay out dividends of 0.012 euros).
07/27/2017
INVL Baltic Real Estate signed an agreement on the sale of Kirtimų street
Investments in real estate company INVL Baltic Real Estate signed an agreement on the sale of 3,000 square meters of office and warehouse space in Kirtimų street, Vilnius. The transaction value is EUR 1 million.
April 2, 2017
The consolidated net rental income of INVL Baltic Real Estate amounted to 586 thousand euros
Real estate investment company INVL Baltic Real Estate consolidated net operating income (net operating income) from own objects in the first quarter of this year amounted to 586 thousand euros, and as a result of investment in the renovation of the property, as compared to the same period last year, decreased by 10 , 9 percent The consolidated income of the company in the first quarter of this year amounted to 1.67 million euros, and, compared to the corresponding period of the previous year, increased by 3.15 per cent, of which the consolidated rental income of own objects increased by 3.78 per cent. up to 934 thousand euros.
11-05-2014
INVL Baltic Real Estate will pay out 789 thousand euros of dividends
Real estate investment company INVL Baltic Real Estate will pay out EUR 789 thousand or EUR 0.012 in dividends for the year 2016. This decision was approved by the shareholders' meeting on April 11 this year.
20/03/2015
2016 "INVL Baltic Real Estate" consolidated net rental income increased by 16%. up to 2.3 million euros
Real estate investment real estate consolidated net operating income of own company INVL Baltic Real Estate in 2016 amounted to EUR 2.3 million or 16%. more than in 2015 (EUR 2.0 million). Last year, consolidated revenues from INVL Baltic Real Estate totaled 6.29 million euros or 10.5%. more than in 2015 (5.694 million euros), of which the consolidated rental income of own objects increased by 21.5 per cent. up to 3.6 million euros.
10-02-2015
E. Damulis is pulled out of investment committee of INVL Baltic Real Estate
Egidijus Damulis, from investment property of INVL Baltic Real Estate, which is managed by INVL Asset Management, will be suspended from February 13, this year. Vytautas Bakšinskas and Andrius Daukšas will continue to work on the committee.
2017-02-07
Vilnius Gate will become the center of technological business
Eight information technology companies will be located in Ginučių street, the capital Vilnius Gate complex until the beginning of 2018. In the middle of this year, in the capital of the "INVL Technology" company "Etronic", "FINtime", BAIP, NRD CS, NRD and "Acena", which will operate in the capital, will migrate to "Vilnius Gate"; in 2018, At the beginning - both "Algorithms Systems" and "Profectus Novus".
29/06/2012
It is planned to resume trading in UTIB's shares in INVL Baltic Real Estate
The Bank of Lithuania approved the prospectus for ordinary shares in INVAL Baltic Real Estate, which is intended to include company shares on the NASDAQ Vilnius Stock Exchange. Following the publication of this prospectus by the company, it is expected that the sale of INVL Baltic Real Estate shares at the NASDAQ Vilnius Stock Exchange will be renewed in the near future.
2016-12-23
INVL Baltic Real Estate has received a UTIB license
On 22 December this year, the Bank of Lithuania granted a UTIB license to invest in real estate for INVL Baltic Real Estate. According to the company's Articles of Association, UTIB INVL Baltic Real Estate will operate for 30 years, until December 22, 2046, with the possibility to extend this term for another 20 years.
11116-11-11
New INVL Baltic Real Estate Articles are registered
The Statutes of INVL Baltic Real Estate, an investment company in real estate, were registered with the Register of Legal Entities. According to them, INVL Baltic Real Estate will become a special closed-ended private equity investment company (UTIB) and will operate for 30 years with the possibility of extending the period of 20 years.