Vilnius, Lithuania, 2018-03-19 08:53 CET (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) - The audited consolidated and consolidated profit of INVL Baltic Farmland Group in 2017 amounts to 885 thousand euros and the group's income is 575 thousand euros (2016 years The consolidated net profit of the Company was 1 193 thousand euros, group income - 531 thousand euros).
AB "INVL Baltic Farmland" has announced a forecast that in 2017 Revenues will amount to 575 thousand euros, and net profit - 350 thousand euros.
In 2017, INVL Baltic Farmland received revenue of 575 thousand euros and earned 885 thousand euros of audited net profit. Net profit was forecasted in the estimation that the value of agricultural land in the balance sheet would not change, however, after evaluating the corporation "Matininkai", it grew by 5.1% during the year. to EUR 12.96 million, or EUR 4.3 thousand per hectare. After eliminating the result of the revaluation of assets and related deferred income tax and administration fees, the profit of INVL Baltic Farmland would reach 350 thousand euros.
Against this background, it can be argued that INVL Baltic Farmland was implemented in 2017. profit forecast.
Additional information:
In the year 2017, INVL Baltic Farmland's investments in agricultural land amounted to 575 thousand euros, the audited net profit was 885 thousand euros. Compared to 2016, the Group's revenue grew by 8.3 per cent, while net profit decreased by 25.8 per cent. At the end of 2017, the equity capital of INVL Baltic Farmland amounted to 12 million euros, and this indicator per share was 3.72 euros, and, having assessed and dividends paid in 2017, increased by 8 per cent over the year.
Value of land managed by INVL Baltic Farmland increased by 5.1% during the year. to EUR 12.96 million or EUR 4.3 per hectare. Property valuation was carried out by the corporation "Matininkai". Upon eliminating the result of the revaluation of the asset and the associated deferred profit tax and administration fee, the profit of INVL Baltic Farmland would reach 350 thousand euros.
According to the company's forecast for the previous year, it was prepared assuming that the value of the land owned by the company will not change and there will be no purchase or sale of land, it is planned that in 2017 INVL Baltic Farmland will receive income of 575 thousand euros and net profit of 350 thousand euros.
"We evaluate the company's results positively - they are in line with the published forecast. The growing value of assets and the orientation towards long-term land lease agreements provide a basis for expecting further growth, "said Kristina Urbonienė, director of INVL Farmland Management, INVL Farmland Management.
Taking into account the results achieved, the company's Board proposes for the year 2017 to approve a dividend of 0.15 euros per share, and a total of 484 thousand euros for dividends. Compared to dividends paid for 2016, their share amount would increase by 2.14 times. It is also proposed to change the dividend payment policy of the company and increase its dividends to the share from 0.06 to 0.10 euros.
The results of INVL Baltic Farmland in recent years provide a basis for increasing dividend allocations in dividend policy, thus giving more value to shareholders, "says Alvydas Banys, Chairman of the Board of INVL Baltic Farmland. Decisions on dividend payment and dividend payment policy changes will be considered at the Ordinary General Meeting of Shareholders that will take place on April 10 this year.
Also, the Board of the company proposes to approve the permit of INVL Baltic Farmland to acquire its shares for the shareholders meeting. The proposed minimum bid price is 3 euros, maximum 5 euros.
The forecasts for the company for this year have been announced. Taking into account the lease agreements, INVL Baltic Farmland plans to receive a revenue of 609 thousand euros in 2018 and earn 360 thousand euros of consolidated net profit. Activity forecasts are based on the assumption that the value of the plots available in 2018 will not change and no land purchase or sale deals will be concluded.
The subsidiaries of INVL Baltic Farmland, listed on the Nasdaq Vilnius Stock Exchange, manage 3,000 hectares of agricultural land in Lithuania, which is leased to agricultural companies and farmers.
         Person authorized to provide additional information:
         Director
         Eglė Surplienė
         E-mail: egle.surpliene@invaldalt.com