The consolidated sales revenue of the Company grew by 50.1% over the year. up to 28.186 million euros, according to a report submitted to the Center of Registers.
Last year alone, the main group of the same name group suffered a net loss of 212 thousand euros (net profit of 3,801 million euro in 2016), the company's revenue decreased by 11.6 percent. up to 2,769 million euros.
Danpower Baltic paid dividends to shareholders of 2.598 million euros last year. After 50 percent Its shares are managed by Göco Investments, a German company owned by Danpower and one of Cento Senukas owners, Augustine and Artūras Rakauskai and their partner Alvydas Žabolis.
The Group consists of the parent company and its subsidiaries, RAZ SPV22, Danpower Baltic Taika Elektrine, Danpower Pakalniškės, Geco-Taika, Energy Investments, Geco Druskininkai, RAZ SPV21, GA Joniškis "(50,003 percent), Marivas, Duke Capital, Danpower Baltic Biruliškių, Danpower Baltic Paneriškių, Danpower Baltic Zietelos and Danpower Baltic Peaks.
The group owns 6 biofuel boiler houses in Kaunas, Vilnius and Joniškis, as well as one of two co-generation power plants in Kaunas.
In 2017, the group employed an average of 93 employees (in 2016 - 68).
The publication of the news agency BNS, cited or otherwise reproduced in the mass media and Internet sites without written permission of UAB BNS is not allowed.