Investment and economic environment



 Real Estate for Business



2005 September 29 Siauliai City Council decision No. T-321 "On the approval of the detailed plan for the industrial park (territory near the streets of Dubija, Radviliškis and P. Motiekaitis) in Šiauliai, Šiauliai Industrial Park was started. At present, Šiauliai Industrial Park is located in an area of almost 52 ha. Since the foundation of Šiauliai Industrial Park, companies have invested more than 43.5 million Euros, creating about 998 new jobs.
Industrial park map >>>>
Why invest in Šiauliai City Industrial Park?
Equipped infrastructure is needed for outdoor greenfield investments. Assistance is provided by the administration of Šiauliai City Municipality and mediation during the construction permit issuance and in dealing with other institutions.
Companies that invest at least 600,000 Euro per 1 ha and create at least 5 new jobs will be exempted from real estate tax and land rent for a period of 10 years.
More >>>>
Companies have opted for the Šiauliai Industrial Park
UAB "Lietmeta" (production and trade of corrugated cardboard products);
UAB "Statga" (metal working);
UAB Vonin Lietuva (production of fishing nets and fish farming equipment);
UAB "Krovlita" (warehousing and logistics);
UAB Scania Lietuva (specialized service);
UAB "Dirita" (catering services);
UAB Formula Air Baltic (industrial dust extraction and ventilation);
UAB "Agroconsult LT" (production of fertilizers);
JSC "ATC Baltic" (metal processing).
WARNING! AWARENESS OF INVESTORS 'SELECTION AND STATE LAND RENTALS SHOULD NOT BE COMPETITIVE IN THE AUCTION OF SHIELD INDUSTRIAL PARKE.
More info >>>


THE FREE ECONOMIC ZONE OF THE PIGSES
- a special area of 133 ha was established. The Free Economic Zone is adjacent to the main transportation arteries of the country - the Panevėžys-Šiauliai-Šiauliai-Panevėžys state-owned highway and Šiauliai International Airport. The special zone, which is located 6 km from the center of Siauliai, is also easily accessible by public transport, thus allowing the employees living in the city to easily access their jobs.
Territory and infrastructure: The territory of the Free Economic Zone is divided into plots of varying sizes from 1 ha to 25 ha, which can additionally be combined or redistributed according to the needs of the investor. For the convenience of the company, the main infrastructure is installed in the area - plumbing, household and rain drains, gas networks, illuminated streets, communications and power lines.
Status: Free economic zone - territory adapted for economic, commercial or other activities, in which the economic entities and special economic conditions of legal functioning are established for economic entities in accordance with the laws of the Republic of Lithuania.
Advantages:
There is no corporate income tax for the first 6 years, then 10 - 50% reduced profit tax.
No real estate tax
Dividends are not taxed in cases established by the Law on Corporate Income Tax of the Republic of Lithuania.
The operator of Šiauliai Free Economic Zone - Šiaulių laisvos ekonominės zonos UAB - offers a full package of services from the selection of a suitable land plot to the discovery of new export-based products.
More information:
 https://www.investmentpartner.lt/siauliai-free-economic-zone/;
http://www.rumai.lt/Users/Nariai/Siauliu-laisvoji-ekonominis-zona


Chief of the Economic and Investment Division of the Department of Strategic Development and Economics of the Šiauliai City Municipality Administration. specialist Aistė Petkuvienė, tel. No. (8 41) 596 283, email. p. aiste.petkuviene@siauliai.lt. Kristina Šmidtiene, Head of the Economics and Investment Department, tel. No. (8 41) 383 430, email. p. kristina.smidtiene@siauliai.lt.

"Installation of new modern UAB" Putokšnis "production bases in Šiauliai city";
Development of "AB Neo-Waste Materials Factory" Group by increasing export volumes ";
Stasys Pakarklis Enterprise project "Modernization and development of the company by installing a new Benninghoven asphalt concrete production line TBA 2000 UC";
The project of reconstruction of the buildings and structures of the branch of UAB "Sporto investicijos" (Ežero str. 11, Šiauliai);
"Concrete mosaic" and the project of the closed joint-stock company "Vilniaus aidai" "Installation of a new modern cement handling terminal in Šiauliai";
"The installation of a new production unit of limited liability company Hampidjan Baltic in Šiauliai"
  Information is being prepared
Economics and Investment Division
tel. (8 41) 383 435
Last updated: 2018-06-26 09:26:21
to come back