Kaunas city municipality controlled heat supply company Kauno energija will allocate 3,339 million euros or 7.8 cents per share for dividends this year. This is three times more than expected.
So, on Thursday, shareholders of the company decided to announce Kauno energija via Nasdaq Vilius Exchange. The board of the company had proposed to allocate EUR 1.07 million for dividends, or 2.5 cents per share.
In total, the company's shareholders distributed 11.281 million euros of retained earnings, of which 3.198 million euros were allocated to the mandatory reserve, 100 thousand euros - for support, bonuses and employee bonuses - 500 thousand euros. The remaining unallocated 4,173 million euros were carried over to the next financial year.
Last year Kauno energija paid out 1,071 million euros, or 2.5 cents a share.
The net profit of Kauno energija audited last year, compared to 2016, decreased by 18.5%. up to 6.069 million euros, revenue - 4.2 percent. up to 60,714 million euros.
Kaunas city municipality owns a controlling 92.84% stake. "Kauno energija" shareholding. The shares of the company are listed on the Supplementary List of Nasdaq Vilnius Stock Exchange.
The publication of the news agencies BNS information, cited or otherwise reproduced on mass media and on websites without the written consent of UAB BNS is prohibited.