The shareholders of the company decided on Thursday at the "Nasdaq" Vilnius Stock Exchange to announce "Pieno Žvaigždės".
Last year, the company paid out 4,062 million euros in dividends, or 9 cents per share.
The company's board was also canceled and new members were elected: Aleksandras Smaginas, Voldemaras Klovas, Julius Kvaracius, Regina Kvaraciejiene, Vitalijus Paškevičius, Artiomas Smaginas and Gegzas Rognojus.
Last year, Pieno Zvaigzdes received 167.753 million euros of audited revenue - 11.7 percent. more than in 2016, when the company's turnover was EUR 150,126 million. Last year, the company suffered a loss of audited net worth of 1.728 million euros when it earned 1.837 million euros in net profit.
J. Kvaraciejus owns 15.7 per cent, while 32.35 per cent with those who work together. "Pieno žvaigždžių" shares. Smilgelė owns 13.8%, Agrolitas Imeks Lesma - 14.8%, Estonian SEB bank, acting as depositary to the Austrian bank, - 11.35%, while Voldemar Klovo - 6.96%. "Pieno žvaigždžių" shares.
The shares of "Pieno žvaigždžių" are listed on the Official List of Nasdaq Vilnius Stock Exchange.
It is forbidden to copy and republish the text of this publication without the written consent of UAB "BNS".