Regular payment of dividends is one of the most important parts of our strategy. Our business model is characterized by high operating cash flow and low capital investment. The company does not own any hotels, aircraft or buses, and we do not plan to invest in such assets - we are of the opinion that our core business can bring more returns than investment in fixed assets. That is why we can pay the bulk of our profits to the shareholders.
The Board expects that, having assessed the audited results of the first 2018 The results of a half-year company will result in the payment of about 6 million euros of interim dividends. In the long-term, the board intends to recommend paying 70-80% of annual dividends. net company profits.
The payment of dividends is approved by the general meeting and must be approved by a qualified majority, i.e. y two-thirds of the shareholders participating in the general meeting. The company has received statements from existing shareholders, stating that shareholders will vote in favor of the decision in 2018. to pay an interim dividend of about EUR 6 million if such payment complies with the legal requirements.
The dividend policy will be reviewed regularly by the board, and all dividend payment recommendations will be based on expected prospects, planned earnings, cash requirements, financial position, liquidity ratios and development plans.
2014-2017 dividends paid to shareholders:
Dividends per year
Total amount of paid dividends (thousand, EUR)
Dividends per share 1) (EUR)
2017
4 500
0.58
2016
5 000
0.64
2015
4 000
0.51
2014
20 000
2.56
1) The value of dividends per share was calculated on the basis of the number of shares after the division, based on the year 2018. January 16 general meeting resolution.