Monday, July 23, 2018
Kedainiai
The day
+27
51
 %
In the evening
+23
72
 %
At night
+19
92
 %
In the morning
+21
87
 %
Forecast for 2 weeks
Market
Farm
Politics
Opinions
Innovation
Forbearance
Advertising
Contacts
Hot stream
»14:12 The turmoil in the global cereal market
»13:59 Is there a reasonable fear of defaulting on grain purchasing contracts?
»11:26 Good news for livestock growers - the sheep buying up meat went up
»09:51 Due to drought - there is an extreme situation in agriculture, and fires in the forest
»08:43 To seek support for foresters - recommendations
»08:22 Due to the clutter of imported fertilizers on the market - the first victims
»08:00 For grain growers in Europe - the threat of bankruptcy
»15:49 A new absurdity: the penalty for the cut tree itself is going to endanger itself
»14:48 Eugene Gentvil: mysterious" peasant "dance about Russian fertilizer
»13:04 Extended distribution of" Augu gruop "shares
"Žemaitijos pienas" will pay dividends - 10 euro cents per share
(Telšiai, April 19) The company "Žemaitijos pienas" has allocated its profit for the previous year and decided to pay dividends to shareholders for EUR 0.10 per share, Vilnius Nasdaq Stock Exchange reported. The shareholders' meeting took place last Friday. According to the report, dividends will be received by those persons who, at the end of the 10th working day after the decision on the payment of dividends, at the end of the general meeting, in 2017, May 2 will be AB "Žemaitijos pienas" shareholders.
  Agroeta
To comment on
ANNOUNCEMENTS
Fatty (oily) oat seed
350 €
I sell refined sunflower oil
400 €
I sell refined sugar bitumen ICUMSA 45
300 €
Wholesale of corn flour and cereals from ...
200 €
I want to buy
1,000 €
Peas seed in Casablanca
250 €
New French Gregoire-Besson RY41 ...
17 500 €
I buy non-condensed grains
110 €
+ Add an advertisement
Sign in
Agroeta contacts
Advertising on the portal
Ads
Ad placement policies and terms
Share information:
It is forbidden to use Agroeta content on other sites, in the media or elsewhere, or to distribute the material in any form without the consent.