0
Wikimedia.org photo
A-A +
Among the young people who have been promoting innovation, for some time now there is a debate about the purchase of the Raudone Castle (Jurbarkas district) built at the end of the XVI century.
The Raudone Castle, after closing this autumn, remains empty. So, according to the makers, using a crowd financing model and launching the first virtual tokens, every single Lithuanian citizen could contribute to the new life of this cultural heritage object. The current owner of the Raudonė Castle, the Jurbarkas District Municipality, does not rule out ideas, although it claims to have no intention of selling the castle yet.
With the help of blockchain technology, investors could be attracted to create funds for Raudon Castle's functions.
Apply the latest technology
The community of the World Economic Forum Youth Global Network in Vilnius spoke about alternatives to attracting investors to acquire Raudonė Castle. As one of the ideas makers Matas Mačiulaitis told "Lithuanian Knowledge", the idea to buy Raudonė castle using modern technologies and innovations, allowing one single object to attract many small investors, was born in the spring, representatives of the said community traveling Panemune.
"The day when we went to Red, the last call came from the school. We learned from the teachers and students that the last call sounds not only for the children leaving the school, but also for the school itself, they will not miss the coming autumn. The municipality would need a lot of money to keep such a building, and with the help of crowd financing technology investors could be attracted, thus creating funds for the change of functions of the castle ", - said M. Mačiulaitis.
According to him, attracting investors could be done using the fast-developing blockchain technology. It is a simpler alternative to shared platform ownership, ensuring maximum transparency and allowing people sharing the property to democratically contribute to building management. So people who want to buy Raudon Castle can buy virtual chips from around the world. It would be an investment from which to make a living in a successful economic activity in the castle.
According to M. Mačiulaitis, the proposed innovation would allow to find more innovative solutions on how to use the remaining cultural property by attracting the capital of Lithuanian emigration. What's more, there are already similar examples in the world - the funding mechanism for the crowd has been used successfully in France by redeeming and rebuilding its owners and adapting the old castle to new needs.
"How we will realize this idea will be revealed next week in the global block diagram chain tendencies in Vilnius. Together with experts in real estate, marketing and other fields, we will try to find answers to our questions: how to create a mechanism for funding the crowd, what should be the function of the said building and how to attract the most attention to this project ", - explained M. Mačiulaitis.
Schools do not go away
Skirmantas Mockevicius, the mayor of Jurbarkas district, told the Lithuanian News that the pupils had fallen so much that they could no longer afford the school in Red. "But the buildings of the former school will continue to remain the property of the municipality. Unless young people want to theoretically test how their idea can be implemented, "said Mockevich. In his opinion, the idea is interesting only in that it can be checked whether Raudone Castle is really expensive for Lithuanian emigrants, especially from the Jurbarkas. According to the mayor, the municipality intends to use the empty Raudon Castle to use for tourism purposes. True, the municipality itself does not have much resources to rebuild its castle buildings, so it intends to look for investors.
"We want Reds to become the center of a foreign (mostly German) tourist destination - not only the hotel, but also catering establishments, tourist information center would work. Tourists arriving from Karmelava airport to Red could accommodate it and travel there to other places of interest of our country ", - S. Mockevičius painted the vision of Raudonė.
It makes a lot of hope
So far, the prominent towns can not boast of a great stream of visitors to this city than to other historic legacies in Nemunas. More tourists from Portugal are expected to arrive. Because with this country, more precisely, with the writer of this country, José Carlos de Faria e Castro, the castle is linked by close links.Because the Castle itself was built by Krishin Kirshenstein, a merchant from Prussia at the end of the 16th century. Her grandson Jeronimas Kryshpin-Kirschstein was later nurtured by her. After the death of Kirchsthein, their relatives Olendsky were settled, and in 1811 they were bought by Catherine II, Count Platon Zubov. The arrival of the Portuguese writer J. C. de Faria e Castro, who came to visit her granddaughter Sofia, fell in love. They married, but after half a decade of common life, Sofia died, and the writer stayed in Raudon for almost a quarter of a century - until the end of his life in 1910.
After the First World War in 1934, the castle was sold out of competition - it was acquired by the Ministry of Education, and later it was transferred to the Bank of Lithuania. At the end of World War II, the Germans blew up the southern huge, 34.5-meter-high tower. This overturned part of the southern body of the castle. In the Soviet times (from 1959 to 1968), the Raudone Castle was restored, but the historic interior was destroyed by the building's adaptation to the school.
NAME EL. PAPER (optional)
COMMENTARY
COMMENT
COMMENTS (3)
The wrong thing comes • 2018-07-19 19:11
The mayor and the Veliuona have been celebrating the museum ... and now the children are in school
YUASH • 07/27/2012 5:08 PM
What does it mean, is the school unaffordable? The mayor of the municipality must subsidize all schools in Jurbarkas district
Regina • 2018-07-16 19:51
This way, the road to Jurbarkas is amazing. Rich in its historic and architectural locations, but it will dry up, as shipping has not been operating for 30 years, and the castles have fallen unattended. Lithuanians are not able to create attractive tourist objects and make profits from them, in order to help them keep these objects.