1
Mars Lietuva, one of the largest food companies in the world, managed by Gargždai food business last year earned a net profit of 7.692 million euros, down 19.5% compared to 2016, when it was 9.552 million EUR.
The company's sole shareholder, Mars Overseas Holdings, has been planning to pay out 40 million euros of dividends this year, according to a report submitted to the Center of Registers. The last time the company paid dividends in 2013 - 10 million euros.
After paying dividends, the company still has accumulated almost 8.7 million euros of retained earnings.
The turnover of Mars Lietuva during the year increased by 3.9%, to 156.664 million EUR. Sales of own production increased by 1% last year, to 133.9 million EUR, imported - 27.3%, to 20.6 million EUR.
The company claims last year that it has invested 16 million euros into the development of production facilities and the new flavors production line.
Last year, the company employed an average of 816 employees (in 2016 - 790).
The BNS news agencies are not allowed to reproduce information on mass media or on websites without the written consent of UAB "BNS".
write a comment
Get a free AGROWARDS weekly in your email:
Choose the FREE weekly you are interested in:
Business management
Marketing
Finance and Accounting
Market
Sales
My business
Trade
Construction and NT
Industry
Agroversla
Transport
Technologies
Leisure time
Most important news for the day:
Please note that the laws of the Republic of Lithuania prohibit:
to call for the change of the constitutional order of the Republic of Lithuania;
to encourage the encroachment upon the sovereignty of the Republic of Lithuania, the integrity of its territory, and political independence;
to instigate war or hate, bully, dishonor, incite to discriminate, violate, physically cope with a group of people or a person belonging to it by reason of age, gender, sexual orientation, ethnicity, race, nationality, nationality, language, origin, social status, belief, convictions , attitudes or religion;
distribute, promote or promote pornography, as well as promote and / or promote sexual services, sexual distortions;
promote and / or promote harmful addictions and narcotic or psychotropic substances. It is forbidden to distribute misinformation and information that defames, offends a person humiliating his honor and dignity. It is prohibited to disseminate information that violates the presumption of innocence and impedes the impartiality of the judiciary.
The published comment is the responsibility of the reader who posted it, which may, because of its content, be prosecuted for criminal, administrative or civil liability. In the comment, we do not directly display the IP address of the author of the comment, but it may be transmitted to law enforcement agencies in accordance with the procedure established by the laws of the Republic of Lithuania.
All contents published on the website vz.lt are property of UAB Verslo Žinios unless otherwise specified. Reproduction, publicity or archiving of content on servers from other countries without the written consent of the company is prohibited.
When quoting, reference to the source is required. The volume of the cited text must not exceed 500 (five hundred) stamps.
You can use the following on your or your company's website without a separate agreement:
* article headline
* the first paragraph of the article (in articles of the vz.lt it is distinguished in the chosen font);
* Continue to follow the link to the full article on the website vz.lt.
The logo of a project or a sponsor / partner of the rubric at the heading of the article is the content created by journalists of the "Verslo žinios" usually. A sponsor / partner of a project or rubric does not contribute to the creation of this content.
Sponsored Content, Business Tribune, Business Workshop - Content Created by Advertiser. Journalists at "Business Knowledge" do not contribute to the creation of this content.
The anniversary of the event is the content created by the advertiser to mark the anniversary of the company. Journalists at "Business Knowledge" do not contribute to the creation of this content.
Expert Insight - The content created by the advertiser. Journalists at "Business Knowledge" do not contribute to the creation of this content.
On this site we use cookies. They help identify affiliated users, measure audience size and browsing habits; so we can change the site to make it more comfortable for you.
Read more
I Agree More