1
Such a decision was made at the shareholders' meeting held on 28 April, via the "Nasdaq" Vilnius Stock Exchange, which was announced by Rokiškio sūris.
Last year "Rokiskio suris" paid out 2.342 million euros of dividends, or 7 cents per share.
In total, the company's shareholders have allocated 64.584 million euros, of which 1.076 million euros were allocated to members of the board, employee bonuses and other purposes, and the remaining 61,356 million euros were carried over to the following year.
Kęstutis Kirejevas, director of the company "Baltijos Enzimai", and Kęstutis Gataveckas, Director of the company "Perlo Service", and Rasa Žukauskaitė, financial officer of the Rokiskio Sūris branch, will be elected to the company's Audit Committee for a four-year term.
The profit of "Rokiškio sūris" last year increased 3.2 times to 12.551 million euros, revenue was 18.8 percent. up to EUR 205.058 million. Last year, the total profit of the group increased 2.7 times to 10.451 million euros, its turnover was 15.1 percent. up to 226,196 million euros.
72.57 percent Rokiskio cheese shares are managed by Milk Industry Investment Management, RSU Holding and Antanas Trumpa.
Rokiskio cheese shares are quoted on the Main List.