0
LŽ
Photo of the organizers
A-A +
This summer, Google Street View cars will reappear on Lithuanian roads. Their goal is to update the country data on the Google Maps platform. This time, the focus will be on updating information on long distance roads.
Street View is a popular Google Maps feature that currently operates in more than 85 countries around the world, even in some Arctic and Antarctic areas. With it, users can see 360 ° views from various streets, get acquainted with the cultural and national heritage. This feature is also available on mobile gadgets on Google Earth or Google Maps.
As always, Google takes care not only for Street View users, but also for capturing people's privacy. Before publishing images, they are all collectible and reviewed by special technology that hides faces and car registration numbers so that they can not be identified. In addition, Street View has a special image removal button, which can be used by the user to report a visible problem by clicking on the lower right corner of the program.
Travel cars will begin on July 25th, it is planned that it will last for about 2 months. For more information on Street View and details about where our cars are currently available, visit https://www.google.com/streetview/understand/.
NAME EL. PAPER (optional)
COMMENTARY
COMMENT
COMMENTS (1)
Jurassic • 2018-07-18 12:25
I wonder who sells Lithuania googliuj?