1
Telia Lithuania, a provider of Lithuanian television, Internet and mobile services, managed by Telia Company, a Swedish telecommunications company, plans to pay out 40.783 million euros in dividends or 7 cents a share this year.
As a result, shareholders of the company will decide on the April 25th shareholders' meeting, during the Nasdaq Vilnius Stock Exchange on Wednesday, Telia Lietuva reported.
Last year Telia Lietuva paid out 17.5 million euros of dividends, 3 cents per share.
The company's shareholders will have to allocate a total of 116,746 million euros, of which 75,962 million euros are proposed to be carried over as the next year.
The revenues of the audited group of companies are no different from those announced at the end of January - they amounted to EUR 370.123 million. 123 thousand euros. Due to the additional cost of impairment of fixed assets, the audited profit for the previous year decreased to 51,805 million euros (54,353 million euros was announced in January).
88.15% Telia Lietuva shares are owned by the Swedish Telia Company.
Telia Lietuva shares are quoted on the Official List of Nasdaq Vilnius Stock Exchange.