0
The European Food Safety Authority (EFSA) has urged EU sanitary inspectorates to warn buyers to be more cautious when shopping for frozen vegetables. Corn was the worst hit.
Specialists once again reminded that before using frozen vegetables, they must be baked, as they can even produce lethal diseases when entering salads, juice and cocktails from them.
The EFSA decided to circulate such an alert after the outbreak of listeriosis in a very dangerous disease in July in the five European Union countries - the United Kingdom, Austria, Sweden, Denmark and Finland.
Infected - from corn
It turned out that at least 47 people died of frozen vegetables from listeriosis, of which 9 had already died.
Most of these illnesses and deaths are associated with frozen maize.
Soon after the EMST alert in Poland, seven types of frozen vegetables were withdrawn from Greenyard Frozen Poland.
They all had corn. Six vegetable kits were sold under the name d'Aucy and one was Penguin.
EFSA has not yet reported which of the products manufactured by the company have been lysteric monosytogenes of a dangerous disease causing the disease.
These bacteria are characterized by the fact that they survive in a low oxygen and cold medium, but they die in turf.
Export is waiting for a shot
Bacteria are especially dangerous to people with impaired immunity, and therefore most often attacks elderly people, children, pregnant women. Listeriosis is transmitted through humans and animals, birds faeces, dirty hands, dishes and badly cooked food.
In the human body, bacteria can damage various organs, so the symptoms of the disease are very diverse - fever, vomiting, diarrhea, imbalance, seizures.
Listeriosis is fairly rare, but the disease is dangerous because about one fifth of patients in both the EU and the US are dying.
Warsaw is in the spotlight of EFSA's overseers because Poland is one of the largest exporters of frozen vegetables. If it turns out that the diseases caused by products produced in this country, this could be a serious blow to local vegetable exporters.
The scandal - and the strawberries
Especially as a week ago in Sweden there was a big scandal over frozen Polish strawberries that caused hepatitis. Sara Engstrom, spokeswoman for the Swedish State Food Inspection Service, has revealed that hepatitis has already infected 15 people.
These strawberries from three Polish farmers in 2017 were bought by one Swedish wholesaler, then sold them to chains, restaurants, cafes, bakeries and even grandmother's homes.
When the Polish strawberries were found to have been infected, they were withdrawn from marketing, but Swedish inspectors predict that the incidence of cases will increase. Because incubation period lasts 2-4 weeks, not all strawberry users have ever felt ill.
In addition, for some people, especially children, the signs of the disease do not show a few more times, so they become dangerous carriers of bacteria.
Swedish accusations were also recognized by the Polish Sanitary Inspection. The last compatriots are calm that the infected strawberries were solely for export, and the Polish market was not released.
But the Poles still can not be calm. At the same time, the Sanitary Inspection revealed that listeriosis-causing bacteria were detected in sausage "Kielbasa Sląska" and in milk pork sausages manufactured by Madej Wrobel.
These products were quickly removed from the market, but the people who bought and consumed them were faced with a real threat of illness.
In August, there was a panic in the two big batches of eggs that hit the market. Some of them have been infected with salmonellosis, while others have been banned from antibiotics. The recent eggs were widely traded in Lithuanian favorite shops "Biedronka".
Clio and Lithuania
The Lithuanian State Food and Veterinary Service has issued a warning from Poland regarding frozen maize, which contains listeria monosytogenes.
It was announced that such products were distributed in Bulgaria, Croatia, the Czech Republic, Denmark, Estonia, Finland, Hungary, Lithuania, Poland, Romania, Slovakia, Belarus, Ukraine, USA.