1
2016-07-26 16:51:00
BNS info
Text Size:
Print
Garden gardener Husqvarna gained 10.499 million euros in revenue last year in Lithuania - 2.1%. less than in 2014 (10.724 million euros).
Husqvarna Lithuania's net profit for the year remained virtually unchanged at EUR 246.1 thousand, according to a report submitted to the Center of Registers. The company plans to pay out dividends of 237 thousand euros this year.
The company's sales cost per annum declined by 2.4%. up to 8.5 million euros, operating expenses - 2.7 per cent. to 1.8 million euros, pre-tax profit - 1.1 percent. up to 297.8 thousand euros.
100 percent The shares of the Lithuanian company are owned by the Swedish Husqvarna Holding. The company located in Kaunas sells equipment for maintenance of giras and parks and construction equipment.


Ads
Notify me of updates to
news
Portal
guest
Ask
a specialist
Discussions
weather
TV
the program
Dating
Games
Horoscopes
Novelty
RSS feed
Facebook
Twitter
Maxima and Gelsva rushed to help the Maribor: it will share water for free
In response to the current situation in Marijampolė, the company "Gelsva" and "Maxima", the company engaged in the production of "Green Grape", have taken the initiative to tackle the problem of safe drinking water shortage. & Sc ...
And A. Tapin did not see the name of this product: he is - the champion of the year (supplemented)
In the virtual space a picture of a product with a strange name is spreading. Interns, after reading the name, laughed at them. ...
10
Twenty Years Investment: Continental launches plant construction in Kaunas District
Continental continues to expand its operations in Europe - today the construction of the company's first factory in Lithuania was officially announced in Kaunas. The beginning of construction was consolidated by Her Excellency President of the Republic of Lithuania Dal ...
26
Maxima Group strengthens its position in the Polish market: it combines trade networks
Maxima Group launches the merger of managed retail chains in Poland. In the trading network "Stokrotka", which the company manages from this spring, will be integrated the Aldik tin ...
Court: Lietuvos rytas must deny defamation against V. Valvonis
The daily "Lietuvos rytas" and "Lietuvos rytas" television must deny false information that Vytautas Valvonis, the director of the Supervisory Authority of the Bank of Lithuania, allegedly carried out corrupt activities. ...
1
The head of "Sūduvos vandenai" has resigned from lava and chlorine-polluted water
Algis Kadišius, director of the company "Sūduvos vandenys", is taking over from the second incident due to contaminated drinking water in Marijampolė. ...
4
Lietuvos paštas poses salaries to employees
From August 1 this year Lithuanian Post increases wages for the least-paid employees of the company. In total, the salary will be increased to 4362 employees of the company. Wage increase for the company at an additional cost ...
"Housing estate" is mocking customers
Rainwater is running into the power line, but the representatives of the house managing company Būsto valda do not see any problems. This is confirmed by Taikos pr. 40 apartment building residents who have not received any help for a week. ...
32
Sennebogen introduced technical innovations
At the IFAT exhibition in Munich, which presented the technology to facilitate the sorting of secondary raw materials, the German company Sennebogen also demonstrated the next generation of trucks. The latter are distinguished by ecological, security, ...
2
Ethics guards: Formerly one of the leaders of the "Lietuvos geležinkeliai" did not stir the interest
Former Deputy General Manager of Lietuvos Gelezinkelius Gerimantas Bakanas did not break the public and private interests - he did not violate the requirement of the law to "cool" from the former service and i & sc ...
More articles