1
City Service, a real estate maintenance company owned by the Icor group, having earned 6.115 million euros of consolidated net profit last year, plans to pay EUR 9,799 million, or 31 cent per share.
As a result, the company's shareholders will decide on the June 28 general shareholders' meeting, City Service reported on the Warsaw Stock Exchange.
The shareholders of the company will allocate a total of 24.544 million EUR, of which 16.493 million Eur is proposed to be left unallocated.
Last year, City Service paid out 19.598 million euros or 62 cents per share for dividends.
The company's audited consolidated net profit last year, compared with 2016, increased 4.9 times, to 6.151 million euros, audited consolidated revenue dropped 7.6% to 160.964 million euros.
84.83% of the City Service shareholding is controlled by Icor concern, which is 15.17%. owned by other private and institutional investors.
City Service shares are traded on the Warsaw Stock Exchange.
The BNS news agencies are not allowed to reproduce information on mass media or on websites without the written consent of UAB "BNS".
write a comment
Get a FREE BUSINESS NEWSLETTER in your email:
Choose the FREE weekly you are interested in:
Business management
Marketing
Finance and Accounting
Market
Sales
My business
Trade
Construction and NT
Industry
Agroversla
Transport
Technologies
Leisure time
Most important news for the day:
Please note that the laws of the Republic of Lithuania prohibit:
to call for the change of the constitutional order of the Republic of Lithuania;
to encourage the encroachment upon the sovereignty of the Republic of Lithuania, the integrity of its territory, and political independence;
to instigate war or hate, bully, dishonor, incite to discriminate, violate, physically cope with a group of people or a person belonging to it by reason of age, gender, sexual orientation, ethnicity, race, nationality, nationality, language, origin, social status, belief, convictions , attitudes or religion;
distribute, promote or promote pornography, as well as promote and / or promote sexual services, sexual distortions;
promote and / or promote harmful addictions and narcotic or psychotropic substances. It is forbidden to distribute misinformation and information that defames, offends a person humiliating his honor and dignity. It is prohibited to disseminate information that violates the presumption of innocence and impedes the impartiality of the judiciary.
The published comment is the responsibility of the reader who posted it, which may, because of its content, be prosecuted for criminal, administrative or civil liability. In the comment, we do not directly display the IP address of the author of the comment, but it may be transmitted to law enforcement agencies in accordance with the procedure established by the laws of the Republic of Lithuania.
All contents published on the website vz.lt are property of UAB Verslo Žinios unless otherwise specified. Reproduction, publicity or archiving of content on servers from other countries without the written consent of the company is prohibited.
When quoting, reference to the source is required. The volume of the cited text must not exceed 500 (five hundred) stamps.
You can use the following on your or your company's website without a separate agreement:
* article headline
* the first paragraph of the article (in articles of the vz.lt it is distinguished in the chosen font);
* Continue to follow the link to the full article on the website vz.lt.
The logo of a project or a sponsor / partner of the rubric at the heading of the article is the content created by journalists of the "Verslo žinios" usually. A sponsor / partner of a project or rubric does not contribute to the creation of this content.
Sponsored Content, Business Tribune, Business Workshop - Content Created by Advertiser. Journalists at "Business Knowledge" do not contribute to the creation of this content.
The anniversary of the event is the content created by the advertiser to mark the anniversary of the company. Journalists at "Business Knowledge" do not contribute to the creation of this content.
Expert Insight - The content created by the advertiser. Journalists at "Business Knowledge" do not contribute to the creation of this content.
On this site we use cookies. They help identify affiliated users, measure audience size and browsing habits; so we can change the site to make it more comfortable for you.
Read more
I Agree More