0
A-A +
I am one of those who like innovation and modernity. I have some, my head, good arguments. The main thing is that neither Lithuania nor the world in general have ever been so wealthy and safe.
Oil, electricity and water supply have made more medicine than people by increasing their lives and increasing their lives. As soon as internal combustion engines, electrification and water supply reach some kind of African outbreak, there is an economic explosion.
Those who make the most successful use of technology are superior to others. This applies not only to business but also to states.
To die of violent death, especially for us, Europeans, is the least statistical probability throughout human history. Even while eating a diet containing sodium glutamate and unhealthy fats, we are still able to reach the age of 70, although we have strange senile diseases. Our progeny in the 1940s massively drove from complications of gum bladder, and the only treatment was tooth decay. In the 19th century, our fifty-year-olds who still have all the teeth seem very strange.
To be unhappy, everything seems to be the same as insulting ancestors, all of whom - even the kings - lived worse than the average welder of this time. Oil, electricity and water was a luxury in Smetona Lithuania. Only a small part of the population had such a luxury before the age of 80 or 100. Life in the Balance Year still has not disappeared from the memory of the living families of Lithuania. At the same time, it seems like a smartphone with us is already eternity - it's hard to imagine that it's just over ten years old. It takes centuries for the light bulb to reach all people. And the phones got over and overrun the bulbs over the years. In Africa, the solar cell on the roof of a shed is often designed to not light up, and the smart batteries charge. Transport, communications, food and clothing have never been so cheap. Even if we are convinced that we are overworked, the people of the 19th century are fascinated by their leisure time and the ability to enjoy it in a wide variety of ways.
When enjoying baroque achievements or medieval tapestries, we should realize that compared to modern technology, it is equally pleasing to see a three-year performance at the theater. In my museums, impressions are more often than not artefacts, and stories about their survival or salvation are already affairs of adults.
In all this argument there is only one but very serious loophole. The emergence of technological innovations often affects both the organization and values of societies. For example, during the Napoleonic era, it was heroic to rise to the battle with a sword, but suicide was approaching the cannon during the Second World War. In a battle in which productivity and birth rates are key factors of state power, survival is more beneficial than honorable death.
From history we know that the emergence of new technology leads to racing for its application, and those who adapt the technology to the best, gain an edge over others. This applies not only to business but also to states. We live peacefully because we live in Pax Americana times. The technology leadership lies in the US, and therefore no state wants to be in the open confrontation. But this leadership due to the pace of change is not guaranteed. The Internet has changed the world and created preconditions for US dominance. And it just happened that such technology was used more effectively in democratic countries at an early stage of life. But there may be technologies that can be deployed more effectively by dictatorships, such as genetic engineering. The selection of embryos in democratic countries would be a huge debate, debate about ethics, and so on. There would not be any similar scrutiny, say, in North Korea. Think about how the world would change if the intellect of the dictatorship's citizens exceeds 40 points in 20-30 years. And this scenario is not the worst. History knows the examples when new technology gives power to the new structures, but not enough to defeat the guardians of the old order. The emergence of the printed word in the sixteenth century made it possible for Protestantism to emerge, but it also triggered 150 years of European war of war, killing every third Germans.
The unexpected impact of technology on society, with the advent of new emergence, may be more frequent. This is the idea of Nassim Taleb's "Black Swans" theory. The white swans brought by modernity - health, longevity, entertainment - can be destroyed by the never-seen black swans. The fact that we have not seen this yet does not mean that they are not.If rumored that Donald Trump has threatened the US withdrawal from NATO, it's true that it's not as hard to imagine that a black swan might appear on the tide of Lithuania. Reading some reports that NATO has rescued our Excellency in our commentary, we have to conclude that a similar comment on NATO could be ruined. And the fact that people use a lot of nonsense, which then costs a lot, is unlikely to have any news in this new technology-enabled fake news world.
Mantas Bileishis is a lecturer at the General Jonas Žemaitis Military Academy of Lithuania
NAME EL. PAPER (optional)
COMMENTARY
COMMENT
COMMENTS (1)
Rimantas • 2018-07-18 16:06
Soldier precisely