1
Grigeo Group, one of Lithuania's largest wood fibreboards, cardboard and sanitary paper manufacturing companies, having earned 3.6 million audited net profit last year, will pay out 3,942 million Eur of dividends this year or 6 cents per share.
The company announced through the Nasdaq Vilnius Stock Exchange that its shareholders have decided on Thursday.
Last year, the company paid out 2.628 million euros in dividends, or 4 cents per share.
The company's shareholders have allotted 17,934 million euros of distributable profit, of which 130,000 euros were allocated to the members of the management board and the supervisory board of the company, and the remaining 13,992 million euros were not transferred to the following year.
Grigeo 2018 and 2019 KPMG Baltics, an audit company selected by the financial statements auditors, will pay no more than EUR 17,000 (VAT excluded) per year for services.
Grigeo net profit last year amounted to 3.602 million EUR and was 15.8% higher than last year (3.110 million EUR), the company's revenue increased by 24.6% to EUR 70.976 million.
Grigeo Klaipėda, Mena Pak and Grigeo Recycling, the parent company Grigeo and its subsidiaries Grigeo Baltwood, Grigeo Klaipėda, Mena Pak and Grigeo Recycling increased by 26.7% year-on-year to 129.867 million EUR, consolidated net profit increased 2.1 times to 9.302 million EUR.
Grigeo shares are quoted on the Official List of Nasdaq Vilnius Stock Exchange.
The BNS news agencies are not allowed to reproduce information on mass media or on websites without the written consent of UAB "BNS".
write a comment