0
Forbidden to stand, visit popular places, feed pigeons, display tattoos with the image of the Buddha, use of stickers and many other strange rules can surprise even experienced travelers. So what do you do when traveling and how to travel without harming the environment?
Try to imagine a few tens of millions of tourists in a small town: the gains from economic benefits are high, the prices of high food and rents, the old townspeople who move from the old town to the distant districts, the constant noise, and the objects of cultural heritage are being thrown out more impressively. Or several millions of single-day tourists on a small beach: the mountains are torn out of plastic, water borne by them, endangered animals and plants.
This list can be continued, so before you go on another journey, think about whether you really want to hang around and drive through a crowd of tourists. If you do not imagine your future vacation without "compulsory sights", do not be surprised if you encounter various rules and geo-prohibitions.
6 photos
It is prohibited to wear high-heeled shoes in Greek historic places and archeology parks in order not to destroy original floorings.
Standing is prohibited
Insurance covers all around the globe - from a limited number of visitors to a specific outfit. But there are some more bizarre rules. For example, in Greek historic sites and archeological parks, it is prohibited to wear high heeled shoes in order not to destroy original pillars.
Sri Lanka has banned tattoos featuring Buddha, and photography near Buddha sculptures - for such disrespect for local faith, punishment can be obtained. Meanwhile, in Manala, in India, a year ago, all tourist lodgings were blocked through the door, as local mobs and community members opposed them.
The most famous tourist ban this year is visiting Maya Beach, which was featured in Leonardo Di Caprio's "Beach" movie. The beach for uncontrolled tourists and their environmental damage will remain closed until November. This year, tourists will not be able to visit Boracay Beach in the Philippines.
Thailand has been banned from smoking on 24 of the most prominent beaches, trying to protect the coastal ecosystem from its many spills. Disregarding insurance, locals and tourists may be fined or even imprisoned.
Still, the bosses can be considered Italy. Venice is forbidden to feed the pigeons of St. On Mark Square, standing on bridges and narrow streets, sit and eat on church stairs, wells and monuments, bathing in canals, letting children play natural affairs on canals. It is also prohibited to go to the courtyards and stairs unless they belong to museums or other public places. In Rome, sitting on the stairs will not succeed elsewhere. And sandy castles can not be built near the Eraskea Beach near Venice.
6 photos
It is prohibited to wear high-heeled shoes in Greek historic places and archeology parks in order not to destroy original floorings.
No shoes are allowed on the island of Capri. The owners of the hotels in Galicia, the Apulia region, are entitled to land abusive tourists. In some beaches in the region, tourists are watched and warned of excessive noise that may interfere with sea turtles that have helped the eggs, while camping in non-designated areas will be fined without penalty.
Friendly for the locals and the environment
When traveling, remember that you are "guests", so respect local customs, culture and rules. You can also contribute to environmental friendliness - just follow some simple rules.
First of all, when possible, choose another instead of traveling
vehicle. Currently, "slow tourism" and travel by train are the world's most popular. By traveling this way, you will not only be able to get to know the location, its culture and people more closely, but also less pollute the atmosphere.
Sometimes the indignation of the indigenous population may seem counterproductive to tourists - when traveling, people make money, and the wealth of the indigenous population should grow. However, this is often not the case - the income generated by tourism falls on minority accounts, and local communities suffer from rising prices and crowds of tourists.
To contribute to the true local economy, you can buy handmade souvenirs, stay in family-owned guest houses, and eat locally based restaurants. True, be careful not to buy souvenirs made from prohibited materials such as turtle shell or ivory. Do not give money or things to children in less developed countries, but better donate to a trusted non-governmental organization.Travel agents and guides can be added to the local economy. If you plan to use their services, check out their work and ethics before you go on a trip. Most importantly, the proposed entertainment is not harmful to nature and animals (for example, it is strongly advisable not to go to elephants, because these animals are beaten by warriors, restrict hours and other torture), architectural heritage, etc. t
There is a lot of talk about reducing the use of plastic in the home. Minimize its use while traveling - select glass bottles for water or multiple drinkers, and use 1-2 tissue bags to put up the luggage to the grocery store or market.
6 photos
It is prohibited to wear high-heeled shoes in Greek historic places and archeology parks in order not to destroy original floorings.
Recall that the more environmentally friendly you are, the more friendly and more convenient the locals will be.