1
State-owned UAB "Lietuvos energija" (LE) will allocate 78.3 million Eur dividends to the state budget for 2017. The decision was made at a general shareholders' meeting, the Finance Ministry said on Wednesday.
"The company offered a dividend of LTL 91.5 million, but the shareholder of the company, the Ministry of Finance, plans to distribute the difference from the previously proposed amount to 2018 in line with the need to plan cash flows. profit ", - it is indicated in the report.
How many dividends for 2017 will pay out to other large publicly owned enterprises (LUs) here. 2018 In the budget from the NGO it is planned to receive more than 222 million Eur dividends, another 4 million Eur. - from municipal enterprises.
Got a net profit of 130 million euros
LE last year received a net profit of 130 million euros, an increase of 10.9% over 2016. In 2016 this energy group paid out 100.7 million euros of dividends. In calculating the period from 2013, when the LE group of companies started its operations, over five years, the company allocated more than 318 million EUR to the state budget.
"Although we reduce the electricity tariff consistently every year, we remain the largest dividend for the state of the payers. This year we will allocate 70% of the dividends in 2017. group earnings. Another part of it will move to next year's dividends. I am proud of the people of our group, because this benefit to Lithuania is created by their hands and everyday sincere work, "said Darius Maikštėnas, Chairman and CEO of Lietuvos Energija.
Vilius Šapoka, the Minister of Finance, who signed the dividend, states that the allocation of a significant amount to the state budget in the form of dividends for several years in a row indicates the maturity and stability of the LE group of companies.
"This is one of the examples where a strong company directly contributes to increasing investors' confidence in Lithuania," says Mr. Chapa
write a comment