Dividends are not taxable if they meet the requirements of Article 35 of the Law of the Republic of Lithuania. 2 d or PM 35 3 d provisions.
Article 35 (2) of the LIA applies when:
Dividends received by a unit of Lithuania for the holding or permanent establishment of a foreign entity which is registered or otherwise organized in the State of the European Economic Area and whose profits are subject to corporation tax or a tax identical to it, shall not be taxed in respect of shares,
It is noteworthy that, in applying the provisions of this paragraph, the Lithuanian unit or permanent establishment must have:
1) a document certified by the tax authorities of the EEA State that a dividend unit registered or otherwise organized in that State is a payer of corporate income tax (or identical tax) (hereinafter referred to as a corporate taxpayer), or
2) other documents proving the above-stated facts, for example, a document certified by the signatures of the persons responsible for the EEA State entity that a profit-making entity registered or otherwise organized in that state is the income taxpayer or another document proving that the dividend was paid out in profit taxpayer. These documents must indicate the foreign unit that has paid out dividends, identifying information such as name, identification number, address, country and commercial or other registry in which the unit is registered.
In the event that foreign units pay dividends to a unit of Lithuania through intermediaries (banks, financial brokerage firms, depositaries) established in their countries of residence or other countries, then the Lithuanian unit may exempt from payment of dividends only if it has a document submitted by foreign intermediaries identifying the actual dividend payers and the above evidence that they are corporation tax payers.
Article 35 (3) of the LIA applies when:
Dividends received from a unit of Lithuania or a permanent establishment from foreign units not specified in Paragraph 2 of this Article in which a Lithuanian unit or foreign entity receiving a dividend having a permanent establishment (in which the shares, share of the capital or other rights for which such dividends are paid) shall receive the following dividends for a period of at least 12 months without interruptions, including the moment of distribution of dividends, controls at least 10 percent of the voting shares (lots, shares), is not taxed if the dividends are received from a foreign unit the profit of which is taxable with corporate income tax or a tax identical to it; and which is not registered or otherwise organized in the target territories.
We draw your attention to the fact that Art. Paragraph 5 (which came into force on March 26, 2016) states that the provisions of paragraphs 2 and 3 of this article regarding the exemption of dividends from foreign units do not apply to dividends by which foreign units reduce profits taxed on income tax or a tax that is identical to it.