The real estate investment company INVL Baltic Real Estate's profit decreased last year, and the equity capital value per share increased by just over a tenth of a year.
The company announced in 2017 earning a net profit of 3.58 million euros - 20.6% less than in 2016. The net profit margin decreased from 71.65% to 57.67%, indicated in the audited group's financial statement.
Consolidated equity value in 2017 At the end of December, it amounted to 33.86 million EUR, while the equity value per share, calculated on the basis of the current number of shares and the nominal value of the share, was 2.57 EUR - increased by 11% during the year. 2016 At the end of the year, the equity value per share was EUR 2.36, as well as the payment of dividends of EUR 0.06 per share.
Continuation by schedule
"We are delighted with the results achieved, which are broadly in line with the published forecast, and as the net rental income of the company increased from its own assets, the value of the assets managed increased as well. We will strive to maintain the expected growth rates, based on the quality of our portfolio of managed assets, continuous work with our customers and the employment of our facilities. We believe that these results and the company's prospects will be appreciated by considering the possibility of investing in commercial real estate, "Vytautas Bakšinskas, Managing Director of INVL Asset Management, INVL Baltic Real Estate, quotes the report.
The financial report of INVL Baltic Real Estate states that during the comparative period, the group's return on equity (ROE) decreased from more than 7%. points - from 18.15% to 11.02%. Return on assets (ROA) declined from 8.22% to 6.32%.
The company plans to increase its share liquidity this year - Invalda INVL has announced plans to transfer up to 22% of the company's shares this year, thus increasing the number of shares in free trade from 16% to 38%.
"It is planned that the acquisition of INVL Baltic Real Estate shares will be offered to institutional investors, and later, after approval by the Bank of Lithuania of the company's prospectus, in which the share price and distribution order would be determined, shares would be offered to retail investors," the report says.
According to the company, the attractiveness of the shares should increase and at the end of last year more than two times - to 0.13 EUR per share - to increase dividends. Dividends of this size, estimated in 2017. The results of INVL Baltic Real Estate are offered by the company's management company for the last year. The total amount of dividends paid in this case would amount to 1.71 million EUR. The decision on this proposal will be discussed by the General Shareholders Meeting of INVL Baltic Real Estate on March 26 this year.
Based on 2017 At the end of the year, the results of the company's projections, announced that in 2017, The net rental income of INVL Baltic Real Estate will reach 2.57 million EUR and will be 28% higher than in 2016. Meanwhile, compared to the 2017 forecast, it is estimated that in 2018, The net rental income of the company will grow by 43% and will amount to 3.69 million EUR. In addition, it is projected that in 2017 At the end of the year, the net asset value of an investment in INVL Baltic Real Estate will amount to 2,5776 Eur (in terms of the new nominal share value) and will be 9% higher than in 2016. at the end of 2018 At the end of the year, after estimating the dividend allocation forecast of 0.13 EUR per share, it will reach 2.6427 EUR. The nominal value of the ordinary registered shares of INVL Baltic Real Estate from 0.29 to 1.45 Euro was changed in January this year in order to increase the liquidity of the shares and reduce price volatility.
INVL Baltic Real Estate manages real estate in Vilnius and Riga: office and commercial premises in the Vilnius Gate complex, IBC business center near Konstitucijos avenue and office buildings in the Old Town on Vilnius street, in northern town, as well as in the production of Dommo business park , storage and office complex next to the Riga bypass of 2017. December 31 According to data, the area of assets managed by INVL Baltic Real Estate was 56,900 sq. m. m, the value is 56.3 million EUR.
"In the next two years the market of Vilnius business centers will be supplemented by another 130,000 sq. m of rented area. It is highly probable that at least a part of the new business centers will not be fully leased on the day of opening, so the vacancy rate in 2018 is likely to be very low. at the end of 2019 At the beginning of the year it can jump to 7-9% or even more ", - reads INVL Baltic Real Estate report.
Follow the NT Market News and Trends on the Facebook page of "VZ Real Estate"
write a comment