The dividend payment will be settled on October 26 at the shareholders' meeting, reported by Linas Agro Group via the Nasdaq Vilnius Stock Exchange.
For the last two years, the company has paid out to its shareholders also a dividend of 1.202 million euros.
The shareholders of the company will have to allocate a total profit of 35.409 million euros on the basis of unallocated profit and transfers from reserves in the previous year. Out of it, 245,000 euros are proposed to be transferred to the statutory reserve, 233 thousand euros to be allocated to the members of the board, and the remaining 33,574 million euros left unallocated.
It is proposed that the shareholders of Linas Agro Group elect Ernst & Young Baltic auditors for auditing activities for 2017-2018, paying up to 30 thousand euros (excluding VAT). Ernst & Young Baltic has audited the company's 2016-2017 financial performance, and the same salary was set at 30 thousand euros.
The net profit earned by Linas Agro Group last year was 6.7%. lower than 2015-2016, when it was 4.993 million euros. The company's financial year begins in July and ends in June next year.
Consolidated sales revenue of the group of companies controlled by Linas Agro Group increased by 4.7% in the previous financial year. up to 644,952 million euros, consolidated net profit - 2.1 times to 8,408 million euros.
At the end of June Danish "Akola" managed 65.37 percent. Linas Agro Group. 10.73 percent The shares were owned by Darius Zubas, 3.78%. - Vytautas Šidlauskas, 3,03% - Swedbank for Estonian Customers. At the end of June, the group employed 2,218 employees (at the end of June 2016 - 2293).
Linas Agro Group shares are listed on the Official List of Nasdaq Vilnius Stock Exchange.
It is forbidden to copy and republish the text of this publication without the written consent of UAB "BNS".