Vilnius, January 4 The small shareholders of Žemaitijos pieno, which merged with the Investors' Association after the first stage of the joint activity, are planning to continue the company's transparency activities.
Over the course of the exchange, it has been reported that more than 10% The joint ventures and votes transfer agreements of the "Žemaitijos pieno" group have ceased and the parties are considered to act separately.
In August 2016, Žemaitijos pienas announced its intention to withdraw from the stock exchange, estimating the entire company at just 35.3 million euros. Smallholders who manage more than 10% of the total. "Žemaitijos pieno" shares, united and agreed not to sell their shares and to seek the clarification of "Žemaitijos pieno".
"The first stage of the joint activity has been completed, therefore, we can measure the interim results of joint activities - by the end of 2017 Žemaitijos pienas was worth EUR 80.6 million on the stock exchange price, and more than a year, the shareholders paid out EUR 10.2 million in dividends. This indicates that the company's assessment was inadequate, and that small shares were going to be bought cheaply, "said Vytautas Plunksnis, Chairman of the Board of Investors' Association.
According to him, there is also a sign of transparency of activity of Žemaitijos pienas - the audit company of the "quartet" employed by the audit of financial statements, as well as reduced the debt of Žemaitijos pienui, the parent company of Zemaitijos milk, Algirdas Pažemeckas. A. A. Pawelemeckas also retired from the posts in the management bodies of Žemaitijos pieno and is currently working as a "mastermind".
"However, there is still room for improvement - loans from Žemaitijos pienas to related persons should be returned, excess cash should be paid to shareholders, and the company's board should openly communicate with investors," said V. Plunksnis.
According to him, due to the closure of Žemaitijos pienas, company shares remain one of the cheapest on the Baltic exchanges. "Despite the fact that in 2017 the shares of Žemaitijos pienas went up by 63%, the company has estimated just 3 forecasted earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and depreciation (EBITDA) - such companies in the world cost several times more", - said V. Pulnoksnis .
Against this background, the small shareholders of Žemaitijos pienas agreed to continue their joint activities and, by the end of 2017, signed a new joint venture agreement, according to which the votes of the shares they manage will later be transferred to the Investors' Association. "To increase the transparency and value of" Žemaitijos pieno ", we invite other investors to join," said V. Plunksnis.