English
Home page
About us
News
The team
Investments
To the shareholders
Partnership
Contacts
Company news
News from group companies
News archive
Company news
Dividends for 2017 payment order
2018-05-23
2018 April 27 The ordinary general shareholders meeting of Invalda Private Capital, AB, approved the distribution of the company's profit for the purpose of allocating a dividend of EUR 0.03 per ordinary registered nominal value of EUR 0.29 per share. | read more
Decisions of the Ordinary General Shareholders Meeting of the Public Limited Liability Company "Invalda Private Capital"
2018-04-27
2018 The Ordinary General Meeting of Shareholders of Invalda Private Capital, which took place on April 27, 2007, adopted the following decisions: | read more
Draft resolutions of the Ordinary General Meeting of Shareholders of the public company Invalda Private Capital
April 20, 2018
The Board of the Company approved the following 2018 April 27 The draft resolutions of the general meeting of shareholders of Invalda private equity will take place: | read more
AB Invalda Private Capital convenes the Ordinary General Meeting of Shareholders
April 4, 2018
On the initiative and decision of the Board of the Company in 2018 April 27 10 hours address Šeimyniškių g. 1, in Vilnius, an ordinary general meeting of shareholders of Invalda Private Capital is convened. | read more
Dividends for 2016 payment order
2017-05-31
2017 April 28 The ordinary general meeting of Invalda Private Capital, AB, has approved the distribution of the company's profit, according to which for each ordinary registered share of EUR 0.29 a nominal value of EUR 0.25 is dividend. | read more
1
2
3
4
5
6
The next
Investment Portfolio
© 2018 Invalda Private Equity. All rights reserved.
Cookie Policy
Solution: EVO MEDIA
This site uses cookies. When you continue to browse the site, you agree to use cookies. Find out more here. I guess