2018 April 27 the annual general meeting of shareholders of INTER RAO Lietuva AB has decided to distribute in 2017. AB INTER RAO Lietuva profit and to allocate EUR 0.355 dividends per share.
Dividends will be received by those persons who, at the end of the 10th working day after the decision on the payment of dividends, at the end of the general meeting, t. y 2018 May 14, will be shareholders of AB INTER RAO Lietuva.
Notice on the procedure for paying dividends. (PDF)
Form FR0021 (DAS-2) issued by a resident of a foreign country for refund of deducted tax. (PDF)
Form Fill Rules. (PDF)