The consolidated net profit of real estate investment company INVL Baltic Real Estate in 2017 amounted to 3.58 million euros and was 20.6%. lower than in the corresponding period in 2016. The consolidated equity value of the Company in 2017. At the end of December, it amounted to 33.86 million euros. The equity value per share (recalculated according to the current number of shares and nominal value of the share) was EUR 2.57 and grew by 11% per year. (At the end of 2016, the equity value per share was EUR 2.36, as well as the payment of dividends of EUR 0.06 per share).
  The consolidated net operating income of own funds of INVL Baltic Real Estate in 2017 amounted to 2.68 million euros or 14%. more than in 2016. The company's consolidated revenue last year was EUR 6.2 million or 1.4%. less than in 2016, the consolidated rental income from their own objects increased by 10.6%. up to 3.98 million euros.
  "We are pleased with the results achieved - they are broadly in line with the published forecast, and as the net rental income of the company increased from its own assets, the value of the assets managed increased as well. We will strive to maintain the expected growth rates, based on the quality of our portfolio of managed assets, continuous work with our customers and the employment of our facilities. We believe that these results and the prospects of the company will be appreciated by considering the possibility of investing in commercial real estate, "said Vytautas Bakšinskas, Real Estate Fund Manager of INVL Asset Management, managing company INVL Baltic Real Estate.
  The attractiveness of INVL Baltic Real Estate should increase by more than two times at the end of last year - to increase the dividend to 0.13 euros. Dividends of this size, estimated in 2017. The results of INVL Baltic Real Estate are offered by the company's management company for the last year. The total dividend paid in this case would amount to 1.71 million euros. The decision on this proposal will be discussed by the General Shareholders Meeting of INVL Baltic Real Estate on March 26 this year.
  In addition, it is planned that the liquidity of INVL Baltic Real Estate shares will also increase this year - Invalda INVL announced plans to transfer this year to 22% by the end of last year. managing the company's shares, thus increasing the share of free float shares from 16% to 38%. It is planned that the acquisition of INVL Baltic Real Estate shares will be offered to institutional investors, and later, after approval by the Bank of Lithuania of the company's prospectus, in which the share price and distribution order would be established, shares would be offered to retail investors.
  80 percent The assets owned by INVL Baltic Real Estate are based in the central part of Vilnius, their employment in 2017. at the end of the year ranged from 78% to 100%. Last year, IBC Business Center, the largest managed facility, continued to maintain a high level of employment and increased rental income, rising by 1.3% compared to 2016. and amounted to 1.88 million euros. Other objects managed by INVL Baltic Real Estate in 2017 were also characterized by a high level of occupancy of the premises and improved performance.
  Based on 2017 At the end of the year, the results of the company's projections, announced that in 2017, The net rental income of INVL Baltic Real Estate will reach 2.57 million euros and will be 28%. higher than in 2016. Meanwhile, compared to the 2017 forecast, it is estimated that in 2018, the net rental income of the company will grow by 43%. and will amount to 3.69 million euros. In addition, it is projected that in 2017 At the end of the year, the net asset value of INVL Baltic Real Estate will amount to EUR 2.5776 (in the new nominal share value) and will be 9%. higher than 2016 at the end of 2018 By estimating a dividend forecast of 0.13 euros at the end of the year, it will reach 2.6427 euros. The nominal value of the ordinary registered shares of INVL Baltic Real Estate from EUR 0.29 to EUR 1.45 was changed in January this year in order to increase the liquidity of the shares and reduce price fluctuations.
  INVL Baltic Real Estate manages real estate in Vilnius and Riga: office and commercial premises in the Vilnius Gate complex, IBC business center near Konstitucijos avenue and office buildings in the Old Town on Vilnius street, in northern town, as well as in the production of Dommo business park , warehouse and office complex near the Riga bypass. 2017 According to the data of December 31, the area of assets managed by INVL Baltic Real Estate was 56,9 thousand sq. m. m, the value is EUR 56.3 million.
  From 2016 On December 22, INVL Baltic Real Estate operates as a closed-ended investment company (UTIB). The management of the company was taken over by one of the leading asset management companies in the country "INVL Asset Management". The UTIB status of the company will run until 2046, with the possibility of extending this term for another 20 years.