Nasdaq Baltic 1.49 EUR -0.33% 2018-07-23
About Us News Business Sustainability Careers Purchases Investor Relations
Hygiene paper
Packaging paper and cellular filler
Corrugated cardboard and packaging
Wood fiber board
secondary materials
Heat
For investors
Home / For Investors / About the section
About Securities Securities Trading Financial Statements Key Performance Indices Notification of Material Events Shareholder Meetings Share Price Comparison Trading Share Stocks Issue and Principal Shareholders Management Principles Company Board Investor Calendar Contact Investor
    This section of the website is dedicated to Grigeo's investors.
Here Grigeo AB reports on material events, financial statements, information on shares, number of votes, main shareholders, shareholders meetings, company management and management, as well as other mandatory and recommended publication of information about Grigeo AB and contact information for investors .
Grigeo AB is a member of AB Nasdaq Vilnius since 1994.
AB Grigeo ordinary registered shares (ISIN code LT0000102030) are listed on the Official List of AB Nasdaq Vilnius (symbol GRG1L).
We are advised that cookies are used on this website. By clicking on the "CONFIRM" button, or while browsing, you will further confirm your consent to the use of cookies. You can cancel your consent at any time by changing your web browser settings and deleting saved cookies. More details are provided in the Privacy Policy.
I AGREE
About us | Business Sustainability Career | News | Purchases | Contacts
All rights reserved Created by Ubie Digital
in
Share it