Register
Sign In
English
Français

The Annual General Meeting of Shareholders held in 2018 April 25 decisions
Share it
April 25, 2018 10:15 ET | Source: Telia Lithuania, AB
multilang-release
2018 April 25 The regular general meeting of Telia Lietuva, AB (hereinafter "Telia Lietuva" or the Company) has taken the following decision:
- Approve audited 2017 The Company's Annual Consolidated and Separate Financial Statements. The consolidated annual report of the Company for 2017, approved by the Company, approved by the Board and approved by the Board, was presented to the shareholders.
- Distributed in 2017 Profit of the Company: from the Company's distributable profit - EUR 116 746 thousand - to allocate EUR 40 783 thousand in 2017. to pay dividends, t. y 0.07 euros dividends per share, and transfer 75 962 thousand euros as retained earnings to the next financial year. Two independent members of the board - Ingai Skisaker and Roland Viršilui - will be given EUR 15,640 in tandems for 2017, totaling EUR 31,280 for tantrums.
The Law on Companies of the Republic of Lithuania provides that those persons who will be shareholders of the Company will be entitled to receive dividends on the tenth working day following the decision of the General Meeting of Shareholders (rights accounting day) that has passed the dividend payment, y 2018 May 10 will be shareholders of Telia Lietuva, AB.
Under the Law on Companies, the Company must pay dividends no later than one month after the date on which the profit distribution decision was adopted. The company plans in 2017. pay dividends in 2018 May 24th.
According to the laws of the Republic of Lithuania, dividends paid to natural persons and foreign residents of the Republic of Lithuania are taxed by natural persons, subject to a 15% personal income tax rate; Dividends paid to legal persons resident in the Republic of Lithuania to legal entities and residents of foreign countries are taxed at the rate of 15%. the corporate tax rate, unless otherwise provided by law.
- To elect UAB Deloitte Lietuva in 2018 as the company's audit company. and 2019 For the audit of the annual consolidated and separate financial statements of the Company and for the year 2018, and 2019 To evaluate the consolidated annual report of the Company. Authorize the Head of the Company to conclude an audit service contract for the payment of services for the price agreed by the parties but not exceeding 240,000 (two hundred and forty thousand) euros without VAT for the audit of the consolidated and separate financial statements of the Company for the two financial years and for the assessment of the consolidated annual report ( ie 120 000 (one hundred twenty thousand) euros excluding VAT in each financial year).

- Taking into account amendments to the Law on Companies of the Republic of Lithuania, which came into force after the last registration of the Company's Articles of Association, to approve the new wording of the Articles of Association. To entrust the Head of the Company (with the right to sub-delegate) to sign the new wording of the Articles of Association.


- Given the fact that from 2018 onwards, April 24 Stefan Block, Ole Stenkil, Inga Skisaker and Rolandas Viršilas, board members of the Board of the Company, elected to the Board of the Company for the current term of office:
p. Agnet (Magdalen) Wallmark (suggested by Telia Company AB)
p. Hannu-Matti Mäkinen (proposed by Telia Company AB)
p. Tomas Balžekas (as an independent member of the board proposed by Telia Company AB)
p. Mindaugas Glodas (as an independent member of the board proposed by Telia Company AB)
Agneta Wallmark (born 1960) - Vice President of Telia Company AB (Sweden) and Treasury Manager of the Group. She is also a member of the boards of Telia Insurance AB and Sweden Pension Fund of Telia, registered in Sweden. Agneta Wallmark holds a Bachelor of Economics from the Stockholm School of Economics and a Master's degree from the University of Stockholm. Telia Lietuva has no shares.
Hannu-Matti Mäkinen (born 1970) - Telia Company AB (Sweden) Vice President and Head of Legal Affairs, Division of Investments in Subsidiaries. He is also a member of the Telia Finland Oyj (Finland) Telia Company Group, Tilts Communications A / S (Denmark) and Tukcell Holding AS (Turkey) and Lattelecom SIA (Latvia) member of the supervisory board. From 2016 April 2017 April Hannu-Matti Mäkinen was a member of Telia Lietuva, AB Board and Audit Committee. He holds a Bachelor of Law degree from the University of Arizona Law College, Master of International Trade Law and the University of Lapland, and a Master of Law in Finland and the EU. Telia Lietuva has no shares.Tomas Balžekas (born 1977) - magazine publishing company UAB Media Bees 51%. the shareholder and general manager of the company, as well as the director of the subsidiary UAB "Media Bite" UAB "Mano daktaras" (internet health portals) and UAB "Lions share" (organization of events) and 24% of the shares. share holder. Tomas Balžekas holds the Concordia International University, (Estonia) International Business Bachelor and Concordia University (USA) Master of International Business Bachelor and Financial Business Administration. There is a founder and shareholder of several Lithuanian companies. Telia Lietuva does not directly own shares.
Mindaugas Glodas (born 1972) is a partner and general manager of the venture capital company UAB Nextury Ventures, a member of the Management Board of UAB Energijos sprendimų centras, a member of the Council of Knowledge Economy Forum, member of the Coordination Council of the Scientific, Innovation and Technology Agency , Member of the Strategic Council for Research, Experimental Development and Innovation (MITA) and Head of several Lithuanian Starters. Mindaugas Glodas holds a Bachelor's Degree in Business Administration from the University of Antwerp (Belgium) and a Business Administration from Vilnius University. There is a member of the small partnership Vox Proxima (50%). Telia Lietuva does not directly own shares.
According to the provisions of the Corporate Governance Code of the listed company Nasdaq Vilnius, new Board members elected to the Board of the Company are considered advisers (non-executive members of the Board) as Board Directors and Tomas Balžekas and Mindaugas Glodas are also considered as independent members of the Board.
- To authorize the Head of the Company to comply with all decisions taken and to sign all relevant documents and make the necessary transactions in order to comply with the specified decisions. The head of the company has the right to authorize any other person to perform specified actions and sign the specified documents.

ADDED:
- Telia Lietuva, AB Consolidated and Separate Financial Statements, Consolidated Annual Report and Independent Auditor's Report for 2017 December 31 the year ended.
- 2017 profit distribution report.
- Articles of Association.
- Curriculum vitae of elected new members.

Darius Joy
Investor Relations Guide
tel. (8 5) 236 7878,
e-mail p. darius.dziaugys@telia.lt
Accessories
2017_Telia_Lietuva_audited_financial_kaskaitos_ir_metinis_publicimas
Profit breakdown_2017
Telia_Lietuva_istatai_2018
CV_Agneta_Wallmark_LT_2018
CV_Hannu_Matti_Makinen_LT_2018
CV_Tomas_Balzek_LT_2018
CV_Mindaugas_Glodas_LT_2018
Related Articles
More articles published by Telia Lithuania
More articles related to:
Other News
Directors and Officers
Profile
Telia Lithuania AB
  Subscribe via RSS

 Subscribe via ATOM

 Javascript
Vilnius, LITHUANIA
Available languages
English
Lithuanian
Media files
2017_Telia_Lietuva_audited_financial_kaskaitos_ir_metinis_publicimas
FILE URL | Copy the link below
Profit breakdown_2017
FILE URL | Copy the link below
Telia_Lietuva_istatai_2018
FILE URL | Copy the link below
CV_Agneta_Wallmark_LT_2018
FILE URL | Copy the link below
CV_Hannu_Matti_Makinen_LT_2018
FILE URL | Copy the link below
CV_Tomas_Balzek_LT_2018
FILE URL | Copy the link below
CV_Mindaugas_Glodas_LT_2018
FILE URL | Copy the link below
Telia Lithuania Logo
LOGO URL | Copy the link below
Newswire Distribution Network & Management
Home
Newsroom
RSS Feeds
Legal
Contact Us
ABOUT US
GlobeNewswire is one of the world's largest newswire distribution networks, specializing in the delivery of corporate press releases for financial disclosure and multimedia content to the media, investment community, individual investors and the general public.
© 2018 GlobeNewswire, Inc. All Rights Reserved.