The Swedish clothing retailer Hennes & Mauritz (H & M) predicts that this year, for the first time since the start of trading in the company's stock market in 1974, dividends paid to its shareholders will be reduced.
Bloomberg surveyed analysts estimate that the company will reduce its dividend by 7.5% in 2018 by decreasing its purchasing power in H & M stores. This would be the first such step from the start of stock trading for retailers in Stockholm.
In recent years, H & M has been able to save SEK 9.75 dividends to the campaign, but cutting it can be inevitable, writes Bloomberg. The Swedish company lags behind the pace of electronic commerce, with the rise of retailers such as Inditex, Zara, and Amazon's Internet giant.
Of the experts interviewed by Bloomberg, only one expects 2018 to increase dividends, 10 predict their cuts, 16 believe that they will not change. Simon Irwin, an analyst at Credit Suisse Group, predicts a 30% reduction in dividends.
H & M policy - for shareholders to allocate at least half of the company's post-tax profits.
However, recently, the company has been increasing its Internet trading platform, and its operating revenue may not be enough to maintain the same level of dividends, analysts say. In addition, they predict that H & M's profits will fall by about 10% in this fiscal year.
The return on capital invested by the company is now 38% lower than the first fiscal year 2016. quarterly and lowest in 16 years, and the debt level is historically high, writes Bloomberg.
February 12 The H & M Board of Directors has announced that it proposes to keep dividends unchanged at SEK 9.75 per share in 2018, and pay them twice in spring and autumn, in a distributed message to investors.
The company's annual meeting is scheduled for May 8th.
VZ previously wrote that the first quarter of H & M, which ended in February, profits fell by 62%, to USD 150 million. In the last sixteen years, it was the worst indicator of corporate profits.
write a comment