Prepared by the Department of Tax Payers of the State Tax Inspectorate under the FM of the Republic of Lithuania
Dividend income tax
1. The following is a duly completed form of the corporate income tax return FR0640 and its annexes: Annex FR0640U "II. Dividends and deductible corporation tax payable to foreign entities "and Annex FR0640G" III. Taxes on dividends received from foreign entities and the corporation tax calculated therefrom ". This form was approved by the order of the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Lithuania No 20 VA-101 "On the Approval of the Rules for Filing and Submitting the Form of the Dividend Income Tax Declaration FR0640, its Addenda".
2. To be paid in 2018 January profit dividend tax.
Payment code:
1001 - Declared taxes administered by the State Tax Inspectorate and from 01.07.2015 fines for administrative offenses, paid in one contribution code
Income tax on income
1. The form FR0313 of the income (sums) paid out to the foreign taxable units duly completed and calculated on the basis of the corporation tax return, is approved, as approved by the Order of the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Lithuania No. 2002. 40 "On Approval of the Form FR0313 of the Revenue (sums) Disbursed to Foreign Taxable Units and the Form of their Corporate Income Tax" and the Form for Completing this Form ".
The declaration is filed and submitted by the persons who deduct the profit tax, who, in accordance with the procedure of the Income Tax, deduct the profit tax from the amounts paid out to foreign units. The declaration is also provided by a foreign entity, having received income from performers and sports activities in Lithuania, for the sale or other transfer of ownership of immovable property located in the territory of the Republic of Lithuania, or for the rental of such property, if such income is received not through a permanent establishment in Lithuania, and such income is are received from a non-resident of the Republic of Lithuania or from another foreign entity not through his permanent residence in Lithuania.
2. To be paid in 2018 January profit tax, calculated on the basis of income (sums) paid to a foreign unit.
Payment code:
1001 - Declared taxes administered by the State Tax Inspectorate and from 01.07.2015 fines for administrative offenses, paid in one contribution code
Excise taxes
1. Owners and registered beneficiaries of excise goods warehouses submit duly completed Form FR0630 of excise duty and its annexes, approved by Order No. 3 of the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Lithuania. VA-106 "On the Approval of Rules Regarding the Formulation of Excise Dues FR0630, FR0630A, and their Filing and Submission Regulations".
It is to be noted that the obligation to pay the advance amount of excise duty arises if the amount of excise duty payable to the budget for the specific tax warehouse of this warehouse owner (or the corresponding registered beneficiary) exceeds EUR 15 000 in the budget for the preceding tax periods from the beginning of the next tax period after the circumstances revealed, by the 15th of the current tax period. the advance amount of excise duty is paid to the budget. This advance amount of excise duty is equal to 1/3 of the average amount of excise duty payable to the budget, which was (or should have) been declared in the declarations of the 3 previous tax periods referred to in this paragraph.
2. Registered, non-registered suppliers of coal, coke, lignite, unlicensed electricity, persons who declare natural gas excise duties, temporarily registered beneficiaries submit duly completed form of excise duty declaration FR0630A and its annexes, approved by the order of the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Lithuania No 26 . VA-106 "On the Approval of Rules Regarding the Formulation of Excise Dues FR0630, FR0630A, and their Filing and Submission Regulations".
3. Excise duties and excise taxes are paid.
Owners and registered recipients of excise goods warehouses, as well as payers of excise duties, must submit excise duty declarations FR0630 or FR0630A irrespective of whether the obligation to pay excise taxes for the tax period has arisen or not.
Payment code:
1001 - Declared taxes administered by the State Tax Inspectorate and from 01.07.2015 fines for administrative offenses, paid in one contribution code
Income tax
1. The duly completed Form A FR0573 annual income tax deducted and paid in Year A, and its Annexes FR0573A and FR0573U, are duly completed. This form has been approved by the order of the Head of the STI under MoF on 26 July 2004. VA-145 "On the Approval of the Rules for the Annual Class A Payment, the Income Tax Form Declined and Paid, and its Application Form, and the Rules for Completing and Submitting it".The duly completed form of the declaration FR0573 and its annexes FR0573A and RF0573U must be submitted by 2017. the tax period is paid according to the tax payment procedure, is assigned to the residents of the A class income, paid Lithuanian units, foreign units operating through permanent establishments in Lithuania, non-permanent residents of Lithuania, carrying out individual activities through permanent establishments in Lithuania and permanent residents of Lithuania.
2. The duly completed form of the monthly income tax return GPM313, dated January 20, 2017, approved by the Order of the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Lithuania No. VA-121 "On Approval of the Monthly Income Tax Declaration Form GPM3013 and its Filing and Submission Regulations".
3. Delivered properly filled:
Form FR0611 "Interest paid by legal persons for permanent residents of Lithuania for the construction or purchase of credits granted for residential housing" approved by the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Finance on 12 September 2012
by order
No. VA-85 "On the Approval of the Rules for Filing and Submission of Form FR0611 Form and its Additional Form FR0611P by Legal Persons Data on Life Insurance Contributions paid by Permanent Residents of Lithuania";
Form FR0612 "Legal entity data on interest paid on loans granted for the construction or acquisition of residential buildings", approved by the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Finance on 18.12.2008
by order
No. VA-65 "On the Approval of the Rules for Filing and Submission of the Form FR0612 Form and its Additional Sheet FR0612P to the Tax Administrator for the Construction or Acquisition of Deducted Lending for the Residential Dwelling by Legal Entities";
Form FR0613 "Data of legal entities on permanent residents of Lithuania for studies and /
or paid tuition fees
"approved by the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Lithuania No. VA-67 of 18.12.2008" On the Approval of the Rules for Completion and Submission to the Tax Administrator of the Form FR0613 and its Additional Sheet FR0613P Form of Legal Persons Data on the Permanent Residents of Lithuania for Tuition and / or Vocational Training ";
Form FR0614 "Loans (part thereof) for the repayment of legal persons' data on the costs of studies and / or vocational training" (electronic document), approved by the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Finance on 18.12.2008
by order
No. VA-68 "Regarding the Repayment of Personal Data on Permanent Lives of the Republic of Lithuania (part thereof) to cover the costs of studies and / or vocational training, approval of the Form FR0614 and its supplementary sheet FR0614P for submission to the tax administrator";
Form FR0615 "Order of Legal Persons Data on Paid Pension Insurance Contributions to Pension Accumulation Funds", approved by the Order No VA-66 of the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Lithuania as of 18.12.2008 "Regarding the Payment of Pension Insurance Pensions of Legal Persons Data on Permanent Livelihoods Accreditation Funds Form FR0615 and its supplementary sheet FR0615P Form and Filing to the Tax Administrator ".
4. If a person withholding tax pays part of the relevant tax payment in the relevant tax month and deduct the full benefit during that month, the person who deduct the tax must pay the deducted income tax to the budget before the 15th of the month if the last Payment was paid out by 15th of this month.
Payment Codes:
1311 - a person's income tax on the income of a resident with an employment relationship or an essentially corresponding relationship with that tax period in Class A
1411 - personal income tax on income tax payable to residents with employment relationship or non-related ratios of Class A and / or Class B benefits from which the person paying the benefit and / or benefits has been paid
1421 - personal income tax on the income from the sale of assets not related to the relationship of an employer with the employment relationship or their substantive maturity (for tax periods until 31 January 2017)
Fee for public natural resources
1. Duly filled in:
2017 10 01 - 2017
12 31 tax period Taxation of mineral resources, water and building soil declarations
KIT708 form,
01 01 2017 - 31 December 2017
the tax period for the use of the tax on the use of game resources in the declaration
KIT709 form,
This form has been approved by the Order of the Head of the Ministry of the Environment and the STI under the FM on 27.12.2006. D1-614 / VA-99 "On Approval of the Procedure for the Taxation of the Republic of Lithuania for State Natural Resources, their Filing and Submission".
2. The state fee for the use of natural resources is paid.
Payment code:
1001 - Declared taxes administered by the State Tax Inspectorate and from 01.07.2015 fines for administrative offenses, paid in one contribution code
real estate tax1. The duly completed form of the Real Estate Tax Declaration KIT711, approved by the Order of the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Lithuania No. 295 of 29 May 2007, shall be submitted. VA-40 "On Approval of the Form KIT711 of the Real Estate Tax Declaration and the Rules for its Completion".
Legal persons, who on January 1 of the calendar year owning and / or acquiring immovable property, with the annual declaration of KIT711 for the year 2017, must simultaneously declare in 2018. the first three quarters of the advance payment.
2. To be paid in 2017 real estate tax.
Payment code:
1001 - Declared taxes administered by the State Tax Inspectorate and from 01.07.2015 fines for administrative offenses, paid in one contribution code
Compulsory deductions from raw wood and do not cut timber sales revenue
1. The duly completed Form FR0463 of the Declaration of Income Taxes on Raw Mines and Cut Timber Sales is presented. The form and the rules for its completion and submission are approved by the Order of the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Republic of Lithuania No. 2003. V-179 "On the Approval of the Form FR0463 Declaration of Income Taxes on Raw Timber and Non-Turned Forest Sales and its Completion".
2. To be paid in 2018 January compulsory deductions from raw wood and do not cut timber sales revenue.
Payment code:
1001 - Declared taxes administered by the State Tax Inspectorate and from 01.07.2015 fines for administrative offenses, paid in one contribution code
Pollution tax
1. The form FR0521 of the Declaration of the charge for environmental pollution from the mobile pollution sources and the Form FR0522 of the Pollution Tax from Stationary Pollutants, Form FR0523 of the Declaration of Taxation for Pollution Taxable Waste Products and Form FR0524 of the Pollution Tax on Waste Packaging, approved Order of the Minister of the Interior under the Ministry of the Interior and the Minister of the Environment on 08.12.2008. VA-61 / D1-658 "On Approval of Forms of the Declaration of the Environment Pollution Declaration FR0521, FR0522, FR0523 and FR0524".
2. The form of the Declaration of KIT717 for the waste discharged from landfills and the form KIT717F of its Annex, approved by Order No. Ms 2016 01 04 of 2016 of the Minister of the Environment and the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of the Interior, shall be submitted. D1-5 / VA-1 "On Approval of the Form KIT717 Declaration of Waste Disposal for Landfills Taxes, Approval of the Form KIT717 Formula and its Addendum KIT717F for the Purpose of the Disposal of Waste Disposal in Landfills".
3. To be paid in 2017 environmental pollution tax.
Payment code:
1001 - Declared taxes administered by the State Tax Inspectorate and from 01.07.2015 fines for administrative offenses, paid in one contribution code
Hydrocarbon Resource Fee
1. Fill in the 2017 IV quarter Form FR0566 of the tax declaration for hydrocarbons, approved by Order No. VA-232 "On the Approval of the Form FR0566 for the Declaration of Hydrocarbons" and its completion ".
2. Fee for hydrocarbon resources.
Payment code:
1001 - Declared taxes administered by the State Tax Inspectorate and from 01.07.2015 fines for administrative offenses, paid in one contribution code