2018 March 26 The annual general meeting of SUTNTIB INVL Baltic Real Estate (company code 152105644, registered office at Vilnius municipality, Vilnius, LT-01109, Gynėjų St. 14, Vilnius) has been held. The shareholders' meeting decided to allocate 0.13 euros of dividends per share.
Dividends will be received by those persons who, at the end of the 10th working day after the decision on the payment of dividends, at the end of the general meeting, t. y 2018 April 10 SUTNTIB was the shareholder of INVL Baltic Real Estate.
From 2018 April 25 dividends will be paid in the following order:
- for the shareholders whose SUTNTIB INVAL Baltic Real Estate shares are accounted for in financial brokerage companies or branches of credit institutions providing securities accounting services, the amount of dividends after deduction of personal income tax or income tax in accordance with the laws of the Republic of Lithuania will be transferred to the shareholder's account in the relevant a financial brokerage firm or a credit institution;

- to shareholders whose SUTNTIB accounting for the shares of INVL Baltic Real Estate according to the Company's authorization is managed by Šiaulių bankas AB, the amount of dividends after deduction of personal income tax or profit tax in accordance with the laws of the Republic of Lithuania will be transferred to the account specified by the shareholder in the Lithuanian Commercial Bank (applications for dividend transfer to the account specified by the shareholder may be submitted to the nearest customer service department of Šiaulių bankas AB. A list of branches of Šiaulių bankas AB can be found here).
2017 dividend tax procedure:
- for residents of the Republic of Lithuania, for natural persons and residents of foreign countries, 15% personal income tax rate;
- for residents of the Republic of Lithuania, for legal entities and residents of foreign countries, 15% the corporate tax rate, unless otherwise provided by law.
More information is available by calling the "Siauliu Bankas" AB short telephone number 1813.
         Person authorized to provide additional information:
         Management Company Real Estate Fund Manager
         Vytautas Bakšinskas
         E-mail vytautas.baksinskas@invl.com