At the shareholders' meeting held at Šiauliai on Thursday, shareholders of Šiaulių bankas shareholders distributed profits to dividends and increase share capital.
The Board approved the proposal to increase the authorized capital by 26.3 million EUR, from the bank's retained earnings by issuing 90.6 million ordinary registered shares of 0.29 EUR nominal value. Issued shares will be distributed free of charge to shareholders at the end of the accounting day of the meeting rights (13 April 2018) for their share nominal value (20%). The meeting also made a decision to distribute profits by distributing dividends to shareholders. It is proposed to allocate 0,005 euro dividends to one ordinary registered face value of 0.29 Eur, which equates to 1.72% of the nominal value of the share.
During the meeting, the shareholders of Šiaulių bankas also approved the financial statements of the last year and updated the bank's articles of association. An annual report, an audit report, was also heard. Independent Audit Firm PricewaterhouseCoopers Elected to Audit 2018 and 2019 Šiaulių bankas and Šiaulių bankas group consolidated annual financial statements and to verify the consolidated annual report.
"Last year, the performance of Šiaulių bankas continued to improve, with typical operating income increasing, assets of the banking group exceeded the symbolic 2 billion euro cartel," said Vytautas Sinius, the head of the administration of Šiaulių bankas, adding that last year bank investors actively bought bank shares, while The Bank's first-ever investment credit rating - Moody's Investors Service, an international rating agency in 2017. October 23 Siauliu Bankas granted the investment long-term lending rating Baa3 and set a positive outlook for it.
VZ wrote that last year the typical operating income of Šiaulių bankas group increased by 12% to 46.3 million EUR. The Group earned a net profit of EUR 32.1 million. The Bank's annual net profit amounted to 30.9 million EUR.
write a comment
Get your FREE FINANCIAL AND ACCOUNTING weekly in your email:
Choose the FREE weekly you are interested in:
Business management
Marketing
Finance and Accounting
Market
Sales
My business
Trade
Construction and NT
Industry
Agroversla
Transport
Technologies
Leisure time
Most important news for the day:
Please note that the laws of the Republic of Lithuania prohibit:
to call for the change of the constitutional order of the Republic of Lithuania;
to encourage the encroachment upon the sovereignty of the Republic of Lithuania, the integrity of its territory, and political independence;
to instigate war or hate, bully, dishonor, incite to discriminate, violate, physically cope with a group of people or a person belonging to it by reason of age, gender, sexual orientation, ethnicity, race, nationality, nationality, language, origin, social status, belief, convictions , attitudes or religion;
distribute, promote or promote pornography, as well as promote and / or promote sexual services, sexual distortions;
promote and / or promote harmful addictions and narcotic or psychotropic substances. It is forbidden to distribute misinformation and information that defames, offends a person humiliating his honor and dignity. It is prohibited to disseminate information that violates the presumption of innocence and impedes the impartiality of the judiciary.
The published comment is the responsibility of the reader who posted it, which may, because of its content, be prosecuted for criminal, administrative or civil liability. In the comment, we do not directly display the IP address of the author of the comment, but it may be transmitted to law enforcement agencies in accordance with the procedure established by the laws of the Republic of Lithuania.
All contents published on the website vz.lt are property of UAB Verslo Žinios unless otherwise specified. Reproduction, publicity or archiving of content on servers from other countries without the written consent of the company is prohibited.
When quoting, reference to the source is required. The volume of the cited text must not exceed 500 (five hundred) stamps.
You can use the following on your or your company's website without a separate agreement:
* article headline
* the first paragraph of the article (in articles of the vz.lt it is distinguished in the chosen font);
* Continue to follow the link to the full article on the website vz.lt.
The logo of a project or a sponsor / partner of the rubric at the heading of the article is the content created by journalists of the "Verslo žinios" usually. A sponsor / partner of a project or rubric does not contribute to the creation of this content.
Sponsored Content, Business Tribune, Business Workshop - Content Created by Advertiser. Journalists at "Business Knowledge" do not contribute to the creation of this content.
The anniversary of the event is the content created by the advertiser to mark the anniversary of the company. Journalists at "Business Knowledge" do not contribute to the creation of this content.
Expert Insight - The content created by the advertiser. Journalists at "Business Knowledge" do not contribute to the creation of this content.On this site we use cookies. They help identify affiliated users, measure audience size and browsing habits; so we can change the site to make it more comfortable for you.
Read more
I Agree More