State-controlled JSC Klaipėdos nafta (KN) announced that it received 106.5 million euros of revenue from its unaudited financial statements last year and earned a net profit of 17 million euros. In 2016, revenues of 103.8 million euros and net profit of 13.8 million were earned.
Photo by Martin Vainor
According to the company's announcement, such results have been achieved through "proper management of freight flows risks, rational planning and adoption of flexible and timely solutions."
The CEO quoted Mindaugas Jusis quoted in the report as saying that financial indicators are really delightful, as the company's operations were influenced by strong external circumstances, which resulted in significantly lower oil product turnover during the first half of the year. Later the cargo flow was stabilized - almost 7.2 million tons of oil products were handled in the company's tanks at Klaipėda and Subačius oil terminals.
In 2017 The Liquefied Natural Gas (LNG) terminal received 15 gas carriers, which delivered 839.8 thousand tons of CNG. The gas was supplied to Lithuania from 4 countries. There were also 6 small SGD congestion operations. For some months, the terminal has been operating at over 90% capacity.
"We have exceeded our goals last year, as we have been concentrating a lot of efforts and internal resources on risk management, the creation of competitive conditions in oil terminals and the rapid implementation of technological solutions adopted. We also earned additional income by providing advisory services in international markets and realizing the oil products accumulated during the production process, "says Jusius.
Last year, the bulk of the company's investment was directed at the development of the Klaipėda Oil Terminal - the construction of new storage tanks - and the construction of the LNG distribution station. In total, EUR 32.9 million was invested in 2017, the first stage of the investment phase envisaged by the company's strategy was implemented and the second phase was launched.
"The most volatile growth is the LNG market, and we are constantly looking for opportunities to develop this important business area. The CNG terminal last year secured almost half of Lithuania's gas needs, and from the beginning of last year we will greatly pave the way for small-scale LNG congestion activities, thus ensuring not only energy independence, but also adding value to the state for new activities ", says M. Jusius.
By 2018, the KN plans a more conservative budget, but will seek to earn a profit of at least EUR 10.2 million. The company points out that the main risks are related to a tense geopolitical situation. One-off technical effects of regulated activities and investments in newly developed activities that will bring profit in the future will have a direct negative impact on the results.
"We will try to reload in Klaipėda the amount of petroleum products that is less than in 2017. However, the market remains highly uncertain, and the sharp competition with other terminals in the Baltic States and Ukraine will be a major challenge for maintaining high profitability. Also, the company's development of new activities - small-scale LNG handling or international projects - is still in its early stages of development and requires additional resources. Therefore, we cautiously evaluate the financial results for 2018 ", - emphasizes M. Jusius.
The manager states that the companies will concentrate on strengthening the company's team.
"This year, we will focus more on the strengthening of organizational culture: we are introducing a new project of value of the company and we intend to maintain an even closer relationship with the surrounding communities, to seek solutions that improve the quality of the environment," says the head of the CN.