The total turnover of Baltic equity markets in the week decreased to 14 842 153.23 EUR or -8.69% less than a week earlier. The capitalization of the Baltic Official List fell by -1% during the week.
Retail turnover of the Apranga Group network (VAT included) in 2018. in March amounted to EUR 15.9 million and decreased by 1.0% compared with 2017. in March
2018 In the first quarter, the retail turnover of the Apranga Group network (including VAT) amounted to 46.6 million euros, or 2.7% less than in 2017. I quarter
Apranga Group network turnover in 2018 in January-March, compared to the corresponding period of 2017, in Lithuania decreased by 4.9%, in Latvia it decreased by 0.5%, and in Estonia it grew by 1.9%.
2018 Apranga Group expanded and reconstructed three stores in the I quarter: Apranga and City stores in the shopping center Panorama in Vilnius and Apranga store in the shopping center "Akropolis" in Siauliai. One shop in Latvia was also closed.
Currently Apranga Group owns 181 stores (107 in Lithuania, 45 in Latvia and 29 in Estonia), with a total area of 84.1 thousand sq. m or by 0,3% more than in 2017. I quarter at the end
APB APRANGA, General Meeting of Shareholders, to be held in 2018. The agenda and draft resolutions proposed by the Board of the Company on April 27,
1. Consolidated Annual Report of the Company for the year 2017. activities.
Draft decision:
Audited by the Company, prepared by the auditor, assessed by the Board and approved by the Board in 2017. consolidated annual report.
Draft decision:
Listened to
3. 2017 consolidation and approval of the Company's financial statements.
Draft decision:
Approved in 2017 consolidated and annual financial statements of the Company.
4. 2017 approving the distribution of profit (loss).
Draft decision:
2017 The Company's profit (loss) is allocated according to the draft distribution of profit (loss) presented to the general general meeting (Appendix 3).
5. Election of the audit company, approval of conditions for payment of audit services.
Draft decision: APRANGA Audit Company in 2018 to collect UAB "ERNST & YOUNG BALTIC". Determine remuneration for audit services in 2018. up to 23,000 euros (twenty three thousand euros) plus VAT. Authorize the Head of the Company to sign an audit service contract with an audit firm.
6. Election of members of the Board.
Draft decision:
To elect members to the Board of the Company for a new 4-year term, nominated by the main shareholder of the Company (UAB MG Baltic Investment, having more than 50% of votes):
6.1. Darius Juozas Mockus;
6.2. Vidas Lazickas;
6.3. Marijus Strončikas;
6.4. Rimantas Perveneckas;
6.5. Ilona Šimkūnienė;
6.6. Ramūnas Gaidamavičius.
7. Amendments to the Articles of Association.
Draft decision:
7.1. To amend Articles 10.1, 10.2 and 10.3 of the Articles of Association of the Company and to set them as follows:
"10.1 The head of a company must announce the announcement of the convening of the general meeting of shareholders in accordance with the procedure established by the Law on Securities of the Republic of Lithuania.
10.2 Periodic and current information (including inside information) specified in the Law on Securities of the Republic of Lithuania, which the Company must disclose, is published in accordance with the procedure established by that law.
10.3 Other 10.1. and 10.2. Information and notices not specified in clauses, which the Company must publish to the public, shall be published in the electronic publication published by the Registrar of Legal Entities, which publishes public notices of legal persons. When notices can not be posted due to technical barriers in the electronic publication issued by the registrar of legal entities, notices are published in the daily Lietuvos Rytas. "
7.2. To approve the text of the new wording of the Articles of Association of the Company amended in accordance with the above-mentioned clause (Annex 4).
7.3. To authorize the Director General of the Company Rimantas Perveneckas to sign the Articles of Association of the new edition of the Company with the right to re-authorize.
8. Replacement of the Company's seat.
Draft decision:
8.1. Change the address of the Company's registered office and register a new address Ukmergės g. 362, Vilnius City, Vilnius City sav.
8.2. To authorize the Director General of the Company Rimantas Perveneckas to register a change of seat in accordance with the procedure established by legal acts, with the right to re-authorize.
9. Amendment of the provisions of the Audit Committee.
Draft decision
9.1. To change the provisions of the Audit Committee clause 2.8. and set it as follows:
"2.8. Committee members may be compensated for their activities in the Committee. The amount of remuneration and the payment procedure shall be determined by the Board. "
Dividends are offered for a share of EUR 0.16.
The stop loss signal triggered the position.
AB Gubernija received a statement from AB MV GROUP Production about its intention to make a bid. Purchase price not yet published.
AS Tallink Grupp moved 1.2% less passengers, 0.3% less freight transport, and 1.4% more passenger transport.On the initiative and decision of AB Amber Grid Board in 2018 April 24 10:00 am, the Ordinary General Meeting of Shareholders of AB "Amber Grid" is convened at the Company's registered office (address Savanorių avenue 28, Vilnius).
Meeting agenda:
AB "Amber Grid" in 2017 annual report
Auditor's conclusion on AB Amber Grid in 2017 a set of financial statements and an annual report
AB "Amber Grid" in 2017 approval of the financial statements
AB "Amber Grid" in 2017 approving the distribution of profit (loss)
Amber Grid AB amendments to the Articles of Association
Revocation of the Director-General S. Bilis from the position of member of the Board
Shareholder Registration: 2018 April 24 9.15 hours
Shareholder registration end: 2018 April 24 9.45 hours
Accounting Date of the General Meeting of Shareholders: 2018 April 17 Those persons who will be shareholders of the Company at the end of the accounting day of the General Meeting of Shareholders will be able to participate and vote in the general shareholders' meeting. The accounting day of the shareholders' rights is in 2018. May 9 The right to receive dividends will be available to those shareholders who will be AB Amber Grid shareholders at the end of the shareholder account.
A person who participates in the general meeting of shareholders and who has the right to vote must submit a personal identity document. A person who is not a shareholder, in addition to the said document, must submit a document confirming the right to vote at the general meeting of shareholders.
The possibility to participate and vote at the general shareholders' meeting is not established by means of electronic communications.
The Board of the Company in 2018 March 23 approved the agenda of the general shareholders' meeting and draft resolutions of the meeting (for explanation, when decisions are not required):
1. AB "Amber Grid" in 2017 annual report
Explained:
"The decision of the general shareholders' meeting is unnecessary. The Board provides the General Meeting of Shareholders with a hearing on 2017. annual report (enclosed). "(Annex 1)
2. Auditor's conclusion regarding Amber Grid AB in 2017. a set of financial statements and an annual report
Explained:
"The decision of the general shareholders' meeting is unnecessary. The General Meeting of Shareholders should take into account the opinion expressed by the independent auditor in the opinion of the shareholders of AB "Amber Grid", when making decisions regarding Amber Grid AB in 2017. approval of the financial statements (enclosed). "
3. Amber Grid AB in 2017 approval of the financial statements
Draft decision:
"To approve Amber Grid AB in 2017. a set of financial statements (attached). "
4. Amber Grid AB in 2017 approving the distribution of profit (loss)
Draft decision:
"Approved in 2017 Amber Grid AB Profit (Loss) Allocation. "
5. Amendment of the Articles of Association of AB "Amber Grid"
Draft decision:
"1. To approve the new wording of the Articles of Association of AB "Amber Grid".
2. To authorize Saulius Bilis, Director General of AB "Amber Grid", or his authorized person to sign the amended wording of the Articles of Association of AB "Amber Grid" and register it in the Register of Legal Entities. "
6. Retirement of the Director-General S. Billy from the position of member of the Management Board
Draft decision:
"To cancel Saulius Bilis, General Manager of AB" Amber Grid "from the duties of a member of the Board from the date of registration of the new wording of the By-Laws of the Register of Legal Persons."
The shareholders of the Company may familiarize themselves with the decisions of the General Meeting of Shareholders and other additional materials related to the general shareholders 'meeting and the exercise of shareholders' rights from 2018. April 3 on working days from 14:00. until 4 pm (Fridays till 15.15), AB "Amber Grid", at Savanoriu pr. 28, LT-03116 Vilnius, tel. (8 5) 236 08 55. These documents are also posted on the Central Regulated Information Database www.crib.ltbei on the Company's website www.ambergrid.lt.
Amber Grid plans to pay off a dividend of EUR 0.1338.
Position activated the purchase signal.
AMG1L
On the initiative and decision of AB Pieno Žvaigždės Board in 2018 April 26 d 10:00 am The General Meeting of Shareholders of the AB "Pieno Žvaigždės" (hereinafter referred to as the "Company", registered office at Perkūnkiemio St. 3, Vilnius, Company code 124665536, VAT payer's code LT 246655314, the data of which is accumulated and stored at the Register of Legal Entities), is convened at Perkūnkiemis g. 3 in Vilnius. Shareholders are registered from 9:30 am.
Dividends will not be paid.
Price down trend. Buy risky.
PZV1L
As AB Lietuvos Energija informs earlier, in 2018, March 26 At the Ordinary General Meeting of Shareholders of the Company the decision was made to elect new members of the Company's Supervisory Board. 2018 April 3 Dominykas Tučkus was elected Chairman of the Supervisory Board of the newly elected Supervisory Board of the Company.We also inform you that, in view of the fact that at the Annual General Meeting of Shareholders of the Company a decision was made to approve new Company's Articles of Incorporation which stipulates, among other things, that the Board of the Company consists of 3 (three) members, in 2018, April 3 At the meeting of the Supervisory Board of the Company, the decision was taken to revoke the Board of Directors from the 4 (four) members in corpore and to elect three (three) members for the four-year term - until now, the members of the Board of Directors of the Company: Eglė Čiužaitė (curriculum area - strategy and management), Darius Kucinas (controlled area - production and system service management), Mindaugas Kvekas (financial discipline and administration).
The elected Board of the Company commences its work from the end of the meeting of the Company's Supervisory Board that elected it.
The change of the Company's Articles of Association, in the view that the Board of the Company consists of 3 (three) members, was initiated in the light of the changed needs for the management of the Company's activities. The area of business development that the former member of the Board of Management of the Company, Nerijus Rasburskis, has been curbing up to now, is now assigned to the Board of Directors of the Company, General Director Egle Čiužaite.
LNR1L
AB Vilniaus baldai in 2018 six months of the financial year in September-February. sales amounted to 31 390 thousand euros, sales of the same period last year - 29 443 thousand euros.
Groups in 2018 September-February of the first half of the financial year Net profit amounted to 1 318 thousand EUR, the same period last year - 1 770 thousand EUR. Profit before tax, interest and depreciation (EBITDA) amounted to 2,322 thousand euros, a year ago was 2,742 thousand euros.
Public company "VILNIAUS BALDAI" in 2018 December to February of the second quarter of the financial year. sales amounted to 13 751 thousand euros, the same period last year - 13 400 thousand euros.
Groups in 2018 December to February of the second quarter of the financial year. the net loss amounted to 127 thousand euros, the net profit of the same period last year amounted to 903 thousand euros. Profit before tax, interest and depreciation (EBITDA) amounted to 243 thousand euros, a year ago was 1,392 thousand euros.
VBL1L
The official purchase price of Olympic Entertainment Group AS was EUR 1.90 per share.
OEG1T
Šiaulių bankas AB, in accordance with the remuneration policy requirements set by the Bank of Lithuania, to pay the Group's share of the employee's variable remuneration to the Bank's shares in 2018. April 3 Nasdaq Vilnius Stock Exchange deals with Bank Shares in accordance with group work orders. The Bank's and the Bank's financial group companies are paying for the Bank's shares for these transactions, thus fulfilling the obligation to pay the variable remuneration to the Bank's shares.
SAB1L
Harju Elekter plans to pay a dividend of 0.24 euros.
HAET
EfTEN Real Estate Fund III AS shareholders' meeting approved dividends of 0.68 euros.
EFT1T
2018 April 4 At the meeting of Grigeo AB Board, it was decided to provide Grigeo AB with the General Shareholders Meeting, which will take place in 2018. The following information and documents are available from April 26, 2010: Company's 2017 Consolidated Annual Report, Company's 2017 auditor's report and audited consolidated and separate annual financial statements of the Company for the year 2017. the company's 2017 profit distribution project in which the Company's Board proposes to allocate EUR 3 942 000 in dividends, i.e. after 0.06 EUR per share, AB Grigeo Ordinary General Shareholders Meeting, which will take place in 2018. The draft resolutions proposed by the Board on April 26, 2006, regarding the agenda item of each general meeting, and the General Ballot Bulletin.
Position activated the purchase signal.
GRG1L
On the initiative of the Board of the Company and decision of 2018-04-04, 2018 April 27 12:00 An ordinary general meeting of shareholders of AB Rokiškio sūris (registered number 173057512, registered at Pramonės g.3, Rokiškis), which will take place at the office of AB "Rokiškio sūris" (Pramonės g.3, Rokiškis), is convened.
Registration will take place from 11:00. before 11.45
The accounting day of the General Meeting of Shareholders - 2018 April 20
The accounting day of shareholders' rights is 2018. May 14
Suggested meeting agenda:
1. The auditor's report on the financial statements and the annual report.
2. Audit Committee's conclusion.
3. The Company's 2017 consolidated annual report.
4. Consolidated and Company 2017 approval of the financial statements.
5. Company's 2017 profit (loss) distribution.
6. Approval of dividend policy.
7. Concerning the creation of a reserve for the purchase of own shares.
8. Concerning the acquisition of the company's own shares.
9. Election of the audit company and establishment of conditions for payment of audit services.Persons who were former shareholders of the Company, in person, or their authorized persons, or persons with whom the agreement on the transfer of voting rights has been concluded, shall have the right to participate and vote at the general shareholders 'meeting at the end of the accounting day of the general shareholders' meeting (20 April 2018).
The dividend is planned to be earmarked for a share of EUR 0.10.
RSU1L
AB Novatur has received reports on transactions between executives and related persons (enclosed).
The General Manager of the Company has sold 28,000 shares for the Central European Tour Operator for an overnight deal of EUR 10.50.
NTU1L
AB Klaipedos Nafta in 2018 April 4 The company K2 SAGL, registered in Switzerland, has concluded an agreement on services related to the transfer of oil products at the terminal of AB Klaipedos Nafta (hereinafter referred to as the "Agreement").
The contract is for one year. The conclusion of the agreement with K2 SAGL will ensure additional flow of oil products at the Klaipėda Oil Terminal.
The essential conditions of the agreement were approved by the Board of the Company, as provided for in the Company's Articles of Association.
KNF1L
AB Panevezio Statybos Trest Board proposes a general general meeting of shareholders to be convened in 2018. April 27 (friday) at 10 o'clock at the company's registered address P. Puzino 1, Panevėžys, the following draft decisions:
1. Audit findings for 2017 Company's financial statements and annual report.
The information is listened.
2. The Company's 2017 annual report
The information is listened.
3. Approval of the Company's 2017 Financial Statements.
To approve the consolidated and separate financial statements of AB Panevezio statybos trestas for the year 2017, prepared in accordance with the International Financial Reporting Standards adopted by the European Union, presented together with an independent auditor's report.
4. Distribution of the company's profit (loss).
To approve the distribution of profit (loss) of AB Panevėžio statybos trestas:
Retained earnings (losses) of previous financial year at the end of the reporting financial year - EUR 33 212 224;
Dividends paid - EUR 1 062 751;
Net profit (loss) for the reporting financial year - EUR 194,450;
Profit (loss) for the reporting financial year not recognized in the profit and loss account - EUR 73 316;
Transfers from reserves - 0 EUR;
Shareholders' contributions to cover losses of the company (if all or part of the loss was decided by the shareholders) - 0 EUR;
Distributable profit (loss) in total - EUR 32 417 239;
the share of profit allocated to the mandatory reserve - 0 EUR;
share of profit allocated to the reserve for the purchase of own shares - EUR 0;
share of profit allocated to other reserves - 0 EUR;
the portion of profit allocated to pay dividends - EUR 981,000;
the share of profit allocated to annual payments (bonuses) to members of the Management Board and Supervisory Board, employee bonuses and other purposes - EUR 38 890;
Retained earnings (losses) at the end of the reporting financial year, carried over to the next financial year - EUR 31,397,349.
To allocate 0.06 EUR for dividends to one ordinary Panevėžio statybos trestas AB for a share price of 0.29 EUR.
5. Election of members of the Audit Committee.
To compile the audit committee:
Courageous Liatuk (as an independent member),
Irena Kriaučiūnienė (as an independent member),
Eglė Grabauskienė.
PTR1L
AB, Vilniaus degtinas on the initiative and decision of the Board in 2018. April 26 At 10 o'clock Company headquarters, Paneriu g. 47, Vilnius, an ordinary general shareholders' meeting of AB Vilniaus degtinė (company code 120057287) is convened. The registration of shareholders starts at 9:00.
The accounting day of the General Meeting of Shareholders - 2018 April 19 Only those persons who are shareholders at the end of the accounting day of the general meeting of shareholders are entitled to attend and vote in the general shareholders' meeting.
Rights Accounting Day - 2018 May 11 Shareholders 'rights arising from decisions taken at the general shareholders' meeting will be used by shareholders in proportion to the number of shares held at the end of the rights accounting day.
Meeting agenda:
1. The auditor's report on the company's financial statements and annual report.
2. Feedback and suggestions from the Supervisory Board.
3. 2017 company's annual report.
4. 2017 approval of the company's annual financial statements.
5. 2017 distribution of company profits.
6. Election of the audit company and establishment of conditions for payment of audit services.
7. Revocation of the Chairperson of the Supervisory Board and the election of a member of the new Supervisory Board
8. Other issues.
Dividends will not be paid
VDG1L
Arco Vara AS VAS will be held in 2018. May 3rd For a dividend it is offered to pay 0.01 euros per share.
ARC1T
Siguldas CMAS proposes to pay the shareholders' meeting 0.08 euros.
SCM1RAB Vilkyškių Pieninė on the initiative and decision of the Board of Vilkyskiu pienine 2018 April 27 13 o'clock AB Vilkyškių Pieninė at the premises of the address, P. Lukošaičio g. 14, Vilkyškiai, LT-99254 Pagėgiai municipality, an ordinary general meeting of shareholders is convened. Participants are registered from 12:00. till 12 o'clock 50 min
Meeting agenda:
Company in 2017 approval of the annual report.
Auditor's conclusion about the company's 2017 consolidated and separate financial statements.
Company in 2017 Approved audited consolidated and separate financial statements.
Company in 2017 approving the distribution of profit (loss).
Due to the unused reserve for buying own shares.
Election of members of the Board for a four-year term.
The Company does not give shareholders the opportunity to participate, vote and give power to represent them at the General Meeting of Shareholders by electronic means of communication.
The accounting day of the General Meeting of Shareholders - 2018 April 20 Persons who at the end of the accounting day of the General Meeting of Shareholders were entitled to participate and vote at the General Meeting of Shareholders, in person, with the exception of the exceptions provided for by law, or their authorized persons, or persons with whom a vesting agreement has been concluded.
Shareholder Rights Account Date - 2018 May 14 Persons who were shareholders on the tenth working day after the end of the general meeting that adopted the relevant resolution have property rights.
**
2018 April 6 AB Vilkyškių Pienine (hereinafter referred to as AB Vilkyškių Pienine or the Company) decided:
- To approve the Company's consolidated annual report prepared by the auditor and evaluated by the auditor for 2017 and submit it to the Company's ordinary general meeting for approval.
- To approve the audited 2017 The consolidated and separate financial statements of the Company and submitted to the Company's Ordinary General Meeting of Shareholders for approval in 2017. consolidated and separate financial statements.
AB Vilkyškių Pieninė Group in 2017 Sales revenue was 113.9 million EUR, compared to 2016. income - 90.5 million EUR, increased by 26 per cent. 2017 net profit - EUR 6.7 million in 2016 net profit - 4.5 million EUR, increased by 49 per cent.
- The Board of the Company proposes, in view of the Company's financial results for 2017 and the dividend policy approved by the company's shareholders, proposes to the shareholders of the company to approve 1,672 million euros in dividends for 2017, which equals 0.14 EUR per share. Dividend offer is formed considering the fact that the dividend amount must be not less than 25% of the Company's consolidated net profit for the previous year but not more than the Company's annual consolidated net profit for the year 2017.
- To approve the Company's 2017 net audited profit for the IFRS allocation plan below and to submit it for approval to the General Meeting of Shareholders.
Draft decision: To approve the distribution of net audited profit in 2017 according to IFRS as follows:
Thousand EUR
1) Retained earnings (loss) at the end of 2016 16,822
2) Dividends approved by shareholders for 2016 (1,433)
3) Transfers from other reserves 136
4) Retained earnings (losses) at the beginning of the accounting year after the payment of dividends and transfer to reserves 15,525
5) Net profit (loss) for the reporting financial year 6,202
6) Distributable result - profit at the end of the financial year 21,727
7) Transfers from reserves 2,508
8) Distributable profit (loss): 24,235
the share of profit allocated to the mandatory reserves
-
the portion of profit allocated to the reserve for the purchase of own shares
-
the portion of profit allocated to pay dividends
(1,672)
share of profit allocated to other reserves
-
9) Retained earnings (losses) at the end of the reporting financial year, carried over to the next financial year 22,563
- To approve the decision to abolish the unused reserve for the purchase of own shares and submit it for approval of the Company's ordinary general meeting:
- The Board proposes to select six Board members for a four-year term and submit it to the Company's Ordinary General Meeting for approval. Candidates for the Board: Gintaras Bertašius, Sigitas Trijonas, Rimantas Jancevičius, Vilija Milaševičiutė, Linas Strelis and Andij Cyba.
- To convene an ordinary general meeting of AB Vilkyškių Pieninė in 2018 April 27 13.00 address P. Lukosaičio g. 14, Vilkyškiai, LT-99254 Pagėgių sav. and to propose to the meeting the following draft agenda:
Buy, as the price continues to rise.
VLP1L