Prepared by the Department of Tax Payers of the State Tax Inspectorate under the FM of the Republic of Lithuania
Dividend income tax
1. The following is a duly completed form of the corporate income tax return FR0640 and its annexes: Annex FR0640U "II. Dividends and deductible corporation tax payable to foreign entities "and Annex FR0640G" III. Taxes on dividends received from foreign entities and the corporation tax calculated therefrom ".
This form was approved by the order of the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Lithuania No 20 VA-101 "On the Approval of the Rules for Filing and Submitting the Form of the Dividend Income Tax Declaration FR0640, its Addenda".
2. To be paid in 2018 April profit dividend tax.
Payment code:
1001 - Declared taxes administered by the State Tax Inspectorate and from 01.07.2015 fines for administrative offenses, paid in one contribution code
Income tax on income
1. The form FR0313 of the income (sums) paid out to the foreign taxable units duly completed and calculated on the basis of the corporation tax return, is approved, as approved by the Order of the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Lithuania No. 2002. 40 "On Approval of the Form FR0313 of the Revenue (sums) Disbursed to Foreign Taxable Units and the Form of their Corporate Income Tax" and the Form for Completing this Form ". The declaration must be submitted by persons who deduct corporation tax, who, in accordance with the procedure of the income tax, deduct the income tax from foreign units.
The declaration is also provided by a foreign entity, having received income from performers and sports activities in Lithuania, for the sale or other transfer of ownership of immovable property located in the territory of the Republic of Lithuania, or for the rental of such property, if such income is received not through a permanent establishment in Lithuania, and such income is are received from a non-resident of the Republic of Lithuania or from another foreign entity not through his permanent residence in Lithuania.
2. To be paid in 2018 April profit tax calculated on income (sums) paid to a foreign entity.
Payment code:
1001 - Declared taxes administered by the State Tax Inspectorate and from 01.07.2015 fines for administrative offenses, paid in one contribution code
Excise taxes
1. Owners and registered beneficiaries of excise goods warehouses submit duly completed Form FR0630 of excise duty and its annexes, approved by Order No. 3 of the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Lithuania. VA-106 "On the Approval of Rules Regarding the Formulation of Excise Dues FR0630, FR0630A, and their Filing and Submission Regulations".
The obligation to pay the advance amount of excise duty arises if, for a specific warehouse of excise goods, the amount of excise duty payable to the budget of the owner of the warehouse (or the corresponding registered beneficiary) over the past three tax periods exceeds EUR 15 000 in the course of the next tax period, which was revealed by these circumstances, until the 15th of the current tax period. the advance amount of excise duty is paid to the budget. This advance amount of excise duty is equal to 1/3 of the average amount of excise duty payable to the budget, which was (or should have) been declared in the declarations of the 3 previous tax periods referred to in this paragraph.
2. Registered, non-registered suppliers of coal, coke, lignite, unlicensed electricity, persons who declare natural gas excise duties, temporarily registered beneficiaries submit duly completed form of excise duty declaration FR0630A and its annexes, approved by the order of the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Lithuania No 26 . VA-106 "On the Approval of Rules Regarding the Formulation of Excise Dues FR0630, FR0630A, and their Filing and Submission Regulations".
3. Excise duties and excise taxes are paid.
Owners and registered recipients of excise goods warehouses, as well as electricity licensed persons, must submit declarations FR0630 or FR0630A, irrespective of whether the obligation to pay excise taxes for the tax period has arisen or not.
Payment code:
1001 - Declared taxes administered by the State Tax Inspectorate and from 01.07.2015 fines for administrative offenses, paid in one contribution code
Income tax
1. The duly completed form of the April Monthly Income Tax Declaration GPM313, approved by the order of the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Finance No. 207 of 2017, shall be submitted. VA-121 "On Approval of the Monthly Income Tax Declaration Form GPM3013 and its Filing and Submission Regulations".
2. If a person who deducts a payment in respect of a relationship of employment or a relationship of substance fulfills the related payments of the tax period of the relevant tax period in installments and disburses the whole benefit during that month, the person who deduct the tax must pay the deducted income tax to the budget before the 15th of the month if the last Payment was paid out by 15th of this month.
Payment Codes:1311 - a person's income tax on the income of a resident with an employment relationship or an essentially corresponding relationship with that tax period in Class A
1330 - Personal Income Tax on B-Class Benefits Payable to Individuals Which Have Been Taxed and / or Benefit-Paying Taxes for Tax Periods From 01/01/2012
1411 - personal income tax on the benefits of Class A unrelated to residents with employment relationships or relationships that are essentially equivalent
1421 - personal income tax on the income from the sale of assets not related to the relationship of an employer with the employment relationship or their substantive maturity (for tax periods until 31 January 2017)
Compulsory deductions from raw wood and do not cut timber sales revenue
1. The duly completed Form FR0463 of the Declaration of Income Taxes on Raw Mines and Cut Timber Sales is presented. The form and the rules for its completion and submission are approved by the Order of the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Republic of Lithuania No. 2003. V-179 "On the Approval of the Form FR0463 Declaration of Income Taxes on Raw Timber and Non-Turned Forest Sales and its Completion".
2. To be paid in 2018 Mandatory deductions from raw wood in April and income from sales of forest are not foreclosed.
Payment code:
1001 - Declared taxes administered by the State Tax Inspectorate and from 01.07.2015 fines for administrative offenses, paid in one contribution code
Charity and support
1. Sponsors referred to in Article 5 of the Law on Charity and Support. 2 d In Item 1, after 2017 providing support in accordance with the procedure established by the said law, county tax authorities must submit duly completed forms of the Support Report Annual Report FR0477.
2. Beneficiaries referred to in Article 7 of the Law on Charity and Support. Paragraph 1, in the year 2017, after receiving support and / or providing support and / or charity in accordance with the procedure established by the LPI, county tax collectors must submit duly completed forms of the Annual Report on the receipt and use of assistance FR0478.
This form has been approved by the order of the Head of the State Tax Inspectorate under the Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Lithuania No. 10.04.2003. V-103 "On Approval of the Form FR0477 of the Annual Report on Provision of Support and the Form for Completing the Form FR0478 of the Annual Report on the Receipt and Use of Support".
Hydrocarbon Resource Fee
1. Fill in the year 2018. Form FR0566 of the quarterly declaration for the Hydrocarbon Resource Tax of the 1st quarter, approved by Order No NIM of the STI under the PM of the Republic of Lithuania. V-13 "On Approval of the Rules for Completing the Form FR0566 for the Declaration of Hydrocarbons".
2. Fee for hydrocarbon resources.
Payment code:
1001 - Declared taxes administered by the State Tax Inspectorate and from 01.07.2015 fines for administrative offenses, paid in one contribution code
Fee for public natural resources
1. The form KIT708 of the tax declaration for mineral resources, water and building soil duly completed by the order of the Head of the Ministry of Environment and the STI under the Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Lithuania dated 12.12.2006 dated 27.12.2006 was duly completed for the taxation period of 01/01/2018 2018 2018. D1-614 / VA-99 "On Approval of the Procedure for the Taxation of the Republic of Lithuania for State Natural Resources, their Filing and Submission".
2. The state fee for the use of natural resources is paid.
Payment code:
1001 - Declared taxes administered by the State Tax Inspectorate and from 01.07.2015 fines for administrative offenses, paid in one contribution code
Sugar surplus tax
The duly completed form for the Sugar surplus tax declaration KIT710 2016-2017, approved by the Order of the Head of the STI under the FM of Lithuania on 09.05.2007, shall be provided. VA-33 "On the Form of the Sugar Production Tax Declaration KIT707 and the Rules for its Completion, and the Approval of the Form KIT710 for the Sugar Transfer Tax Declaration and the Form for its Completion".
                      Providing electronic VAT invoices (i.SAF)
When taxpayers - VAT payers - carry out economic (taxable and / or non-taxable) and non-economic activities (for example, state or municipal functions), they are obliged to provide STI with all VAT invoices issued and received (for both economic and non-economic activity data). In this case, the data of the registers shall be provided starting from the month of the calendar year in which the person was engaged in an economic activity and shall be provided before the end of the calendar year, regardless of whether or not those activities were carried out during those periods.