1
2012-04-06 02:43:14
BNS info
Text Size:
Print
Vilniaus baldai, controlled by Invalda, which last year earned 26.824 million litas of audited net profit, intends to allocate 38.863 million litas (11.255 million euros) of dividends or 10 litas (2.9 euros) per share for this year.
The shareholders will consider such a proposal by "Vilniaus baldai" board on April 27th.
"The company works successfully and does not have debts, therefore we are offering to pay out the free funds to the shareholders," Vytautas Bučas, Chairman of the Board of Vilniaus Baldai, said in a press release.
A 3 million litas tantemose are being submitted to the shareholders' meeting, and in the next year it is planned to transfer LTL 33.5 thousand of profit. At the end of April, the furniture producer will allocate 41.896 million litas of profit.
The Board of "Vilniaus baldai" is proposing to re-cast current members - the main shareholders of "Invalda" - V. Bučas, Darius Šulnis and Dalius Kaziunas for the new 4-year term.
According to audited data, "Vilniaus baldai" earned 26.823 million litas of net profit - 3.4 percent last year. less than before, when it amounted to 27.848 million litas. Net audited profit of "Vilniaus baldai" group last year decreased by 3.8 percent. up to 26,811 million litas, is announced in the company's 2011 financial statements.
According to audited data, "Vilniaus baldai" revenue last year, compared to 2010, increased by 20.9 percent. up to 238,368 million litas, while the turnover of "Vilniaus baldai" group was equal to the turnover of the main company. The audit did not change the turnover of "Vilniaus baldai".
Vilniaus baldai exports almost all of the products bought by the Swedish concern Ikea.
Last year, Invalda was managed by 72.14%, Swedbank's 10.07% customers, including 10,01% of the KJK Fund registered in Luxembourg. "Vilniaus baldų" authorized capital.
The shares of "Vilniaus baldai" are listed on the Main List.


Ads
Notify me of updates to
news
Portal
guest
Ask
a specialist
Discussions
weather
TV
the program
Dating
Games
Horoscopes
Novelty
RSS feed
Facebook
Twitter
The most economically powerful region in China is Lithuanian lessons
Lithuania can not only learn, but also help to grow others. This was reappeared after the July 17th delegation of the delegation from Guangdong, one of the most important and most economically viable provinces in China, visited ...
Thousands of residents - Sodra reminders to pay contributions
Sodra has today sent notifications to 6,321 residents, who may have to pay a compulsory health insurance (PSD) on their own. Messages posted by Sodra Personal ...
Revealed a way to attract employees by offering lower pay
More and more companies are finding difficulty finding competent staff. Young people without a lot of experience at once want a high salary, professional and competent potential employees are also becoming more and more difficult to afford, and i ...
Employers suspect employees of abusing "bulletins"
Employers in the catering industry suspect employees of abusing sick leave - they are likely to get sick, but social networks say they've actually celebrated or been vacationing. Sodra believes that summer is not here & sca ...
3
A greener and more competitive business - 1.5 million euros in EU investment
The Ministry of Economy offers 1.5 million euros to companies seeking to grow more green and become more competitive on the international market. The third call for applications for micro, small and medium-sized enterprises under the ...
Rokiškis businessmen: we have two problems - emigration abroad and to Vilnius
The Rokiskis Independence Square, located midway between Vilnius and Riga, is almost non-existent on Friday afternoon. ...
Holidays Abroad: What Is It Worth to Arrange In Forecast?
Lithuanians are increasingly traveling and resting abroad, but not all the impressions and adventures are pleasant. While staying abroad, four residents of Lithuania are suffering daily - with such an intensity of customer messages this year ...
The year with the new Labor Code: salvation or fiasco?
The Labor Code was not promised to employees for the promised happiness. Maybe a newer code will replace life? "We need to defend our rights, but if our people do not want anything, it's good as it is," he says, "can stand on his head, there will be nothing", & nd ...
11
Does your dream reward cost EUR 1,500?
Over the last two years, households have been improving their financial position. 66 percent households indicated that their financial situation is good or medium (58 percent of respondents said that two years ago). But a third of res ...
9
The whole truth about discount cards: what are they really useful for?
Loy cards seem to have already crashed into the wallets of buyers, and if you do not have any cards, you will be happy to offer it at the box office. However, who are they more important to: buyer or seller? ...
5
More articles