1
Last year, the company Olifėja, the largest lottery organizer in Lithuania, earned a net profit of 5.217 million euros - 8.1%. more than in 2016, when it was 4.826 million euros.
The report to the Center of Registers states that the company intends to pay dividends to shareholders of EUR 4 million this year. The same amount was allocated to dividends last year.
51.3 percent The shares of "Olifėja" belong to the Lithuanian National Olympic Committee, after 17.85 percent. - Antanas and Janinas Muraškoms, after 5.5 percent. - Donatas and Eglis Kazlauskas, 2% - Romualdas Domeika.
The company's sales revenue increased 3.2 percent over the year, to 74.596 million euros. Perl's digital lottery revenue dropped 1.3 percent to EUR 45.3 million, while instant lottery grew by 11.1 percent to 29.3 million euros.
According to Olifeya, the company last year occupied 81 percent. Lithuanian lottery market (97% in 2016).
The BNS news agency's information is reproduced on mass media and on websites without the written consent of UAB BNS.