0
Workers in the painting shop recall how a small, practically domestic event - a sewage pipe accident occurred at the factory. Spilled waste has blocked them to work. And what should be done in this case? Under normal circumstances, work will simply stop, because going through such a mass is neither pleasant nor safe. A slippery and so-injured worker will be described through all media. But this time, as Tesla employee Dennis Duran remembers, managers have led the way through straightforward waste, as Model 3 was in a hurry.
It would only be a funny story, perhaps even showing the company's commitment to contributing to the production of Model 3. And in fact, sometimes you have to do everything to do your job properly. However, this story is reminiscent of other Tesla security issues. Since 2013, Tesla's main factory has detected 40 security breaches, but former employees said half the lips that the situation was actually much worse.
Earlier it was announced that Tesla's factories often visit emergency services. Workers were often traumatized, working very closely with robots, moving conveyors and cars and trucks. The reasons can be searched in different places. First of all, Tesla has employed a very large number of people for a relatively short time. A lot of them had no experience and, probably, competencies. Secondly, rapid automation did not allow for proper adjustment of the movement of people and machinery in the factory. It should not be forgotten that Tesla is a very young automotive company, so the lack of experience is obvious.
The worst thing is that incidents were possibly hidden. In April, a statement appeared that part of the incidents were due to Tesla's avoidance of warning signs and adhesive stickers for aesthetic reasons. In other words, alerts for employees could not be installed, because they would look awkward. It was also alleged that the company may have misconstrued the trauma of workers so that it does not impair the company's image.
Tesla strongly denies this and claims that employee safety is central. Whatever the situation, the situation will only improve in the future, as Tesla gains experience - employees will be trained better, production lines will be better adjusted. Injuries are occurring in all large factories, and the ambition to become the safest factory in the world is welcome.