1
To improve the quality of browsing, we use cookies on this site. If you agree, click "I agree", otherwise go ahead and browse. You can cancel your consent at any time by changing your browser settings and deleting saved cookies. Learn more about our cookie policy here.
Posted: March 31, 2016
Source: News of INVL Baltic Real Estate
Investments in real estate company INVL Baltic Real Estate for 2017 will give shareholders a dividend of 1.71 million euros or 0.13 euros per share. Today's General Meeting of Shareholders approved this decision. Dividends will be paid within a month from this decision, and will be available to investors who will be INVAL Baltic Real Estate shareholders at the end of April 10 this year.
  The value of the consolidated equity capital of INVL Baltic Real Estate in 2017. at the end of the year amounted to 33.86 million euros. The equity value per share (calculated on the basis of the number of shares and the nominal value of the share after the change in the nominal value of the company's shares and the change in the number of shares at the beginning of 2018) was EUR 2.57 and grew by 11 per cent during the year. (At the end of 2016, the equity value per share was EUR 2.36, as well as the payment of dividends of EUR 0.06 per share).
  It is planned that this year the share capital of INVL Baltic Real Estate will increase in 2017. Invalda INVL has announced plans to transfer up to 22% this year. managing the company's shares, thus increasing the share of free float shares from 16% to 38%. It is planned that the acquisition of INVL Baltic Real Estate shares will be offered to institutional investors, and later, after approval by the Bank of Lithuania of the company's prospectus, in which the share price and distribution order would be established, shares would be offered to retail investors.
  INVL Baltic Real Estate owns real estate in Vilnius and Riga: offices and commercial premises in the Vilnius Gate complex, the IBC business center near Konstitucijos avenue and office buildings in the Old Town of Vilnius street, in the northern town, as well as the production, storage of Dommo business park and office complex near the Riga bypass. 2017 According to the data of December 31, the area of assets managed by INVL Baltic Real Estate was 56,9 thousand sq. m. m, the value is EUR 56.3 million.
  80 percent The assets owned by INVL Baltic Real Estate are based in the central part of Vilnius, their employment in 2017. at the end of the year ranged from 78% to 100%.
  From 2016 On December 22, INVL Baltic Real Estate operates as a closed-ended investment company (UTIB). The management of the company was taken over by one of the leading asset management companies in the country "INVL Asset Management". The company will operate in UTIB until 2046. with the possibility of extending this term for another 20 years.

Return to news list