1
2018-04-27 17:00:00
day.lt info
Text Size:
Print
State-controlled oil and liquefied natural gas (LNG) stevedoring company Klaipedos Nafta has allocated the entire net profit earned last year to its dividends - EUR 17.031 million, or nearly 4.5 cent per share.
The shareholders of the company decided on Friday, "Klaipėdos nafta" informed Nasdaq Vilnius Stock Exchange.
Last year, the company paid out 9.656 million euros in dividends, or 2.54 cents per share.
The shareholders of the company elected Tom Lukoševičius, Eimantas Kiudula and Andrius Varanavičius to the company's supervisory board.
The audited net profit of "Klaipedos Nafta" last year, compared with 2016, increased by 23.5 percent. to 17,031 million euros, audited revenue - 2.5 percent. up to 106,484 million euros.
The state owns 72.32 percent. The shares of Klaipedos Nafta, concern Achema Group - 10.24 per cent.
Klaipedos Nafta shares are quoted on the Main List.


Ads
Notify me of updates to
news
Portal
guest
Ask
a specialist
Discussions
weather
TV
the program
Dating
Games
Horoscopes
Novelty
RSS feed
Facebook
Twitter
People are shaking: "VIP" circus - tortured animals?
Animals in circuses are great passions. When a clip was opened in Klaipėda, where the cats were seen with the owner of the circus, people did not regret criticizing the need to ban animal appearances. Although the port himself ...
7
Harmonized investments of Klaipėda Energy
The National Control Commission for Prices and Energy (NCCPE) has coordinated investments of AB Klaipėdos Energija for the total amount of 1.355 million EUR, for which it is planned to use EU structural funds support. ...
It is hoped to reduce the fees of Klaipėda port
In order to increase the turnover of Klaipėda port container distribution center, to ensure long-term loyalty of shipping lines, it is planned to reduce ship levies, the newspaper "Lietuvos Žinios" writes. ...
Klaipeda region will form a development strategy
Klaipėda region municipalities will form a unified vision of tourism and agriculture sectors in 2030. - the process of developing a sectoral development study, which will begin in the first half of the year, which will form the integral part of tourism and land of Klaipeda ...
6
On the covered balconies - pigeon lights
The Smiltelis street's nineteenth-century caused dissatisfaction among the population with unwanted neighbors. The second staircase in the 5th and 7th floor uncovered common use balconies is dervishes and doves. It is said that the president of the community does not go ...
3
Against the partisan commander A. Ramanauskas-Vanagas - delusions
Member of the Klaipėda Council Vyacheslav Titov joined the proposal of the daughter of Adolph Ramanauskas-Vanagas to commemorate her father-Lithuanian partisan commander in the seaport. Politics has publicly praised this mint ...
76
Need to arrange School Street
The pipelines' work on the street stops car traffic and loses its drivers for driving. Municipal officials believe they have the means to demand that the streets raiseth the workers to them ...
3
Hurry to free the Old Town
The area of Žveju Street, which was excavated last year, was re-equated with the construction equipment. Workers are hurrying to do this before the Sea Festival, so that the residents of Klaipėda and the city would not be able to see the video of the damaged Old Town ...
6
Port of Klaipėda profit - 20%. bigger
Klaipėda port's performance continues to exceed expectations. 2018 January-June Klaipėda port handled 22.2 million tons of cargo, which is 7.6 percent. or 1 566,0 thousand tons more than last year during the same period. ...
3
Think about the investment of Klaipėda Energy
At the Friday meeting, the State Control Commission for Prices and Energy should coordinate the investments made by heat supplier Klaipėdos Energija this year, with an estimated amount of 1.35 million euros. ...
More articles