1
This is indicated on the company's annual report published on the Nasdaq Vilnius Stock Exchange on Thursday. The dividend transfer will still have to be decided by the company's shareholder - the Ministry of Finance.
For 2016, the company transferred 100.7 million euros to the state budget, 86 million euros for 2015, and 52.7 million euros for 2014.
The annual report also indicates that the audit of the company made some adjustments to the company's financial results for the previous year.
According to audited data, last year the company's consolidated revenue decreased by 0.1%. to EUR 1,101 billion. At the end of February, it was announced that incomes decreased by 0.5% per year. to € 1,096 billion.
In turn, Lietuvos Energija earned 93.525 million euros of audited consolidated net profit last year - 21 per cent. less than in 2016, when it was 118,438 million euros. In a preliminary announcement, the company announced that it earned 91.546 million euros of consolidated net profit last year - 22.7 percent. less than before.
In the fall of last year, the Ministry of Finance refused to offer Lietuvos Energija nearly € 44 million in dividends for the first half of 2017 and said they would be paid out in 2018. Such a decision was taken because the state budget exceeded the planned revenue.
The sole shareholder of Lietuvos Energija is the Ministry of Finance. The Group is owned by ESO, LEG "Lietuvos dujos", "Litgas", and other companies.