0
The first two places remained the same - the most popular are still the economist Gitanas Nausėda and the Mayor of Kaunas, Visvaldas Matijonasitis. True, their both ratings fell slightly - in May, for Mr Nausėda, they would have voted 21.6%. of respondents, in June - 20.6 percent. for V. Matijošaitė, in May, would have voted 11.6 percent. of respondents, and in June - 10%.
The biggest change in June is the loss of Prime Minister S. Skverneles' position. In May, they would have voted 9.7 percent. of the respondents, and in June, already 6.3%. Due to the fall of S. Skvernė another candidate - V. Ušackas, whose rating has not significantly changed, has risen to third place. In May, for V. Ušackas, they would vote 6.5%. of respondents in June - 6.7%.
Also, as many as 23 percent of the respondents said they did not know what to vote for, or they were not going to vote in general. In May, such people were 29%.
Make conclusions early
Małvydas Jastramskis, a political scientist at the Institute of International Relations and Political Science of the University of Vilnius, believes that it is still too early to draw conclusions about the changes in the rating table, as next month ratings may look different again.
"The question that arises here is whether this is intrinsic or accidental, which is often the case in such investigations. There are always differences between the two surveys, maybe three percent. It is unclear whether this indicates a genuine decline in popularity, or is it just the elementary random sampling error. Another thing, maybe other polls show it, "- said M.Jastramskis in DELFI.
Asked about the reasons why V. Ušackas could rise to the first three, and whether this is related to his position towards Russia, the political scientist emphasized that the rating of this candidate has not essentially changed, and the third place he has risen only due to the fall of S. Skvernelis' rating . Therefore, if this is not just a short-term detriment, the reasons for the search should be sought not in the rhetoric of V. Ušackas, but in S. Skvernelis's activities.
"I think that he (falling - red.) With a specific public policy is less involved - whether with Russia, or with taxes, or the like. I would not be surprised if this would be the next month and would actually lower that rating, due to institutional tension.
The squadron occupies the post of head of executive power, and from the executive branch, from the government and from the parliament, Lithuanians always require a great deal of time, they expect rapid changes in terms of welfare, security, order, law, etc. And any person who occupies that post will continue to grow in the ratings as much as possible (...) In this regard, this is not related to Skvernij, it is related to the misery that he occupies. And that trajectory will not go up as long as he is the prime minister, "my political scientist at TSPMI.
Personality struggle
He also noticed that, despite the fall, S. Skvernelis has stayed at the top of the rating for quite some time. According to a political scientist, this can be attributed to the personal qualities of the Prime Minister, even bearing in mind that presidential elections are essentially personal elections.
"One can look at this thing from the other side: according to the political situation, according to the long-term political orientations of Lithuania, what are the preconditions for holding Skvernius among the main leaders? One thing is, since presidential elections are naturally highly oriented towards specific personalities, Skvernelis has such personality traits as solidity, determination, which is well appreciated by Lithuanians, "- said M.Jastramskis in DELFI.
Mažvydas Jastramskis
According to him, the leader of the ranking table, Kaunas Mayor M. Matijošaitis, has similar characteristics. Although he is not involved in national politics, he is mentioned in ratings as a potential presidential candidate.
"It would seem that his type is a good city administrator, a good man, a good manager, no ideology, well-managed, pragmatic, fit for an average Lithuanian who does not want politics but wants good leadership. On the other hand, in general, not only here in Lithuania, there is such a thing as a political legend, a political myth that always develops and it is difficult to deny it - Matijošaitis has such a legend that good, recovering, managing Kaunas myth. Again, until he comes into national politics, the legend will probably survive unless something happens in Kaunas, "my political scientist said.
The role of the parties in the party
In the first ranking of five, only one V. Ušackas has publicly announced his candidacy for the presidential election. Neither G. Nausėda nor V. Matijošaitis nor S. Skvernelis or Ingrida Šimonytė have not yet published their final decision. M. Jastramskis believes that such a strategy is successful, since after the announcement of candidacy a person falls into a completely different political background."Presidential elections in Lithuania are particularly unstable and if there is not such a prominent leader as Grybauskaitė, it is very difficult to predict. This is due to the fact that people still do not care now what they will vote for, they do not know who they will vote for, this rating is like a picture. Since the candidates know that many people are still undecided, they decide on that and keep it as long as possible. If you publish, then there can be a negative focus, and nothing will come of it. You pay attention to yourself one day, maybe two, but then you forget about it all because you do not think about the elections. And those people who write articles have already demanded a lot from these candidates, "said M. Jastramskis.
He also regretted that there is not one party leader in the broad sense at the top of the list. In the opinion of the political scientist, this indicates the weakness of the Lithuanian parties.
"There are no strong candidates in this rating who would be considered as an elite leader in those traditional parties. These elections confirm once again the simple point that our parties are in fact very weak, their roots are very poorly tolerated in society. I'm sad about this thing. This shows that we do not have party democracy, "said political scientist DELFI.
According to him, not only the presidents of the parties could go to the elections, but also other significant parties to the parties. However, these ratings confirm once again that such people, at least so far, are absent in Lithuania.
Spinter tyrimai, a public opinion and market research company, conducted a public opinion poll on June 19-27, 2018, on the website of the news portal DELFI. The study involved residents aged 18 to 75 years. The survey was conducted using the standardized interview method.
The study was conducted throughout the territory of Lithuania, a total of 65 selective points, arranged in such a way as to represent the entire territory of the country. The survey interviewed 1003 respondents. The distribution of survey participants is proportional to the population of the country's regions.
The error of the research results is 3.1%.
It is strictly forbidden to use the information published by DELFI on other websites, in the media or elsewhere or to distribute our material in some form without consent, and if consent is obtained, it is necessary to indicate DELFI as a source.