0
PHOTO GALLERY Building at the intersection of Lieliai and Savičius streets (4 photos)
Photo by Rūta Vizbariene (VŽ)
Photo by Vladimir Ivanov (VZ)
In the Old Town of Vilnius, at the intersection of Lieliai and Savičius streets, Collkling space "Workland", Queensberry restaurant and luxury clothing store are created. Previously, Nordea's branch operated.
On the first floor of the building 210 sq. The area of вЂ <вЂ <creates a restaurant, 290 sq. km. m has rented the name so far not wanting to reveal the store, and 1,260 sq. km. m will occupy a collaborative space, announced the concept of a lease developed by NT Real Estate Management, Consultancy and Mediation UAB Solid Real Advisors. This building houses the "Two Brothers" shop located here earlier.
Workland, a cooperative space operator operating in the Baltic States, plans to offer 110-130 jobs on the market on two floors. At present, the company has 2,000 sq. M. m area of collaborative space at Gedimino Ave., where the cost per workplace varies between 220-300 EUR / month.
"All former bank headquarters premises were leased after the decision to move out in just 6 months. We analyzed three different scenarios, including hotel and rental of the entire building for offices or supermarkets, but the concept of "retail space plus offices" turned out to be the optimal solution. I would say that such a model makes it possible to make the most of the main advantages of the city center - the location, prestige and flows of people - most effectively, "said Dom Jagmin, Solid Real Advisors' partner, commercial project manager.
The owner of the building is UAB Nordija. Its shares are managed by Cypriot companies: 44% - Inorate Limited, 30% - Blixgate Holdings Limited. The remaining 26% are owned by Autotrade Corporation, as shown by Creditinfo's Center of Registers.
Nordia received 0.6 million euros in revenue last year and suffered a loss of almost 0.1 million euros. 2016 earned the same income and earned a net profit of 0.03 million euros. 2017 At the end of the year, the company managed assets for EUR 6.7 million.
Follow the NT Market News and Trends on the Facebook page of "VZ Real Estate"
write a comment