0
The world of Donald Trump and Vladimir Putin on Monday in Helsinki is still under the baton. Frustrated critics of the US president are afraid of what it can do in the future.
On Tuesday, around the world, media coverage was dazzling with headlines that were well summarized by the Finnish daily Kauppalehti's first page: "D.Trumpas - 0, V. Putin - 1".
Whatever the outcome of this meeting, it is now considering what is expected of Russia-US relations.
No matter how Russia is now pleased that D.Trumpas it has become the best US president, he could imagine the Kremlin, the future may not be so bright.
The Russian media were pleased with their president's pride, but they also realized that they would not have to expect a rosy road in the future.
"Modest D.Trumpas flashed against V. Putin. Clearly, it turned out to be better.
It puts pride in it, but it also raises concerns - winning against Trumpe does not mean winning against the entire US political class.
It's scary that Washington can answer that, "wrote the Russian publication Moskovskij komsomolec.
10 photos
The Russians are glad that Putin succeeded in curtailing Trumpa. However, he is not the only US policymaker.
This is probably the main reason for the Kremlin to worry.
After a press conference in which Dr Trump has repeatedly denied that Russian interference with the US Foreign Intelligence Agency was announced by the US presidential election, and said that Putin was relying on Putin's words that there was no interference, Washington's feelings for Russia would not really work.
And any attempts by the White House to continue to approach Moscow with the American political elite can again be declared a betrayal.
Moreover, the bullying of all sides D. Trumpa, who cares about the image is extremely important, can lead to totally unpredictable revenge.
Even members of his party did not spare the critics of D.Trumpai. Republican Senator John McCain said that it was one of the shameful appearances of the US president.
The presentation was critically evaluated by political scientists.
University of Helsinki Professor Veli Pekka Tynkkynen "Lithuanian morning said that, in his opinion, the Russian leader with questions at a press conference coped better.
"He not only denied helping Truman win the election, but also presented his own accusations against the influence of Russia in Russia, which could be said to have pushed the ball to the other side of the network. The US leader did not show such ability, "the Russian expert said.
The fact that the US president has decided to declare Washington being guilty of relations with deteriorated countries just like Moscow has begun to talk even about the change in his doctrine.
"His slogan" America first "turned into" First of all, I ", - the reviewers of the news agency AP said.
Presumably, representatives of other countries of the old continent predict that such a situation would not have happened to him. NATO summit criticized German Foreign Minister Heiko Maas before the US and Russian presidents Skela agreement: "We can no longer completely trust the White House."
It is important that H. Masas also referred not to the whole of America, but to D. Trump's residence. Apparently, this reflects the fact that Europeans increasingly seek to connect with Washington through other channels by avoiding an unpredictable president.
What about Syria, Ukraine and other issues that the Presidents have said have been discussed? Progress is hard to anticipate, as promising to compete in the energy market or to solve Ukraine's or Syria's issues, even asking them, could not detail them.
Markku Kivinen, research director at the Alexander Institute of Studies at the University of Helsinki, Center for the Study of the University of Helsinki, said that the situation in Syria remains complicated, so it would be difficult to expect abrupt changes there.
"This is not about the lack of political will for leaders.
Just presidents are not independent, and the crucial role played by the relations between the army and military industry, "-" Lithuanian morning "explained political scientist.