0
According to the lawyer Gintaras Černiauskas, the impression is that the prosecutor's office began to delay the time and did not investigate the case.
"The prosecutor responded to our requests in writing, which prevented us from submitting complaints. We complained to the Prosecutor General's Office of such actions by the prosecutor, and also requested that the investigation of the case be taken over by the Prosecutor General's Office. However, the Prosecutor General's Office has not yet expressed the will to take over the case. However, the prosecutor investigating the case has been given an order for the replies to be lodged, without prejudice to appeal. I get the impression that the case is being delayed, but I really do not know the reasons for that, "says G. Černiauskas.
The lawyer says that the ice cream has moved a bit only after a complaint to the Prosecutor General's Office, which ordered the prosecutor investigating the case to be removed from the proceedings, that is, to answer the questions as it relates to the case, and not at his own discretion.
According to the lawyer, it is also strange to him that the investigation of the case becomes more similar to that of the court rather than the work of the prosecutor's office.
"The prosecutor's case is to gather evidence and transfer it to the court where defendants are given the opportunity to defend themselves. The evidence is really enough, and you will not be able to gather new evidence after so much time. I would understand if the prosecutor would change tactics, do other actions, but I see that this is not the case.
G. Černiauskas says that he is also surprised at the fact that neither the number of suspects in the case nor suspicion of Mr Pinkis is changing. He is accused of bringing suicide and the distribution of narcotic substances. However, the evidence provided that, according to a lawyer, a clear case of trafficking is not a matter for the public prosecutor.
A family-run lawyer says he will still seek to re-examine the General Prosecutor's Office for their application to take over the case and has already lodged a refusal complaint. Moreover, in his opinion, if the case is not taken over, it is not useless to delay it and all should move to court.
DELFI reminds that the girl was killed on November 20, she was informed about the misfortune at 19.30. Originally a witness named by R. Pinikas claimed that the girl came with her from Vilnius to Klaipėda voluntarily. However, in the course of the investigation, he became a suspect for induction of suicide, and further investigators and evidence gathered this week to raise suspicions about drug trafficking.
There were R. Pinikas and one more man on the day of the girl's death on the balcony. The prosecutor's office did not file any suspicions either because of the death of the girl or because she was stunned.
After a mischievous girlfriend, a girlfriend told me that Pinikas, following the presentation of Juozas Statkevičius' collection in Vilnius, followed Dovilė and went to her home where the event took place. One of the friends believed that Dovilė was already stunned when she left with R. Pinik in Klaipėda - she had no control over her actions, she was apathetic and weirdly behaved.
Dovilė's relatives after the tragedy told DELFI that they want to know the truth not only for themselves. At the same time, this tragedy reveals that show business, which is being discouraged from speaking publicly. Find out more here.
The lawyer says that according to the evidence available there is sufficient reason for suspect R. Pink to be accused of much more serious crimes: rape because Dovilė was stunned, murdered, trafficked and witnessed by influences.
Rick Pinak's own version of the version of her affairs told her she denied the blame for exploiting the girl. Read more here.
It is strictly forbidden to use the information published by DELFI on other websites, in the media or elsewhere or to distribute our material in some form without consent, and if consent is obtained, it is necessary to indicate DELFI as a source.