0
SUPPORTS THE AUCTIONS
ACTUAL
LITHUANIA
ABROAD
CRIMINALS
WEATHER
COMMENTS
TRIBUNE
HISTORY
VILNIUS KNOWLEDGE
MORE
Post a Newsletter
Sign in
THE LATEST
Angela Merkel: US-Russian summits should be routine
Policymakers in the aftermath of the incident in Klaipeda show the will to ban wildlife appearances
Kaunas police arrested the thief faster than the German victim found theft
Ukraine rejects the possibility of a peace treaty with Gazprom
DETAILED
Kristina Mishiniene: "The photographer touched, and the girls seem to feel it's normal, they only need to suffer"
2 121
What happened to the Titanic Tragedy?
423
The Internet is laughing at the reddening Melanie Trump face after greetings with Putin: watch the video
6 533
A man running at a high speed motorcycle sank in Vilnius
47
Arvydas Sabonis's house in Žaliakalnis is for sale
237
ITAKA.LT
Plan your winter holidays in advance and take advantage of it!
15MIN AKTUALU LITHUANIA
Published: July 18, 2018 09:33
The latter rained hundreds of thousands of damage
Photo by Eglė Girdenytė / Strong rains disrupted traffic in Karoliniškės, cars sank
Author: LRT TV News Service
Source: Lrt.lt
22
After last week's rainfall, municipalities are still counting losses, while insurers say that damage could have been inflicted across the country for 150 thousand euros.
According to employees of the car service center located in Šiauliai, after the storm last week they were approached by more than one customer.
Parts of drivers, even those with casco insurance, will have to pay themselves if losses are due to their fault. For example, it runs on paved streets.
Insurers estimate that damage could be caused in the whole of Lithuania for 150 thousand euros. The most affected by natural disasters were the inhabitants of Šiauliai, Vilnius, Kaunas, Panevėžys, Alytus.
Vasario's rumor to Vilnius
+13
The municipality of Vilnius says it may take a thousand euros to repair a new bike path damaged in Antakalnis. It is planned to do this in two weeks.
Insurers say that due to the changed climatic conditions, the damage caused by the storm is increasing annually.
The lion washes the new bike path on P.Vileišio street on the capital
15min reader Nerijus
SEE ALSO VIEW
02:11
A circus showcases the appearance of a gray bear cast on the Internet
01:46
For 15 minutes, the readers shot down the streets of Vilnius after the rain
The rain blew the P. Vileišis bike path
+19
Vilnius washed the rain
+35
SEE ALSO:
In Japan, the hottest heat flooding has claimed 14 lives
The municipality promises to eliminate the effects of rain on bike paths within two weeks
COMMENTS: 2
22
THEMES: 4
Rain Weather Lies Losses
A
a
NEWS
Ecuadorian assault in Vilnius: The police and the victim's version are radically different
In Kaunas - ballet dancers A.Mikalajūnaitė and V.Osadcenko weddings: first of all fell in love with body language
INTERVIEW
Grygaravičius, Mayor of Alytus, who received the grudge: "I've always been disappointed with politics"
In the scammers case, Mia's husband N.Antanavicius was found guilty: remains in prison until the first breach
Fast not only in basketball: David Gailius presses in drag race
Drinkers buy less, but they pay more for the state
Jonas Gelzinis demonstrates the possibilities: the fastest 1006 km racing training
It's a tradition: the flight of "Small planet airlines" is delayed due to a malfunction
After A.Toupane's departure - warm message from Š.Jasikevičius
Weather forecast: the seaside will be warm and rain free at weekends
+10
In photographs, the plastic bags do not appreciate aesthetics and jeopardy
Thom Mann Festival completes the First World War cycle: Looking at the future when analyzing the past
Why do train drivers not bear on coins to ramps?
The labor force flooded even more: the number of Ukrainians increased by 50 percent per year
Celebrities were horrified by the circus leader N. Zobov's behavior: "Save the animal from the devil's house"
CNN: Suspiced Scribes' Scribes After the US-based commercial flight, fleeing the UK
A rich sheep hat, perfectly negotiating with noodles and rice
S. Mikoliūnas was disappointed with the Faroese challenge: "We have not revealed our true face"
Wizz Air canceled flights for winter: Rome, Athens, Nice
Experts advise not to drink in 6 Lithuanian ponds
NAMES
Police are asking for help: Sandra Grafinina, formerly "Olialia pupyte", returned to her homeland
13 671
The court is a divorce case filed by Millionaire Stasys Brundza and his wife
10 223
The man's and wife's acrobatic numbers have just ended a tragedy: a failed trick is captured by a camera
782
KELIONIUKAADEMIJA.LT
SUMMER holiday offers to BULGARIA only from EUR 279!
IDEA WEEK
Strange wonders and interesting places in Lithuania
Mid-weekend summer weekend menu: Gourmet Vegetable Show
PANORAMA.LT
Even 20 new gourmet food stores!
VIDEO
03:11
The prosecutor will decide whether to appeal to the verdict against N.Antanavich and his colleagues
00:27
The US intelligence chief reacted unexpectedly to the invitation to Putin to visit Washington
00:07A "Make It For Change" Campaign A video clip on straw hunts
FOOD
Lithuanian Deer Test: Where to look for good taste and naturalness?
4
Universal green beans - both fast food and winter supplies
Dinner with Jurgas and Paulius: 2 simple Italian desserts with strawberries
PRACTICAL ADVICE
Summer steak in a different way: Grilled pork cut
Lunch on the shore of the lake - a recipe for chives with chicken
HEALTH
One of the growing "A Crystal Sons": "His bones break even when they touch"
11 1623
After a strange sensation in the legs - the verdict of doctors: the parasites stuck in the spine
265
Martyne detected cancer of the eye: mom can no longer see how the sons get tormented
24 4128
HAVE TOGETHER
Daujenai bread is valued all over Europe
Food quality is a priority for farmers
MUSIC
Galapagos returns "Other talks" with special guests - Brothers Lavrinovičiai
Jessie Ware: High standards of security, nutrition and important information for the concert
WORLD KITCHEN
Lithuanian U.S. in the United States: three teddy bears a refrigerator at home
2 1192
Spit on the Spanish resort of indecent tourists: will share a thousand fine
1 170
One of the most beautiful natural places in Europe, where you will even need sunglasses at night
1 635
FAMILY
She lives in three homesteads in a village with a pension of 157 euros and does not complain
10 889
Tips for having kids: How not to become "Superfood"
What are the signs that a child could have been sexually abused?
CHINA
The most expensive film in China suffered an epic scale failure
Top 10 series released in 2017
6
"Leitis" - a historical episode that we did not deserve
16
LIFE
One of the growing "A Crystal Sons": "His bones break even when they touch"
11 1623
She lives in three homesteads in a village with a pension of 157 euros and does not complain
10 889
After a strange sensation in the legs - the verdict of doctors: the parasites stuck in the spine
265
FESTIVAL "GALAPAGAI"
Galapagos returns "Other talks" with special guests - Brothers Lavrinovičiai
Vidas Bareikis presents a song for the girls "Galapagai" - "You Are Beautiful"
1
EVENT GUIDE
New space for space "COZY by Siemens arena" has been targeted at Spotify once
The punishment of a wicked sophomore: most hurt is not due to a pecuniary punishment
9
Write a review about 15min
Write to the Advertising Agency Career with 15min Contact Us Shareholders Authors Terms of Use Rules for Commenting 15min Without Advertising
All rights reserved. © 2008 JSC "15min". Copy, reproduce and distribute only with written consent of UAB "15min".
On this site we use cookies. They help identify affiliated users, measure audience size and browsing habits; so we can change the site to make it more comfortable for you. More about this: Privacy Policy. I agree Cookie settings