1
2017-05-02 16:36:00
Mindaugas Samkus, BNS
Text Size:
Print
Jonava Fertilizer Producer Achema, managed by Achema Group, one of the largest concern in Lithuania, will pay 17 million euros of dividends this year.
The company announced on its website that on April 14 the shareholders decided to pay EUR 25.9 per share. Last year Achema paid out 30 million euros for dividends.
In the 2016 activity report submitted to the Center of Registers, Achema points out last year's net profit of 5.269 million euros - 12.4 times less than in 2015 (65.221 million euros), its revenue amounted to 359.253 million euros - 36.1 per cent. less (562,583 million euros). Achema plans to reach 411 million euros this year, and will invest 12 million euros.
100 percent Fertilizer producer shares are managed by the Achema Group. The main shareholder of the concern, Lyda Lubienė, with her daughter, Victoria, manages more than 52 percent. shares. 11.6 percent owned by Jurati Zadeikiene, 7% - Jonai Sirvydys and Marija Kaminskienė, 4.75 per cent. - Arunas Laurinaitis, 0.5% - Adam Jadeika.


Ads
Notify me of updates to
news
Portal
guest
Ask
a specialist
Discussions
weather
TV
the program
Dating
Games
Horoscopes
Novelty
RSS feed
Facebook
Twitter
Maxima and Gelsva rushed to help the Maribor: it will share water for free
In response to the current situation in Marijampolė, the company "Gelsva" and "Maxima", the company engaged in the production of "Green Grape", have taken the initiative to tackle the problem of safe drinking water shortage. & Sc ...
And A. Tapin did not see the name of this product: he is - the champion of the year (supplemented)
In the virtual space a picture of a product with a strange name is spreading. Interns, after reading the name, laughed at them. ...
10
Twenty Years Investment: Continental launches plant construction in Kaunas District
Continental continues to expand its operations in Europe - today the construction of the company's first factory in Lithuania was officially announced in Kaunas. The beginning of construction was consolidated by Her Excellency President of the Republic of Lithuania Dal ...
26
Maxima Group strengthens its position in the Polish market: it combines trade networks
Maxima Group launches the merger of managed retail chains in Poland. In the trading network "Stokrotka", which the company manages from this spring, will be integrated the Aldik tin ...
Court: Lietuvos rytas must deny defamation against V. Valvonis
The daily "Lietuvos rytas" and "Lietuvos rytas" television must deny false information that Vytautas Valvonis, the director of the Supervisory Authority of the Bank of Lithuania, allegedly carried out corrupt activities. ...
1
The head of "Sūduvos vandenai" has resigned from lava and chlorine-polluted water
Algis Kadišius, director of the company "Sūduvos vandenys", is taking over from the second incident due to contaminated drinking water in Marijampolė. ...
4
Lietuvos paštas poses salaries to employees
From August 1 this year Lithuanian Post increases wages for the least-paid employees of the company. In total, the salary will be increased to 4362 employees of the company. Wage increase for the company at an additional cost ...
"Housing estate" is mocking customers
Rainwater is running into the power line, but the representatives of the house managing company Būsto valda do not see any problems. This is confirmed by Taikos pr. 40 apartment building residents who have not received any help for a week. ...
32
Sennebogen introduced technical innovations
At the IFAT exhibition in Munich, which presented the technology to facilitate the sorting of secondary raw materials, the German company Sennebogen also demonstrated the next generation of trucks. The latter are distinguished by ecological, security, ...
2
Ethics guards: Formerly one of the leaders of the "Lietuvos geležinkeliai" did not stir the interest
Former Deputy General Manager of Lietuvos Gelezinkelius Gerimantas Bakanas did not break the public and private interests - he did not violate the requirement of the law to "cool" from the former service and i & sc ...
More articles