0
https://www.lzinios.lt/lzinios/Ekonomika/gyventojams-rupi-es-lesu-panaudojimas/269208
Projects that improve the infrastructure are noticeable and relevant to the population. / Photo by Romu Jurgaitis
A-A +
Tauragė and Širvintų districts and Elektrėnai municipalities are closest to the investments of the European Union (EU) - as the survey showed, their inhabitants mostly use the results of these investments and feel the most positive impact on their quality of life. Only in the largest cities of the country the city of Kaunas came into the top ten of the most open municipalities. This explains the EU-targeted regional support and increased visibility of the projects implemented.
The index of openness of municipalities to the EU investment portfolio was compiled for Spinter tyrimai by interviewing more than 4.5 thousand respondents from all 60 municipalities of the country.
Most of Lithuania's residents see the benefits of EU investment in renovating cities and towns, reconstructing roads, renovating multi-apartment buildings, and the positive impact of investments in cultural, environmental and health sectors.
"The index was considered solely in the opinion of people living in a particular region, regardless of the amount of funds invested in that region. The results of this study revealed that the impact of EU investments does not depend on their volume. This is understandable, as in smaller regions of the country, where the overall level of public and private investment is lower, EU-funded projects are becoming more visible, "said Loreta Maskaliovienė, Deputy Finance Minister.
According to the research data, most of Lithuania's residents see the benefits of EU investment in renovating cities and towns, reconstructing roads, renovating multi-apartment buildings, and the positive impact of investments is also visible in the fields of culture, environment and health.
According to the openness of municipalities, the Tauragė District Municipality is the leader in the EU investment index. According to the survey data, 55% Tauragiskis is relatively well informed about EU investment projects, 66%. use the results of these projects, 72%. sees the benefits of these investments for quality of life.
In the second place of the index - Elektrėnai municipality. 36 percent Polluted electricians named themselves participating in public meetings to discuss EU investment projects, half of respondents said they were using EU investment results, 61%. see their benefits for quality of life.
In the third place in the district of Sirvintos, the positive impact of investments on the quality of life was 63%. survey participants and 58% use the project results. of respondents. True, the people of Sierventes are less informed about EU investment projects in their region - only 30% of the information is well known. Sirvinist
Jurbarkas, which is ranked fourth in the index, is most distinguished by the EU's investment impact assessment - even 70%. The surveyed Jurbarkas believe that these investments improve the lives of local people. I also think 63 percent. the study population of Kaunas.
Kaunas is the only metropolitan city to enter the EU's most open investment in the municipality's top ten.
Projects are regionally oriented
Ramūnas Dilba, Director of the European Union Investment Department of the Ministry of Finance, has identified the main reason why residents of smaller towns are more satisfied with EU investment projects. According to him, in smaller regions of the country, due to renewed projects from EU funds, projects of higher concentration are more visible and people are more likely to use EU investment results. "It may sometimes seem that almost all of the towns have been renovated from EU funds, although only a few objects have been updated there," said R. Dilba.
Eglė Stebulienė, Project Manager of Public Enterprise Versli Lietuva, reminded that in the financial period of this financial year 2014-2020, EU money is focused on promoting regional vitality. "The target group of most of the tools and invitations that you take for you, as well as the right applicants, are the small and medium-sized businesses operating in the regions, living communities, organizations, municipalities, etc. t In addition, these measures are often aimed at installing, upgrading and modernizing the infrastructure, so the inhabitants of the cities immediately notice the improvement of the infrastructure. And in metropolises, companies are more cautious about targeting tools such as Intelligence, R & D, and so forth, whose impact is not seen by the general public, but by its employees and partners, "she said.
In smaller regions of the country, due to renewed projects from EU funds, projects of a higher concentration are more visible and people are more likely to use EU investment results.
Encouraged the recruitment of specialists
Virginija Eičienė, Deputy Mayor of the Taurage District Municipality, according to the open index of EU investments, pointed out that the infrastructure of drinking water and surface wastewater was renovated with the funds of EU projects, renovated brownfields, buildings in which urban and rural communities and young people could carry out their activities. In order to attract as many young people as possible to engage in creative activities, the Student Creation Center, the museum is being renovated.Alina Ozić photo
According to the speaker, the main investments are in public buildings: kindergartens, schools, cultural houses, health care institutions, etc. Managed urban infrastructure that meets the needs of people with disabilities.
Although EU funds, as the deputy mayor has acknowledged, did not directly create jobs, the created infrastructure provides opportunities for doing business and attracting investment. A more focused on improving the quality of public services, the general renewal of public infrastructure, and the creation of tourist sites. However, as noted by V. Eičienė, the implementation of projects and work is carried out by specialists from different fields: designers, technical supervisors, contractors, designers, etc.
For decades, wait for updates
The municipality of Širvintai has indicated that its administration is currently implementing 19 investment projects financed by the European Union Structural Funds. The total value of the projects is about 15 million euros.
In the commentary sent, the municipality said that public spaces, streets and most of public buildings in Širvintos were not processed for decades. "Sidewalks - sloping paddles, bicycle paths and pedestrian walkways - pothle, do not light up. The squares, the parks, are full of shabby shrubs, trees and grass, and do not look after them. Sirvintos settled in a dark, dark, forgotten provincial town. Creating a modern, orderly, functional, comfortable and attractive place to live and work, a friendly environment for the city, it was necessary to integrate it in a complex manner. A coherent and rational plan was selected for the preparation and implementation of projects financed by the EU structural funds, other funds, state and municipal budgets, "the municipal report states.
According to the municipality, a lot of positive changes have brought reconstruction of one of the main streets of Širvintų city - Kalnalaukio street - section. There were no sidewalks on the street, cars could not slip in places, there was no safe traffic infrastructure. During the implementation of the project, there are equipped safety devices: high-rise crossroads, street lighting, 1,5 km pedestrian and bicycle trail, safety net, pedestrian crossings, safety fences, road marking. As a result, the quality of the living environment of the inhabitants improved, the conditions for safe traffic, shortened time spent on the road.
The municipality noted that after the arrangement of public infrastructure, the living environment of the inhabitants of Širvintai was considerably improved. People's attraction centers are created, where everyone can choose an attractive way to spend their free time, to have active or passive rest, to communicate. This way the inhabitants become acquainted with each other, the feeling of community, satisfaction with the living environment increases. Beside such attraction centers, where there are flows of people, conditions are created for the development and development of the services sector.
One of the plans to complete the planned completion of projects in 2019 - "Complex management of the territory near the Sirvintos pond". The project will be equipped with a square and a street stretch of Vilnius Street adjoining this square. The square will be equipped with pedestrian walkways, lighting, small architectural elements, updated greenery. An amphitheater will be installed on the slope, on the terrace there is a terrace. A pedestrian and bicycle trail will be repaired on the south-west bank. There will also be a pedestrian bridge over the Širvintos river pond.
According to the prepared landscape management project, the territory in front of the Širvintos St. Archangel Michael Church and along Plento Street. In front of the church, a rotunda will be built, greenery work is carried out, as well as pedestrian paths, small landscape architectural works, and along the Plento street - greenery work.
During the implementation of the project "Installation of the central square of Sirvintos" the existing coatings and green areas will be restored, pedestrian walkways, lighting, small architectural elements, a fountain, and the area will be adapted for people with disabilities. The square will be suitable for public events, representation, active and passive recreation of the inhabitants.
A lot of attention, as stated by the municipality, is also given to solving social problems. One of the projects of this kind is "Development of Social Housing Fund in Sirvintos Town", after which the built 18 apartment building was completed, the interior decoration was completed, the social housing environment was adjusted.
The aim is also to improve the quality of education services. Laurynas Stuoka-Gucevičius Gymnasium Stadium is set up, several educational institutions will be renovated.The report also states that schools, community centers, shops, post offices, libraries, day care centers, and non-governmental organizations operate in villages of the Širvintai District Municipality; however, in many settlements the environment is not well-equipped, there is a lack of public spaces for people to have free time, exercise, socialize, organize common events. Street lighting is not installed in many villages, therefore, it does not ensure the safety of residents during dark times, a high risk of accidents. The Širvintai District Municipality Administration will implement 6 projects, which will invest in the development of infrastructure of settlements.
Projects aimed at improving the quality of life and ecological and environmental problems will be implemented. For example, the construction of new water improvement facilities in Musninkai and Gelvonai will be carried out, the construction of water supply and sewage collection networks and waste water treatment plants in Musninkai will be carried out. New drinking water networks and sewage networks will be built, sewage treatment plants will be built.
The interest of the population is growing
It is noticeable that the public interest in projects implemented with European Union support funds is constantly growing. Such a trend was revealed by a study by Spinter Research, commissioned by the Ministry of Finance.
According to him, for the time being, only one in eight inhabitants of the country has participated in public discussions of EU projects, although he would like to get involved in such discussions.
According to Ieva Aidietė, the representative of the Ministry of Finance who initiated the good practices in municipalities, local communities are becoming more and more active participants in public life - residents are concerned about how their living environment changes, how EU investments can drive business, create more jobs. Therefore, it is natural that interest in projects has grown significantly.
"Research shows that as much as 55% of the population would like to take part in the consideration of EU investment directions in their city or region. It is a large number that encourages project promoters to listen to the needs of the population and take measures to involve communities in project activities, "said I. Aidietė.
Most of the Lithuanian population sees the benefits of EU investment in renovating cities and towns, reconstructing roads and renovating multi-apartment buildings. Photo of LŽ
According to her, one of the simplest means by which people can be informed about ongoing projects, to bring them together for joint activities is public discussion. However, as practice shows, EU applicants are lacking in knowledge and experience in organizing such discussions.
According to I. Aidietė, local communities should cooperate from the very first stages of the implementation of projects - this is the fastest way to succeed in projects. In addition, it is worth thinking about the inclusive forms of public discussion. In other words, public debate should be more than a desk review. They could take another suitably chosen form, such as tours, open days, or ideas workshops.
The top ten municipalities in the EU invest in
1 Taurage District Municipality
2 Elektrenai municipality
3 Širvintos district municipality
4 Jurbarkas District Municipality
5 Kaunas City Municipality
6 Ignalina District Municipality
7 Alytus district municipality
8 Alytus City Municipality
9 Siauliai District Municipality
10 Šilalė District Municipality
Source: Ministry of Finance
NAME EL. PAPER (optional)
COMMENTARY
COMMENT