0
https://www.15min.lt/naujiena/aktualu/lietuva/prezidento-rinkimu-reitingu-trejetukas-be-s-skvernelio-56-1002622
According to a poll conducted by the public opinion and market research company Spinter tyrimai in June, S. Skvernelė was ranked as a member of the Homeland Union - Lithuanian Christian Democrats (TS-LKD), a former diplomat Vygaudas Ušackas, whose overall rating remained unchanged: for him if the elections were held next weekend, in June it would have voted 6.7 percent. of respondents.
Confidence in S.Skvernelius has fallen from May 9.7 to June 6.3.
As before, the economist Gitanas Nausėda remains in the first place of the leader, as well as in the past, Visvaldas Matijošaitis, Mayor of Kaunas. In June, 20.6 percent voted for G. Nausėda. of respondents (in May - by 21.6 percent), for V. Matijosita in June, they would have voted 10 percent, in May - 11.6 percent. of respondents.
There was also an increase in the number of undeclared people: they did not know what to vote for, in June it was 23.5%; in May, the proportion of such voters was 18.3%.
According to the survey, 6 percent would support the representative of TS-LKD Ingrid Šimonyte, 4 percent to party colleague Žygimantas Pavilionis, 3.4 percent to MP Antanas Guogas. of respondents.
The public opinion poll of the market research company Spinter tyrimai was held on June 19-27 by the order of the news portal delfi.lt, and 1003 respondents from 18 to 75 years were interviewed.
The error of the research results is 3.1%.