1
https://www.vz.lt/finansai-apskaita/2018/05/25/maxima-grupepernai-ismokejo-100-mln-eur-dividendu
Retail Manager Maxima Group, an indirectly managed entrepreneur Nerijaus Numovic, last year for 2016. paid out 100 million euros of dividends - one tenth less than in 2016, when EUR 110 million was paid out in 2015.
Maximos Grupės 2017 m. Submitted to the Center of Registers. The report states that at the end of last year, the company had accumulated 284.054 million euros of retained earnings. Information about this year's planned dividend payment is not provided.
Maxima Group's net profit last year compared to 2016 decreased by 2.5 times to 99.422 million EUR. The consolidated net profit of the entire group over the year has more than doubled to 74.868 million EUR.
In a report submitted to the Center of Registers of "Vilniaus prekyba", which manages Maxima Group, it indicates last year total dividends received in the amount of 158.99 million Eur. Last year, the company allocated 1.2 million euros to dividends (912 thousand euros in 2016). Vilniaus prekyba had, by the end of 2017, accumulated 349.815 million euros of retained earnings.
The net profit of Vilniaus prekyba last year compared to 2016 increased by 21.8%, to 158.159 million EUR, the consolidated net profit of the whole group of companies - 82.9%, to 173.189 million EUR.
The Vilnius Trading Group, through the subsidiaries Maxima Group, Euroapotheca, Hermitage and Akropolis Group, manage shopping centers, pharmacy networks and real estate development and rental companies in the Baltic States, Poland, Bulgaria, Ukraine and Sweden. .
The BNS news agencies are not allowed to reproduce information on mass media or on websites without the written consent of UAB "BNS".
write a comment