1
http://www.diena.lt/naujienos/verslas/ekonomika/energetikos-imoniu-holdingas-ketina-ismoketi-348-mln-euru-dividendu-707988?full
2015-08-31 16:19:00
BNS info
Text Size:
Print
Lesto, the largest electricity distributing company in Lithuania, and Lietuvos Dujos, an operator of gas distribution networks, intends to pay an interim dividend of 34,758 million euros, which is controlled by the energy company Lietuvos energija.
Lesto intends to pay EUR 21.742 million for the first half of the year, or EUR 0.036 per share, Lietuvos energija gamyba - EUR 2.667 million, or EUR 0,042 per share, and Lietuvos dujos - EUR 10,348 million, or EUR 0, EUR 0356 per share, dividends. Shareholders of all companies will pay dividends on September 24th, according to Nasdaq Vilnius Stock Exchange.
According to BNS estimates, the total amount of dividends received by the Ministry of Finance for Lietuvos Energija will be 33,083 million euros.
In the first half of this year, Lesto earned a net profit of EUR 43.039 million - 2.9 times more than in January-June last year, while the net profit of Lietuvos energija was 14%. to 19,256 million euros, the profit earned by "Lietuvos dujos" from gas distribution activities this year increased by 28 percent. to EUR 7,678 million.
Lesto paid a total of 31.319 million euros in dividends for the past year, of which the interim dividends for the first half of 2014 amounted to EUR 19.24 million. "Lietuvos energija gamyba" has paid out for the last year a total of 41.953 million euros of dividends, of which 20.233 million euros were interim dividends for the first half of 2014. During the year, Lietuvos dujos paid out dividends of EUR 48.2 million, of which EUR 14.807 million accounted for interim dividends for the first half year.
Lietuvos Energija manages 96.13% "Lietuvos energija gamyba", 96.6 percent. "Lietuvos dujos" and 94.39 percent Lesto shares.
The shares of Lesto, Lietuvos dujos and Lietuvos energija production are quoted on the Main List.


Ads
Notify me of updates to
news
Portal
guest
Ask
a specialist
Discussions
weather
TV
the program
Dating
Games
Horoscopes
Novelty
RSS feed
Facebook
Twitter
Traffic safety on Lithuanian roads - EUR 11 million in EU support
In order to improve road safety on Lithuanian roads, over 13 million dangerous intersections will be reconstructed over two years, about 12 km of bicycle paths will be built, speed meters will be installed or upgraded. ...
Polish frozen vegetables with Listeria were delivered to Lithuania for two years
Frozen vegetables infected by the Polish Greenyard Frozen Poland Listeria were removed from the Lithuanian market - vegetable mixtures with dangerous infections were supplied for at least two years. ...
4
Trade in pets is subject to compliance
The State Food and Veterinary Service (SFVS), after receiving information from its colleagues from the Estonian competent authority on breaches of trafficking in dogs, has inspected people involved in this activity in our country. ...
Lithuanians liked non-alcoholic beers: beating sales records
Today, the International Brewers' Day is celebrated, which reminds not only the old traditions of brewing, but also the innovations of beer industry. The non-alcoholic beer, which has not been sold for so long ago, is already completing its disposal & s ...
1
54 thousand people will soon receive letters from the Tax Authorities
The State Tax Inspectorate (STI) informs that residents who declare income for 2017, but have not yet paid the personal income tax (GPM) until today, will receive reminder letters this week calling for ...
Sodra payments after tax reform: frequently asked questions
"Will my salary and Sodra payments not reduce if the taxes paid by the employer and the employee are combined? What impact will the tax changes have on me personally? "- such and similar questions come from & bd ...
What demand for specialists will increase three times over a couple of years?
Just a couple of years - in 2020 - Lithuania will require at least 300 information systems, road and rail transport engineers. Such labor market demand will emerge after the launch of the European railway track "Rai ...
In which areas do young families have the right to purchase housing and receive a subsidy?
Starting from September 1, young families will be eligible for a state subsidy for the first housing in the region, but first of all the family will have to find the house they want to buy or the land where they want to build a house. ...
Pension funds have already accumulated more than 3 billion euros
The assets of II pillar pension funds operating in Lithuania exceeded the 3 billion EUR limit and at the end of June amounted to 3 082 million EUR. The results of most pension funds in the second quarter of this year were better than the first, but the long-term 10 years. the return is te ...
1
The Government established a Commission for the Reduction of Shadow Economy
The government decided on Wednesday to set up a Commission for the Reduction of Shadow Economy. It will replace the current commission dedicated solely to coordinating the control and legislation of the shadow economy. ...
More articles