0
https://www.vz.lt/nekilnojamasis-turtas-statyba/2018/07/18/workland-planuoja-tolesne-pletra-vilniuje-investuos-15-mln-eur
Published: 2018-07-18 09:35
PHOTO GALLERY Building at the intersection of Lieliai and Savičius streets (4 photos)
Photo by Rūta Vizbariene (VŽ)
Photo by Vladimir Ivanov (VZ)
The Estonian office rental company Workland Group will open its second center in Vilnius this autumn, and in the next two years, plans for 2-3 more such spaces in the capital.
In total, the company plans to invest 4.5 million euros in the Baltic States next year, of which a third should be made in Lithuania, according to a report distributed on Wednesday.
On Tuesday, VZ announced that Workland's office space would open on Broad Street, the building where Nordea Bank was previously located.
"Our second business center will be located in a historic building where previously the cinema and the bank were active. 1,259 sq. Km It is planned to install up to 150 jobs in the m-area business center. The space for teamwork will be located in a unique room with high ceilings, which reaches over 7 meters and windows with a height of almost 6 meters. The agreement with the first tenants is scheduled to be signed at the end of July, "says Laura Panovienė, head of Workland's centers in Lithuania.
Workland is planning to open the autumn in Great Street.
At present, the company has 2,000 sq. M. m area collaborative space on Gediminas Avenue, where the price per work place varies from 220 to 300 Eur / month.
Workland, a network of well-equipped offices (serviced offices), currently has three centers in the Baltic capitals. This summer is preparing to open a second office space in Tallinn.
"New business centers will target an even wider audience - with no private workplaces and meeting space, there will be coworking and joint workplaces and places for coworking," says Indrek Haal, Chairman of the Board of Workland Group. .
According to him, the company's goal is until 2020. have 10 business centers.
On the Great Street, managed by Nordia, besides Workland, the Queensberry restaurant and the store are still open. The "Two Brothers" shop, which was previously located, also operates here.
Follow the NT Market News and Trends on the Facebook page of "VZ Real Estate"
write a comment