1
http://www.diena.lt/naujienos/verslas/imoniu-pulsas/achema-ismokes-30-mln-euru-dividendu-744426
2016-04-15 17:53:00
BNS info
Text Size:
Print
Jonava Fertilizer Producer Achema, managed by Achema Group, one of Lithuania's largest concern, last year earning 73.4 million euros of pre-tax profit, allocated EUR 30 million to dividends.
Shareholders decided on Friday. In 2015, the company received 562.6 million euros of audited income - 6%. more than in 2014, when it was 530.5 million euros, the company said.
"The better than the results of last year was determined by the shorter repair time than in 2014, which made it possible to produce and sell more products, especially liquid fertilizers. The second important factor, which has allowed to increase export volumes, due to the fall in prices of crude oil and other raw materials, the competitive difference between us and other fertilizer producers, "Ramūnas Miliauskas, General Manager of Achema, said in a press release.
Achema last year produced 2.6 million tons of production - 13%. more than in 2014 (2.3 million tons), the company's pre-tax profit increased by 55.2 percent over the year. to EUR 73.4 million (EUR 47.3 million). The net profit company does not publish.
Last year, Achema announced a net loss of 25 million euros in 2014, with Russia's Gazprom not reaching an agreement on gas prices. This year, the fertilizer manufacturer began purchasing Norwegian Statoil gas, which will be transported through the Klaipeda LNG terminal to October this year, and in the fourth quarter it will again use Gazprom's gas purchased at the auction held at the battle.


Ads
Notify me of updates to
news
Portal
guest
Ask
a specialist
Discussions
weather
TV
the program
Dating
Games
Horoscopes
Novelty
RSS feed
Facebook
Twitter
The non-alcoholic "alcohol" fashion is spreading in Lithuania
Already more and more Lithuanians drink alcohol in their favorite drinks - they are not necessarily needed. In order to choose from an ever-expanding range of non-alcoholic beverages, residents of the country are increasingly choosing exactly the non-alcoholic beer, cider ...
1
Western Union will provide an annual study funding for a postgraduate student
More and more businesses are seeking cooperation with higher education institutions - engaging in the process of study organization, providing themes for final projects, admitting students to practice, setting up scholarships or assigning study f ...
Lithuanian dairy products conquer the Canary Islands market
In July, the delegation of the largest milk producer in Spain, Jose Sanchez Penate SA, visited Lithuania. Spain has visited dairy farms, Marijampole Dairy Tin factories and production workshops, which ...
Top Sport Cheat Clients?
The soccer world championship has also attracted paymen attention. But those who have made the final goal to put their head in the final will not do anything. The betting organizers explain, though the goal is scored by the head, but it skr ...
8
Norfa in Klaipėda smiles customers?
Expirational products in Norfos stores are becoming more and more noticeable - in a very short time, several cases have been recorded in which customers of Klaipėda purchased obsolete food. This is also verified by the ...
19th
Maxima establishes practical training centers for food production
The largest employer in the country - the retail chain Maxima establishes practical training centers for food production in nine cities of Lithuania, where experienced and professional Maximos employees will train the required qualifications ...
Vegetarian lovers will be happy - this summer, harvest prices are lower
The warm season is a real refreshment for fresh vegetables. In summer, buyers are attracted not only by their wide range of products, but also by attractive prices. Although the price of vegetable prices in July last year is far too much for buyers ...
3
The Center of Registers is a new corruption prevention office
The Center for Prevention and Internal Investigation of the Registry Center is being directed by Giedrius Cininas, who until then was the Chief Inspector of the Ministry of the Interior. ...
3
Early hot summer changed Lithuanian shopping habits
This summer, a very early summer, changed the Lithuanian shopping habits. As Maxim's sales figures show, in the middle of the summer, Lithuanians more than last year bought ice cream, fresh vegetables and fruits ...
Lithuania, for the first time in history, has sold grain directly to Saudi Arabia
Saudi Arabian State Grain Organization has bought 115 thousand wheat from the Lithuanian grain trading and export company Agrorodeo during an international competition on Monday. Lithuanian capital company Agrorodeo & ldqu ...
More articles