0
http://www.diena.lt/naujienos/lietuva/salies-pulsas/vokietijos-poligonuose-testuojami-lietuvai-pagaminti-sarvuociai-boxer-872974
2018-07-18 10:15:00
BNS info
Text Size:
Print
In Germany, the Boxer infantry fighting machines manufactured by the Lithuanian Army are being tested, which will be called "Wolves", keeping in touch with the history of the country and military traditions.
As reported by the Ministry of National Defense (KAM), the manufacturer of infantry fighting machines (WCM) "Vilkas", ARTEC in German landfills, intensively tests two prototypes of Lithuanian PKM.
Both prototypes were made in accordance with the requirements of the Lithuanian Armed Forces, which equipped the Israeli production towers, equipped with fast-paced 30mm cannons and anti-tank missiles "Spike LR".
"The project of infantry fighting machines is one of the most important elements of modernization and strengthening of the Lithuanian Army," the Minister of National Defense Raimundas Karoblis quotes.
According to him, "Wolves" adapted to the needs of the Lithuanian Armed Forces signify a qualitative leap in the modernization of the army, supplying it with modern technology and weapons, which brings NATO standards closer.
According to KAM, the main task of prototype is to help the manufacturer identify the weak points of PKM "Wolf" in order to eliminate technical defects, ensure the quality of the product and the functionality of all systems before the massive production of combat machines starts.
"We call these two PKM prototypes, because they are the first machines manufactured in accordance with the requirements of Lithuania with integrated weapon towers and for assessing the integrity and functionality of all systems at the current stage," said the project manager, Lithuanian Army Major Nerijus Šivickas, about the prototype of the PKM.
According to him, compared to last year's driver training machines, these prototype combat machines are much more complex, they have more and different equipment, which turns an armored conveyor into a capable combat vehicle.
At the end of the tests, the technical condition of both prototypes will be restored to the factory parameters of the PKM "Vilkas" and they will be returned to the Lithuanian Armed Forces. The first Wolf FCM should arrive in Lithuania at the beginning of 2019.
In July, Lithuania also sent a letter of intent for the NATO Support and Purchasing Agency (NSPA) to provide the Boxer Supply and Maintenance Program for infantry combat vehicles.
According to KAM, the aim is to ensure the logistic supply of the PKM purchased by the Lithuanian Armed Forces - the availability of general spare parts and central warehouses, repair facilities for the main units, technical and engineering support, etc.
According to the agreement signed in 2016, the Lithuanian Armed Forces will purchase 88 infantry combat vehicles equipped with high-speed cannons and anti-tank missiles for nearly 386 million euros.
These PKMs will be equipped with the Mechanized Infantry Brigade Iron Wolf, the Lithuanian Grand Duke Algirdas Mechanized, and the Great Duchess Birute Ulon Battalions.


Ads
Notify me of updates to
news
Portal
guest
Ask
a specialist
Discussions
weather
TV
the program
Dating
Games
Horoscopes
Novelty
RSS feed
Facebook
Twitter
Polish frozen vegetables with Listeria were delivered to Lithuania for two years
Frozen vegetables infected by the Polish Greenyard Frozen Poland Listeria were removed from the Lithuanian market - vegetable mixtures with dangerous infections were supplied for at least two years. ...
The Klaipėda ship was barely built, but it has already been destroyed
In the southern part of Klaipėda, after reconstruction of Naikupė street and pedestrians and cyclists trail, there was also a solar station charging service station. True, the Klaipeda people enjoyed this device for a short time - to the sto ...
A new shift in Lithuanian troops departed for NATO's operation in Afghanistan
The international military operation "Strong Support" in Afghanistan, on Wednesday, left a new shift of Lithuanian troops to the Lithuanian Army's "Spartan" aircraft. ...
The future school of the port city has doubled
The newly planned school dedicated to the centenary of the Lithuanian state will cost 12.5 million euros in Senvagės street - twice as much as originally planned. In the past few years, the price of not only building materials has risen, but ...
3
Ice sculpture has a question to the Seimas - "Are you clear"?
Earlier on the morning of Wednesday, near the statue of the Seimas, near the statue "Žinia", a sculpture of ice was erected, asking "Are you transparent like me?". ...
1
Weather: days will be tumultuous and nights
In the coming days, hot weather will stay in Lithuania, and some rain will give some refreshment. The tent will be even at night. ...
President: It is impossible to ridicule the historical truth about the genocide of our nation
President Dalia Grybauskaitė met with the mission "Mission Sibir'18" in the Presidency, who will leave tomorrow in Kazakhstan. ...
4
It is proposed to double scholarships for doctoral students
The Cabinet of Ministers will consider the proposal of the Ministry of Education and Science (MES) to almost double the scholarships for doctoral students on Wednesday. ...
2
July 18th in Lithuania and in the world
July 18th, Wednesday, Week 29. ...
A camp of young border guards, riflesmen and rescuers was opened at the Border Guard schoolOn Tuesday, the VSAT Border Guard School opened the summer camp for students, gathered by members of the Young Border Guards, young shooters of the Lithuanian Shooters Union, young police supporters, young people of the Firefighting Union ...
More articles