0
https://www.lrytas.lt/lietuvosdiena/aktualijos/2018/07/18/news/kuriamas-naujas-visuomeninis-judejimas-lietuvos-liberalai-atgaivina-liberalias-vertybes-6988861/
A new vibrant social movement "Lithuanian Liberals" is developing in Lithuania. I invite like-minded people to turn a whole new page of history and prove to the people of Lithuania that liberal values are worthy of trust. It is possible to achieve new breakthroughs, "said Paula Marcinkevičiūtė, a student at Mykolas Romeris University, who is one of the organizers and founders of this movement.
- What led to the creation of a new social movement "Lithuanian Liberals"?
- There is a lot of communication not only with students, but also with older people who are disappointed with the scandals that have been lately politics in Lithuania, tired of existing policies, decisions made by politicians, which sometimes are not understood by common sense.
This is also confirmed by the current scandals in the Lithuanian political arena - politicians and parties are involved in games, the goals of which, as we see in the State Security Gazette of the Republic of Lithuania and the conclusions of the National Security and Defense Committee of the Republic of Lithuania, do not really represent the people of Lithuania.
I believe and understand that there is a presumption of innocence in Lithuania, but the data presented in the State Security Gazette, in the conclusions of the NSGK, me, my beloved, and all the people of Lithuania are very much overwhelmed. With such politicians I'm off the road and, I think, not just for me. I hope and I hope that for many Lithuanian people this will deteriorate. Many say who is going to be here, nothing will succeed and change, so it's better to emigrate.
Emigration can be a solution - pull everything out and emigrate, but maybe we can not change anything and create a new movement that would be good for Lithuania and its citizens? Failure in this situation will certainly not help.
- There is no shortage of believers that new politicians will come, but nothing will change. What would you say to them?
- If we do so, then we will definitely not change anything and we will continue to vote for the existing politicians and all the populists who say one thing and do the rest.
- Why did you call "Lithuanian liberals"? After all, there is Liberal Movement already?
- This is the Liberal Movement. However, we are not going to compete with them. I have not been devastated by liberal values, but recent events have shown that they are really not off the road.
What can be the credibility of such politicians and political parties whose goals are completely different from the declared values? How can you cast your vote for politicians who are liberal values and how do they engage in common-minded games?
Our goal is to bring together young, young people who are not devastated by liberal values, ideas and policies. And those who, with liberal ideas, only cover and possibly try to represent some kind of concern, large capital, or business groups by participating in suspicious schemes, we want to say that our values are cardinally different. We want to send a message to the people of Lithuania that we are seeking to strengthen the spread of liberal ideas and values in Lithuania and create a completely new social movement with the prospect of becoming a political party, in isolation from the current Liberal Movement.
We will not be able to compromise the liberal ideas that, after such events, undermine people's confidence. This is very unfortunate. I would like to draw the attention of future voters to the fact that liberal values, ideas and policies have nothing to do with what is happening with the party representing liberalism. And we will not really have until the final decision of the institution of justice is in place. We are creating a new social movement and creating new and honest people whose liberal ideas, values and policies are not harmed.
- Many people will think that your movement is a derivative of the liberated members of the Movement. And what is it really?
- I can assure you that this is not really the option, as it was with the social democrats. We start everything from a fresh clean sheet, we are a completely new movement, and therefore, we are inviting everyone to join us and to participate actively in the movement, without leaving out liberal ideas, values and politics.
We strive to at least prove and try to influence the existing political processes, raise the liberal values in Lithuania, because the time has come for change. Only new people can create a new political movement and try to change something. Inactivity, passivity really will not solve the situation. Concerns are not enough. After all, we will live and live in Lithuania, so the time is coming for change.
- What kind of ideology will be spread by the public movement "Lithuanian Liberals"?
- Let's decide together with the movement's members what kind of ideology we will spread.
At the moment, we are concentrating on modern, progressive liberalism. The most important thing is to be well represented by liberal values and ideas.
- How do you promise to compete with the current Liberal Movement?- We are not really going to compete. Let the people of Lithuania decide what is acceptable to them, with whom they are going and what they want to vote for. There is a political crisis, or even a political theater, if it is possible to do so, just broke back and compromised liberal victories and values. I invite like-minded people to turn a completely new page and prove to the people of Lithuania that liberal values are worthy of trust. New paths can be found in this direction.
- Did you make a mistake in choosing the word "liberals" in the title of the movement? Recently, the liberals have gotten a negative shade in the public space, and it is unlikely that the situation will change soon.
- Masking and avoiding the word "liberals" does not really make sense, the masquerade of the names does not change anything in essence, it is important that there is a movement that actually represents liberal values.
We can use any name, but we do not hide anything so that there is no doubt that "Lithuanian liberals" represent only liberal values. Not the name of the essence, but the values. You do not need to avoid and be afraid of what you represent and what values you care for, it's necessary to tell people the truth, not to play games. We decided to create a completely new political movement and tell the people of Lithuania, the future electorate, that not liberals, or liberal ideas and values are guilty, but people who admire these ideas, declare one, but do the other.
We have no doubt that after the current political scandal, the name of liberals in Lithuania has been compromised. The time has come when people have to break their heads, thinking what is really presenting Lithuania in a transparent way to liberal ideas and values, and who just gets the names.
Liberal politics must really exist in Lithuania as a counterweight to other political forces. I think it's time to abandon the oligarchic and plutocratic methods of action, which incite, suppress and conquer Lithuania, which is reflected in the conclusions of the NSGK. They are likely to present only a small part of what is actually happening, as it may turn out to be even more serious.
We understand that without the help of financial, large capital aid, financial injecting into the political summit is impossible, it is possible and we will have the same fate, but it is better to try to do it independently and re-establish people of liberal views than to be someone else's project.
We do not have any person who has been a member of the Seimas for many years, minister or a prominent political figure. Our goal is to create a new, powerful political movement with completely new people with liberal attitudes and aspirations.
- Do you have enough finances to appear in the political arena? Can you compete with existing political movements and parties without funds?
- A very good question and very important. First of all, we aim for ourselves as transparency and decency from the very beginning. As practice shows, the receipt of any financial support becomes a burden later on, and the timing of repayment of debts will come to notice, so we do not really want to devote ourselves to obligations and other filthy schemes. As a result, from the very beginning we declare that we want the movement "Lithuanian liberals" to live independently and without any financial sponsorship and commitment to anyone. It is our fundamental and fundamental goal that the political movement be born naturally, independently, transparently and without any commitment.
We will not try after companies, companies and we will not ask for any financial injections, sponsorship, or some kind of things in exchange. Of course, it will be harder for us to reach our audience with constituents, but we will know from the very beginning that we started to develop without any financial injections and we were not someone else's project. We are well aware that any support will be needed sooner or later. Therefore, we chose a very difficult path. We will try to prove that it is possible to create a transparent political movement in Lithuania. Nobody believes that without financial support, we will succeed, but we believe that the most important asset is not money, but people, the team of all gathering and trust.
Therefore, once again I invite all the members of the "Lithuanian Liberals" movement. People come to parties or political movements, but they are not heard or seen by anyone, mostly they are there because of the number. There will be nothing like us: no protection, mediation, acquaintances. Everyone is equal from the beginning. It is important to join the minds of those who are not afraid of liberal ideas. I hope we will be able to revive liberal values in Lithuania.
We do not even create our new logo, and we want to bring together the people of Lithuania's liberal communities to do this together so that everyone will contribute to this work with their ideas and arguments so that we all feel responsible for the work done. Similarly, mobile apps and other things will be created and will be joined by all the members of our community.
- How do you imagine such activities and communication?- We will try to make a completely new innovative, progressive movement and, as far as possible, include the Lithuanian citizens who are currently emigrating and to whom the fate and liberal values of Lithuania are not undone. We will strive to introduce the latest technology, so that each member of the movement can give his opinion, ideas for hearing each member. Every member's opinion and ideas are very important. We create everything from scratch. It will not be a movement, as it has become fashionable lately, when dissatisfied, or non-party leaders create new parties or movements, change names, migrate and tempt people to join. However, in most cases, these are only slightly changed colors and titles, and the aim is to collect the number of people who need to set up a political party. Later those members are forgotten.
We will use an entirely new communication platform and we will try to communicate with each other. It will be done using information technology. When emigrated Lithuanian citizens really do not go to meetings, we have innovative solutions for this. Behind the window of the 21st century, so many things can be solved with the help of the right information technology solutions.
- As practice shows that a political movement is needed, a leader or a known public figure is needed. Will you also have a well-known personality ahead?
- We have a really very intelligent and well-known person in society. There are ongoing discussions with him. He does not object to the invitation to join, but I want to say that we do not want to rely on the politics of wolves or those who are "n" years old in politics. On the one hand, we create ourselves the task of reaching the people of Lithuania not with known names, famous names, or to entice the voters with sweets.
Such examples were not one, but all ended in political scandals or pre-trial investigations. As you can see, we even use the name "Lithuanian liberals" from the very beginning and do not plan to hide it.
It would be funny to call it a different name, I mean without the word "liberals", and use liberal values and ideas to tell voters that we are not liberals. We want to be proud to represent the citizens of Lithuania and to improve as much as possible the current situation in Lithuania. I do not want to talk about the economic situation, the political scandalous Lithuania, the decisions that are made, and I do not intend to criticize. But let's ask ourselves, is everything really so good in Lithuania? Why emigration grows every year?
We are not really going to introduce some kind of political accounts. It is important for us, future Lithuanian liberals, to restore patriotically minded people and young people.
I agree, perhaps, with something that satisfies the current political and economic situation in Lithuania. But it does not seem to me and my circle of minders. We think that something needs to be done, changed, because by continuing to see the same faces in politics that have not changed for many years, they will receive new taxes or other solutions that they will want to emigrate even more. We live in Lithuania, and those who are at the political summit, apparently, are away from the problems and reality of people. The young generation should think more about what should be changed in Lithuania. Therefore, we also invite you to join the new Lithuanian liberal movement.
- What people are interested in your movement?
- We are talking with people from different professions, as well as sportsmen who are interested in our new movement. People are few and trust in politicians and are very cautious about proposals.
I hope and I hope that we will be interested in people who want to turn a new leaf with the Lithuanian liberals and prove it through their work.
If the interest in the movement "Lithuanian Liberals" will be, we are planning a "social evening", which we plan to do in a public place with all new members and live music.
Who else has not lost his civil solidarity, loyalty to Lithuania and who has not been devoured by liberal values, do not be indifferent to us at www.lietuvosliberalai.lt or send us an email by e-mail: info@lietuvosliberalai.lt.