15min.lt
Achema will pay € 17m dividends this year | Business
1 minute
The company announced on its website that on April 14 the shareholders decided to pay EUR 25.9 per share. Last year Achema paid out 30 million euros for dividends.
In the 2016 activity report submitted to the Center of Registers, Achema points out last year's net profit of 5.269 million euros - 12.4 times less than in 2015 (65.221 million euros), its revenue amounted to 359.253 million euros - 36.1 per cent. less (562,583 million euros). Achema plans to reach 411 million euros this year, and will invest 12 million euros.
100 percent Fertilizer producer shares are managed by the Achema Group. The main shareholder of the concern, Lyda Lubienė, with her daughter, Victoria, manages more than 52 percent. shares. 11.6 percent owned by Jurati Zadeikiene, 7% - Jonai Sirvydys and Marija Kaminskienė, 4.75 per cent. - Arunas Laurinaitis, 0.5% - Adam Jadeika.