A record number of passengers and flights in 2017. Upon arrival of Lithuanian airports this year, the largest amount of dividends will be allocated to the state budget through the history of the company's activities. It reaches 3.4 million euros - almost 1.7 million euros more than a year ago.
According to Tom Krakauskas, Chairman of the Board of Airports of Lithuania, the improvement of the company's performance each year creates added value for the whole country, and shows that the continuous improvement of the efficiency of the processes carried out results.
"For the activities of the three airports of the country in 2017, A dividend of EUR 3.4 million will be paid to the state budget. This amount is as high as 138%. 2017 net profit received. The amount of dividends exceeds the annual profit due to the company's retained earnings reserve from previous periods, "explains T. Krakauskas.
According to audited data, the net profit of Lithuanian airports in 2017. amounted to almost 2.5 million euros. For the state in 2017 Dividends paid by Lithuanian airports will be almost 98%. higher than in 2016, when it exceeded 1.7 million euros.
Marius Gelzinis, General Manager of Lithuanian Airports, is convinced that such a solid financial return would have been impossible without a particular joy in 2017. results.
"Last year we increased passenger traffic by one-tenth, and the number of flights increased by 5%. We expect to maintain consecutive growth this year, so we hope that the number of passengers who have used the services of Vilnius, Kaunas and Palanga airports will increase to 6 million. Such growth will be felt in the form of annual dividends and state treasury, "M. Gelzinis does not doubt.
It is forecasted that in 2018 The net profit of the three airports of the country's airports will reach about 6.2 million euros. In this case, the state pocket would have been replenished with almost 5 million euro dividends.
The Lithuanian Airports Network has three air gateways in Vilnius, Kaunas and Palanga. In 2017 They received 5.2 million passengers and completed 55,000 flights. In the summer season, 17 airlines from Lithuanian airports fly 79 regular flights to 67 cities in 29 countries. According to the International Airport Council (ACI Europe), Lithuanian airports contribute 2.5% to Lithuania's GDP.