0
https://www.lrytas.lt/verslas/rinkos-pulsas/2018/07/17/news/lietuva-ir-ukraina-planuoja-naujus-tiesioginius-skrydzius-traukiniu-marsrutus-6990802/
Lithuania and Ukraine plan to resume direct flights between Vilnius and Lviv, start train services on the Kiev-Minsk-Vilnius-Riga route and improve the conditions for freight transportation by all modes of transport.
These issues were discussed at the Intergovernmental Commission for Trade and Economic and Scientific and Technical Cooperation between Ukraine and Lithuania, which was held on 16-17 July in Lvov, the Ministry of Transport and Communications.
According to the report of the Ministry, Lithuania and Ukraine are planning to expand the geography of the flights between the two countries in cooperation in the field of aviation.
The target will be 2019. to resume direct flights between Vilnius and Lvov - because of this route, representatives of Ukraine are already talking with airline companies. Analysis and statistics show that such a route should be promising and attractive for passengers, contribute to business contacts and tourism development, the Ministry of Transport and Communications informed.
Ukraine also initiates passenger trains. September 28th this year The Ukrainian Railways train will start a new route connecting the four capitals - Kiev, Minsk, Vilnius and Riga. It is planned that this train will initially start once a week and a new timetable will be prepared in December.
In order to attract more cargo routes between the Black Sea and the Baltic Sea and Scandinavian countries, Lithuanian and Ukrainian rail companies will jointly develop economically sound tariff policies and marketing measures.
The joint effort will be aimed at increasing the flow of goods from Turkey and the Caucasus countries, to further promote the successful growth of container ship Viking, which is still growing.
To increase the efficiency of Viking it is planned to implement the concept of the electronic transport corridor throughout the whole route of this train, that is, to use the unified electronic document system in all the countries through this route to accelerate transport services and make them more attractive to customers.
Issues of international passenger and freight transport by road were discussed at the meeting of the Commission. Lithuanian representatives introduced the process of negotiations on the EU Mobility Package. It was agreed that issues of liberalization of bilateral and transit road haulage will be further discussed when the Ukrainian legislation is brought into line with the provisions of the Ukraine-EU Association Agreement.
The Lithuanian-Ukrainian Intergovernmental Commission approved the cooperation between the countries in transport infrastructure projects, emphasized the importance of improving the economic relations and business environment of the countries.
Meanwhile, the Minister of Economy Virginijus Sinkevičius, who chaired the meeting, emphasized that although the indicators of economic cooperation between Lithuania and Ukraine are growing, it is necessary to look for new opportunities and directions of partnership.
"Both Lithuania and Ukraine should think not only how to strengthen cooperation in the growing fields of tourism and exports, but also in future sectors - financial technologies, artificial intelligence, Internet of things and others. Both countries have a strong technology sector and their cooperation could be beneficial for both of them, "said V. Sinkevicius in a statement from the Ministry of Economy.
Lithuania is interested in increasing exports to the Ukrainian market, developing cooperation in the field of high value added goods production.
"The export potential in the Ukrainian market has not yet been exhausted, the country's business is slamming its exports to a large and viable Ukrainian market. To promote it, an export-credit guarantee program of Lithuanian origin was created and launched, which allows reducing market risks ", - said V. Sinkevicius.
The Ministry of Economy informs that after the meeting a protocol of cooperation will be signed, whereby the parties will agree and further strengthen bilateral cooperation in the fields of transport, energy, standardization, tourism, trade, agriculture, environment and other fields.
Next - the 19th - the IGC will be held in 2019 in Lithuania. The 17th Lithuanian-Ukrainian IGC meeting was held in Vilnius in June 2017.
According to the data of the Department of Statistics, in 2017 Of the more than 180 foreign trade partners of Lithuania, Ukraine ranked 19th in terms of trade turnover, 12 in terms of exports, and 22 in terms of imports. Trade turnover between Lithuania and Ukraine in 2017 compared to 2016 increased by 19.8%. and amounted to 1086.3 million euros. Exports of goods and services to Ukraine increased by 20.9%, respectively. and amounted to 800.7 million euros, while imports from Ukraine increased by 16.8%. and amounted to 285.6 million euros.
The scale of Ukraine's investment in Lithuania in 2017 compared to 2016 increased by 29.3%. and amounted to 22.58 million euros or 0.15%. of all foreign direct investment in Lithuania. Ukrainian businessmen mostly invested in real estate transactions and wholesale and retail trade, but Ukraine's investment in professional and scientific and technical activity has been increasing recently.