1
https://www.vz.lt/rinkos/2018/04/30/zemaitjos-pienas-ismokes-69-mln-eur-dividendu
One of the largest milk processing companies in Lithuania, Žemaitijos pienas, having earned a net profit of 4.182 million euro last year, will pay out 6.946 million Eur of dividends, or 15 cents per share.
The decision on dividend payment was made at the company's shareholders' meeting held on Monday at the "Nasdaq" Vilnius Stock Exchange, which was announced by Žemaitijos pienas. The Board of Directors offered to shareholders not to pay dividends for the previous year.
Žemaitijos pienas for 2016 twice paid 10,187 million Eur dividends.
The shareholders of the company, having assessed the unallocated profit and transfers from reserves in the previous year, distributed a total of 53.598 million EUR. Of these, EUR 5 million was earmarked for the purchase of own shares and the remaining EUR 41,652 million transferred to the next financial year.
By the shareholders' decision, the company will be able to acquire up to 10% in 18 months. your stock. The minimum bid for the shares would be 1.75 Eur, the maximum price would be 2.20 Eur.
It is said that the company intends to provide shareholders with the opportunity to sell shares, increase, maintain or stabilize stock liquidity and their market price, have the opportunity to allocate their own shares to employees, and also use their shares in potential exchanges, acquire or sell shares of other companies.
The shareholders of Žemaitijos pienas approved the decision of the Board to borrow from the banks 10 million Eur. 5 million EUR is intended to be allocated from 2016 an investment project of 18 million euros, for the development of cheese and butter production units, raw material and product logistics and storage facilities. The remaining EUR 5 million will be used to finance working capital.
For the members of the collegial body of the Company for the period from the decision of the shareholders' meeting until 2019 Approved budget of 120,000 Eur approved by the Ordinary General Meeting of Shareholders.
At the beginning of March, 28.97% of the votes of Zemaitijos milk were managed by Algirdas Pažemeckas and Danutė Pažemeckienė, 6.51% - by Romusas Jarulaitis and Regina Jarulaitienė, 6% by Klaipedos Pienas. The Investors' Association and its joint shareholders control about 11% of Žemaitijos pieno votes.
The shares of Žemaitijos pienas are quoted on the Supplementary List.
The BNS news agencies are not allowed to reproduce information on mass media or on websites without the written consent of UAB "BNS".
write a comment