2015-05-21 08:54:00
BNS info
Text Size:
Print
This year, Smiltyne Perekla, a record-breaking profit of 1 million euro last year, will pay the major shareholder in the state - the state - the largest dividends in the history of operations - nearly 0.5 million euros, writes Verslo žinios.
The remaining unallocated profit of EUR 0.57 million will be used to increase the authorized capital. This has already been approved by the General Meeting of Shareholders.
Upon registration of amendments to the articles of association, the company's authorized capital will increase to 5.75 million euros.


Ads
Notify me of updates to
news
Portal
guest
Ask
a specialist
Discussions
weather
TV
the program
Dating
Games
Horoscopes
Novelty
RSS feed
Facebook
Twitter
Infrastructure is being developed in the nursery quarter
Infrastructure development will begin shortly in the nursery quarter. Saulius Budinas, Director of Administration of Klaipeda City Municipality, on Friday, July 13, signed an agreement with "Telšių keliai", which will work ...
3
Workers in the city of Klaipėda have crashed the cramped Opel
When reconstructing the heating circuit at Taikos Avenue on the Vėtrungė station, workers had to bypass the already left-handed car here. Such misunderstandings often become headaches for construction contractors. ...
6
Closed crossroads - driver stroke
When reconstructing Tilžės street, it was necessary to close the traffic at the railway crossing. The inconvenience is a passion, because some drivers are still trying to achieve happiness, thus causing great congestion. ...
2
J. Basanavičiaus street in Palanga is intended only for pedestrians
The government of the largest resort in Palanga is determined to ban bicycle traffic from the next year in the most popular street of Jonas Basanavičius and turn it into a pedestrian zone, writes Lietuvos žinios. ...
4
Russian citizens are the hostages of the ship in Klaipėda port
The ship's crew of Ivan Lopatin flying the flag of the Russian Federation lacked patience. After spending a few months on the ship without receiving a single penny, men turned to the authorities protecting the rights of seafarers, believe ...
2
Ten ships entered the history of Klaipėda port
On the 8th of July, a ship arrived at Klaipėda port, which was entered into the list of the most impressive ships in Klaipėda port. ...
1
The book of the Klaipeda collector - for researchers
Klaipėda collector Šarūnas Toliušis published a manual of periodicals published in the Lithuanian, Jewish and German languages of the Klaipėda region. The compiler of the catalog recognizes that the publication is not very wide, b ...
1
New covers will not be thieves
The watermen quickly took care of covering the wells from which the lids were stolen. Used structures that should no longer be of interest to the long-awaited ones. ...
Klaipėda District Municipality will take action on non-performing entrepreneurs
Still on April 27 Klaipėda District Municipality has signed a contract with winners of the tender and water amusement services in the territory of Gargždai quarries from UAB Lentų brolis, which had to be provided from July. ...
Train tickets become scarce
People who are trapped in trains are increasingly uncomfortable with the services provided by the state-controlled company Lietuvos geležinkeliai. And because of ticket shortages, and because of train delays. ...
7
More articles