0
https://www.15min.lt/sportas/naujiena/futbolas/prancuzu-talentas-paverge-pasauli-laimeta-premija-paaukojo-kilniam-tikslui-24-1002524
According to Sports Illustrated, K.Mbappe earned an average of 19.2 thousand euros per game and 299.2 thousand euros for winning the championship. As the young soccer player played in 7 matches, it is estimated that his championship earnings amounted to about 433.6 thousand euros. According to Business Insider, Mbappe decided to donate this money to the Premiers de Cordee Association, which is committed to ensuring that disabled children have the opportunity to play sports.
"He's a wonderful person. When K.Mbappe is not very busy, he is happy to contact us. K.Mbappe and his children have a beautiful friendship, he always finds them a word of encouragement. Sometimes it seems that the game with children gives him more pleasure than the children themselves, "said the chief executive of the association, Sebastien Ruffin.
K.Mbappe's talent drew the attention of the football legend Pele.
"This is the second teenager to score in the finals of the world football championship! Welcome to the club, K.Mbappe, it's wonderful to have such a company! "- wrote Pele in the social network Twitter.
"If Kyliaan continues to level up to my record, I might have to blow the dust off of a sports shoe," joked Mike.