According to the findings of the audit company Deloitt & Touche, Lietuvos Energija received 95.296 million litas of net profit last year. At the shareholders' meeting, it was decided that, in addition to the aforementioned dividends, 44.750 million litas of profit will be transferred to the statutory reserves, to the non-distributable reserve (for investments) - 10.369 million litas, to the distributable reserve totaling 2.058 million litas, of which tandem members will be assigned to the board 40 thousand litas, for support and other purposes according to the decisions of the Board - 2.018 million litas.
The state has a controlling interest of 85.7 percent in the statutory capital of 689.515 million litas in Lietuvos Energija. a block of shares managed by the Ministry of Economy. After the majority shareholder of the company, the state's largest 10.9 per cent shareholding is managed by the German company E.ON Energie, the remaining shareholders are small shareholders.
Last year, the profitability of Lietuvos Energija assets amounted to 7.7%, the return on capital was 13.8%, almost 55%. The total profit last year was obtained from the export of electricity (its exports amounted to 6.8 billion kWh, while export revenue was 307 million litas).
In carrying out the activities of the transmission network operator, the company transferred 8 billion kWh of electricity through high voltage electricity networks for the country's needs. As an independent supplier, 4.9 billion kWh of electricity was sold to free domestic customers and distribution network companies.
Last year, after reviewing the rating of Lietuvos Energija, from the negative BB + (negative), it was changed to a stable BB + (stable). Last year, loans to the credit institutions amounted to 184 million litas, loans were 100 million litas, liabilities to financial institutions decreased by 93 million litas per year.
This year the company plans to earn a net profit of 63 million litas. Less than last year, due to reduced electricity transmission costs, higher repair costs, higher amortization deductions, more will need to be spent on securing a power reserve.
This year, the energy company intends to borrow up to 135 million litas for refinancing loans and investment activity. During the year, it is planned to repay 158 million litas to the banks, 115 million litas are foreseen for the implementation of investment projects.
Copying, distributing, publishing ELTA information and photo information without the written consent of ELTA is prohibited.