0
https://www.lzinios.lt/lzinios/Lietuva/ko-reikia-kad-lrt-taptu-neitiketina/269130
Alina Ozić photo
A-A +
Monika Garbačiauskaitė-Budrienė, who heads the fourth month of the National Radio and Television of Lithuania (LRT), does not delay the change: heads of departments and journalists are changing, as well as management principles. From the new season we will not see the brightest LRT stars every day, but we will try to get new ones.
- Will the spectators beat LRT Television in the fall of the new season? - "Lietuvos Žinios" was firstly asked by the Director General of the LRT, Monika Garbačiauskaitė-Budrienė.
Monika Garbačiauskaitė-Budrienė: "LRT must not be like a third brother - a non-existent outdated government institution."
- There will be no radical changes, because television likes continuity. On the other hand, we did not have financial prospects for big changes as well, because we inherited a surplus budget for the acquisition of broadcasts. But in the future, we plan to better assess whether some of the shows are worth purchasing from external developers. For example, we will prepare the national selection of Eurovision for ourselves. We are strengthening the news service. The journalistic research department is being set up, and five journalists will be working in August. We strengthen regional divisions. We are planning next year to have a correspondent in Brussels.
Instead of "Attention" we will have five observers in Panorama. The "Right to Know" is restarted. Innovations - delivery to the family, delivery of consumer control, concerts by Lithuanian poetry songs, a series of films about the 13th of January heroes.
LRT faces - and in other TV projects
- Some changes have already caused a breakthrough. Liudvikas Gadeikis, chairman of the LRT Council, said that it would be a problem if the audience did not like being left in Edmundas Jakilaitis's "Attention Center". What will you do if there is a significant drop in your daily interview?
- We did not abandon E. Jakilaitis, he will be the LRT forum, we will show his "National expedition". By the way, we suggested that he remain one of the five daily interviewers, but he did not care.
In our opinion, such broadcasts should be created not by external producers, but by LRT Television News Service. We selected five experienced journalists, not worse than E. Jakilaitė. For spectators, this will provide more variety, a wider range of interlocutors. And ratings are not an absolute criterion, they are just one component. If it fails, we will consider what needs to be changed.
- However, what led to self-determination regarding E. Jakilaitis?
- One nuance was the price. When using internal resources, it costs less.
- But one out of five - Audrius Matonis is not an "internal resource". He recently released from the television news headlines.
- But this will be one in five. After dismissing A. Matonius from the administrative duties, I said that I hope that he will have a fun creative work on television.
- One of the main political winners, Rita Miliūtė, analyzes political processes in "Freedom TV", while E. Jakilaitis will "LRT Forum", but will launch a new project on Delfi TV? Commercial TVs would not allow this to happen to their "faces."
- The permission of R. Miliūtė to participate in the activities of "Laisvės TV" was given by the former administration of LRT. E. Jakilaitis did not allow us to enter "Attention Center" on other TV channels, but we do not value the work on the portal less strictly. Also, I do not think it will be analogous to the release.
Spending money on mission
- Song Festival, LRT World Cup Championship has been ranked top. But such events do not happen every day. Still, give preference to mission or popularity?
- Song festival and football LRT generated a lot of spectacularness - in the first half of July, LRT was the most viewed TV in Lithuania.
Of course, first of all - the mission, the content. But the question arises: where the mission begins, and the waste of money. Do you miss the mission, if you broadcast 500 people, are you only listening to relatives and friends? Now it's easy to get involved with the mission, and how much people do not care about it. One of the goals of this year is to create a system of content assessment and compliance with the mission. We are looking for the mission to be attractive and reach as many viewers, listeners and readers as possible.
- Lakmuso paper, more importantly - ratings or mission: will "Give it steam"?
- It will remain. It should be borne in mind that in Lithuania there are different people, Lithuania is not only Vilnius, but entertainment is not only a high culture. If a large part of the public performs a constituent function, we will not pick it up from viewers.
We do not get cheap popularity, our other task is to make things related to the mission appealing and to be seen by people. And if it's entertainment, it should be quality. For example, "Two Voices - One Heart" - entertainment is not about zvonke, but it was viewed and will be continued in the new season.
The second channel and portal will not be overlooked
- Are you looking for a new name for the second TV channel? Is it a necessity, or maybe somebody suspects, is it possible to dismiss workers?- It's not a land of redundant workers. Our arguments for changing the name are different. The contents of this channel do not fully correspond to the name of the culture, which causes various obstacles in positioning the brand to attract new viewers. We want the second channel not to be neglected by the child who falls to the one who does not fit into the first one, but to become a quality leisure, culture, sports television with documentaries, cinema evenings, concerts, wellness, and other new releases. Novelty - Every day before Panorama will be a cultural knowledge.
Trademark change is a way to note that the channel is resuming. The Council postponed the issue of the change of name until the next meeting, instructing us to discuss with the public. We will do it. If the council agrees, the second channel will start a new season in October with a new name.
- And there will not be cultural broadcasts on the first channel?
- Culture is and will be part of Panorama, and separate cultural programs will be on the second channel. We are thinking about the general edition of LRT cultural journalists. We also want cultural people, intellectuals to speak more often not only on issues of culture, but also on the phenomena of society, politics, everyday issues, so that they do not enter into their own space, but can contribute more to the development of the public eye.
- Will LRT Radio have fewer changes or little talk about them?
- We will launch the renewed radio net with the TV for the new season. From a communicative point of view, radio is unduly pushed to the second plan, although it is very important for impact and significance. We have already made updates: the program "10-12" was launched, in which we integrated the topical issues of political, social and cultural life. We want to update "Morning Sounds", and there will be other innovations.
- You have the most experience in managing the portal - you have been the chief editor of delfi.com for 17 years. What do you want to change on lrt.lt?
- It was the most disadvantaged area of LRT. Our goal is to have a modern, operational, reliable source of news and easy to use media. We have strengthened the site from the point of view of content. We are now managing the technical structure, this will allow us to have process control and save up to 70-80 thousand euros in three years time. Planned new portal and mobile application design. We will have an updated portal and mediation in September or October.
Next year we will have an open portal in English, now Lithuania as a state does not have an open source for free news in English.
The forerunner left financial surprises
- The plans you are talking about are worth the money. Your predecessor has been criticized for lack of transparency in the management of finance.
- We are faced with some surprises. As I said, the budget for purchases is overdrafted, with the end of the term increasing salaries for all employees. They must be raised and competitive, but also linked to goals and results. Salaries are covered with all kinds of accessories. In commercial structures, these issues are very clear, and LRT is a case where a LRT employee receives a salary and three times more than a royalty. The question is what a person then works during his work.
How will we survive until the next financial year? Let's keep going, but it's a shame that we are not free to make decisions. Regarding the acquisition of the programs, it would be desirable to have higher quality, but the funds have been exhausted. Moreover, some of the producers have signed such contracts that we will be obliged to broadcast the entire production.
We are now optimizing processes in the organization. Our goal is to release as much money as possible for quality products, good journalism, missions, training. In this organization we miss the systematic and strategic vision. For example, we buy expensive software and other TV equipment, but nobody asks what will happen after three to five years. Review purchasing plans, reduce unjustified purchases, because in the absence of a technology development strategy so far, a lot of purchases are expensive and not all of the equipment purchased is being exploited. We will make inventory of IT equipment. We have updated our procurement procedures, we have provided additional control points. Service contracts reviewed. We optimized the use of transport and already reduced costs. We perform an internal audit of employee functions to reduce duplication, non-performing functions. We are planning to connect all news services - primarily through systems for sharing information, and then for everyone working in one place. However, LRT buildings are not up-to-date and energy-efficient. We will do a study of real estate and its management prospects, and then we will decide whether the buildings will be renovated, demolished and new or built.
We are trying to increase the financial literacy of all employees so that everyone understands that there are budgets set up, there is financial discipline, and not so that I will come and ask and get more money.
We want to apply good European broadcaster management practices. But it's complicated and unproblematic processes.
- You trusted full transparency. Will you publicly publish estimates for contracts with producers?- The country looks one by one, and when it comes to legal matters, it turns out that not everything can be made public. We will not bid on each release as this will reduce our competitive advantage. But we can now post various information on the website. We will show the minimum and maximum prices of program competitions, the total value of the wires, the composition of the acquisition commission. We will also provide memos for the promotion of social and cultural information, KTS and equipment provision services.
- Do not hear what the Seimas commission is currently doing, investigating LRT financial activities.
- She is still asking for some documents, and in September she will publish the conclusions. It is very worrying about what they will be and whether there will be radical legislative amendments. It is possible to discuss a different management model, but one must keep in mind that LRT is not a railroad, but a specific media organization. It is very important to ensure its independence from politicians.
- Not only do you change a number of departmental executives, but you have also invited a few costly journalists. Existing staff proved insufficiently qualified?
- Mostly changing the guides. They have to meet the three key criteria for good leadership - excellence, loyalty and activity. I change leaders and try to change the speed - not at the ministry, but in private institutions. This organization could have been in the old style, but I think that after five years it would have faced big problems.
And if we are talking about salaries of professionals, then I will say that it is not good and cheap.
- By nominating LRT managers you have presented the most comprehensive program. Is the reality very different from the theory?
- The bottom line is the same, just the details start, for example, how to involve employees in the changes, because they have been used to looking for leaders for many years, and the initiative is very important. We want people to be motivated, we talk to them so that they get involved in change, have the stated goals.
But sometimes it feels like a mournful hour for this organization to live in a big bubble, it does not see how other analogous organizations live.
- Maybe it would be more interesting to be a commercial TV manager, then the changes would be faster?
- Speed is not everything. LRT is a great opportunity because you can invest in content, do not have to keep track of ratings, can test your ambition to make the national broadcaster unbelievable both for technological innovation and for content. What other structure could send ten operators to the Song Festival? We are now preparing for the Pope's visit. We can create such unique content as people can see through a national broadcaster. We will strive to expand the audience of all LRT channels, increasing the quality and relevance of the mission. Commercial TV, unfortunately, has gone down the staggering viewer, with no political waves left on the major channels, knowledge of "soft".
But LRT must not be like a third brother - a non-existent out-of-date government body. On the contrary, we need to be an example of a flexible, efficient organization.
NAME EL. PAPER (optional)
COMMENTARY
COMMENT
COMMENTS (5 of 21)
A real misfortune • 2018-07-18 13:55
"What needs a LRT to become incredible?" First of all, Budrienė and its level journalists should not be in charge of it. All the same ones who made money from taxpayers to Siauliai, leave it a little bit for a while. What are the changes here? Only to the bad ones. when the Cultural Channel is required to "open" a wider circle. Knowing what Budriennes turned into Delphi, nobody would be surprised if the cultural channel was attributed to pornographic footage with ivanos and pylons.
D.M. • 2018-07-18 13:31
1. In order to move LRT to a higher qualification level, it is necessary for the management team to capture LRT spectators for a week - if after LRT spectators they will not cook them (that is, they will love everything and they will do well) - will mean that LRT will continue to lead poorly ( low level) team. 2. The LRT must act according to the rules of law, and not according to the opinions of friends / stooges or relatives - only then will qualitative diversity and real interest be. 3. It is obvious that until now, LRT was broadcasting to the public what they liked and therefore "translated and perceived" to a shameful level. 4. The LRT must itself be able to create high-performance broadcasts, etc., and not to buy for our funds from commercial companies.
Garbačiaevskaya does not understand that • 2018-07-18 12:36
The LRT should be a solid vestry, not a tropical moorland swamp.
why • 11/27/2012 11:39 am
LRT re-broadcasts commercial advertising? Why are not so good in the morning so few reports and practical, home-grown-up reporter-reporters from Lithuania?
Interesting • 2018-07-18 09:57
said he would be a correspondent in Brussels. Is this place foreseen by the head of the former LRT council, Peculiar Schnapper?
ALL COMMENTS