2017 At the Ordinary General Meeting of Shareholders of AB Lithuanian breeding stock held on April 27, it was decided to allocate 0,0146 EUR dividends (without taxes) to one shareholder of AB "Lietuvos veislininkystes" with a nominal value of 0.29 EUR.
Dividends will be paid to those shareholders who at the end of the property rights accounting day were shareholders of AB Lietuvos veislininkystė.
Dividends will be paid to shareholders from 2017. May 01 AB Lithuanian Breeding Company at the Marijampole branch office at Trakėnų g. 14, Trakiškiu k. , Marijampole Municipality, Republic of Lithuania or on request, dividends will be transferred to the personal account specified in the shareholder's request. You can submit the applications in writing (Lithuanian breeding stock company at Tilžės 335, Sutkunai village, LT76116 Šiauliai district) or by e-mail info@veislita.lt.
Dividend Taxation Procedure:
Dividends paid to natural persons of the Republic of Lithuania are taxed at the rate of 15%. personal income tax rate.
additional information
Tel. 841 507100;
Tel. 8343 94111
Director Gediminas Valiulis