0
https://www.15min.lt/pasaulis-kiseneje/naujiena/kelioniu-pulsas/6-naujos-unesco-saugomos-vietos-europoje-637-1002474
UNESCO annually places protected sites of cultural, historical or scientific significance on the World Heritage List. This year 19 new such sites were published, 6 of them in Europe.
Denmark: Aasivissuit, Greenland
Jens Fog Jensen Photo / Aasivissuit, Greenland
These Inuit hunting places are outside the circle of the polar circle. It is well-known in the territory of 62 thousand square kilometers, where fjords and lakes lie.
Germany: Landscapes of Hedeby and Danevirk
Photo by Rainer Heidenreich / Landscapes of Hedeby and Danevirk
In the archaeological complex of the Hedeby and Danevirk Complex in Germany, the legacy of the old trading city remains - the remains of the road, cemetery, port, buildings. Their age reaches the 1st and 2nd centuries.
Spain: Medina Azahara
Photo by M. Pijuán / Medina Azahara
The ruins of the Arabian Muslim Medieval Palace in Andalusia reach the Xth century, but have long been forgotten - re-discovered only in the 20th century. early in the year. There are still roads, bridges, buildings and an abundance of decorated walls.
Italy: Ivrea
123rf.com's photo / Ivrea
The industrial center of Italy was placed on the list as a "modern social project" - UNESCO recognized its scientific and cultural significance. Ivrea has been named as a contemporary vision of the relationship between industrial production and architecture.
Germany: Naumburg Cathedral
123rf.com's photo / Cathedral of Nashumburg
From 1028 The stationary cathedral admires romantic and gothic architecture. Inside it - the sculptures of human builders and many works of art from its builders.
France: Puy Mountains
Photo by Pierre Soissons / Mountains
These 40-km-long mountains were once volcanoes. Their highest point is the lava dome, which is almost 1.5 thousand meters above sea level. The mountains are beautifully green and are truly paradise for hiking in mountainous areas.