0
https://www.15min.lt/verslas/naujiena/transportas/nuplauke-tukstanciai-siltu-darbo-vietu-viskas-del-skrydzio-i-londona-667-1001992
The order of the Economy and Transport Ministers provides for support for flights to London City Airport. The support of this flight - 2.1 million euros in three years - was also promised by Vilnius municipality. The Lithuanian airports organizing the competition will firstly be waiting for the lack of willingness to carry out such flights without support. If such an airline does not exist, financial support will be provided, the amount of which is not yet disclosed.
In the vital direction of the London City government, the government has read the analysis of the "Invest in Lithuania", which states that so far, due to the lack of attractive businessmen for the flight to London, Lithuania has lost 186 million euros of value added per year. And if the flight to London does not occur in the near future, the country may lose another 254 million euros of potential value added per year.
The analysis says that due to the lack of business segment contact with London, Lithuania has already lost at least 9 foreign direct investment projects. These projects would have created an added value of EUR 186 million per year. Their developers have chosen other places due to poor traffic, which has led to the loss of 4.3 thousand jobs in Lithuania.
Lost jobs
At present, Invest in Lithuania is working with 35 foreign direct investment projects, which are the most relevant business segment for Vilnius-London. The potential value of these projects is more than EUR 254 million per year. These projects in Lithuania can create almost 6.5 thousand jobs.
It is noted that among these projects there are 24 business centers, 10 technological projects and one production project.
Currently, Wizzair and Ryanair fly to London to Stansted and Luton Airports. For businessmen, this is not appropriate, as cheap airlines fly mostly to emigrants and tourists, while business classes do not exist on these planes. In addition, they are flown to further airports, so it takes longer to reach the city center.
The analysis suggests that most of the business segment opts for indirect flights to London. 19,1 thousand passengers fly to London over the years through Riga, Copenhagen, Frankfurt and other cities.
"Invest in Lithuania" does not specify to which airport - Hitrou, Gatwick or Sith - it would be best to fly for business. It was not explained by the authors of the idea of supporting the route to the London Sith.