ve> News> Economy> Economic News
Economic News
The state-owned joint-stock company Lietuvos paštas, for the first time in history, paid out dividends to shareholders of 589,082 litas.
According to Lina Minderienė, Director General of the Lithuanian Post, Lithuania earned a profit after a four-year break. According to audited data, net profit of 736 thousand litas was earned. EBITDA (profit before taxes, interest, depreciation and amortization) was positive - LTL 9,411 thousand.
Last year the company's sales revenue amounted to more than 183 million litas. It is 5.2 percent. more than in 2010.
Compared to 2010, the volume of services rendered increased by 4.5%. The largest part of sales revenue is the income received for the provision of universal postal services - 49.4%. Income from incoming services compared to 2010 increased by 11.8%.
The highest growth was recorded in revenue from retail and non-promotional advertising - by 45%, respectively. and 24%
100 percent The shares of Lietuvos paštas are managed by the state represented by the Ministry of Transport and Communications.
Tags: lithuanian mail, dividends
It is strictly forbidden to copy and publish information published by "Western Express" on other websites, in traditional media or otherwise use without the written permission of publishers. Content usage rules.
Your comment
Today VE.lt read