1
http://www.diena.lt/naujienos/verslas/imoniu-pulsas/husqvarna-lietuva-beveik-visa-pelna-skyre-dividendams-762270?full
2016-07-26 16:51:00
BNS info
Text Size:
Print
Garden gardener Husqvarna gained 10.499 million euros in revenue last year in Lithuania - 2.1%. less than in 2014 (10.724 million euros).
Husqvarna Lithuania's net profit for the year remained virtually unchanged at EUR 246.1 thousand, according to a report submitted to the Center of Registers. The company plans to pay out dividends of 237 thousand euros this year.
The company's sales cost per annum declined by 2.4%. up to 8.5 million euros, operating expenses - 2.7 per cent. to 1.8 million euros, pre-tax profit - 1.1 percent. up to 297.8 thousand euros.
100 percent The shares of the Lithuanian company are owned by the Swedish Husqvarna Holding. The company located in Kaunas sells equipment for maintenance of giras and parks and construction equipment.


Ads
Notify me of updates to
news
Portal
guest
Ask
a specialist
Discussions
weather
TV
the program
Dating
Games
Horoscopes
Novelty
RSS feed
Facebook
Twitter
The non-alcoholic "alcohol" fashion is spreading in Lithuania
Already more and more Lithuanians drink alcohol in their favorite drinks - they are not necessarily needed. In order to choose from an ever-expanding range of non-alcoholic beverages, residents of the country are increasingly choosing exactly the non-alcoholic beer, cider ...
1
Western Union will provide an annual study funding for a postgraduate student
More and more businesses are seeking cooperation with higher education institutions - engaging in the process of study organization, providing themes for final projects, admitting students to practice, setting up scholarships or assigning study f ...
Lithuanian dairy products conquer the Canary Islands market
In July, the delegation of the largest milk producer in Spain, Jose Sanchez Penate SA, visited Lithuania. Spain has visited dairy farms, Marijampole Dairy Tin factories and production workshops, which ...
Top Sport Cheat Clients?
The soccer world championship has also attracted paymen attention. But those who have made the final goal to put their head in the final will not do anything. The betting organizers explain, though the goal is scored by the head, but it skr ...
8
Norfa in Klaipėda smiles customers?
Expirational products in Norfos stores are becoming more and more noticeable - in a very short time, several cases have been recorded in which customers of Klaipėda purchased obsolete food. This is also verified by the ...
19th
Maxima establishes practical training centers for food production
The largest employer in the country - the retail chain Maxima establishes practical training centers for food production in nine cities of Lithuania, where experienced and professional Maximos employees will train the required qualifications ...
Vegetarian lovers will be happy - this summer, harvest prices are lower
The warm season is a real refreshment for fresh vegetables. In summer, buyers are attracted not only by their wide range of products, but also by attractive prices. Although the price of vegetable prices in July last year is far too much for buyers ...
3
The Center of Registers is a new corruption prevention office
The Center for Prevention and Internal Investigation of the Registry Center is being directed by Giedrius Cininas, who until then was the Chief Inspector of the Ministry of the Interior. ...
3
Early hot summer changed Lithuanian shopping habits
This summer, a very early summer, changed the Lithuanian shopping habits. As Maxim's sales figures show, in the middle of the summer, Lithuanians more than last year bought ice cream, fresh vegetables and fruits ...
Lithuania, for the first time in history, has sold grain directly to Saudi Arabia
Saudi Arabian State Grain Organization has bought 115 thousand wheat from the Lithuanian grain trading and export company Agrorodeo during an international competition on Monday. Lithuanian capital company Agrorodeo & ldqu ...
More articles