1
http://www.ve.lt/naujienos/ekonomika/ekonomikos-naujienos/klasco-akcininkams-bus-mokami-dividendai1/
On Friday, AB Klaipėda Stevedoring Company (KLASCO) shareholders meeting decided to allocate 26.2 million litas to dividends held by Achema Group. Shareholders will be paid LTL 2.07 for one nominal share.
At the KLASCO shareholders' meeting, the audit company UAB Ernst & Young Baltic confirmed that in 2010 the company was profitable. The revenue from the main activities last year was 126.51 million litas, in 2009 - 115.63 million litas.
According to KLASCO Chairman of the Board, Bronislaw Lubis, the company is implementing an approved investment program this year. At the end of the summer, it is planned to complete the expansion of the grain terminal. Construction of a new fertilizer warehouse will also be started.
"KLASCO is working successfully, providing stable wages and social guarantees to its employees, a new collective agreement has been signed for this two-year period, dividends paid to shareholders, about 25 million litas is planned for this year's investments," said Lubys after the shareholders' meeting.
A new board of directors was approved for the 4-year term of office of shareholders. It also includes Audrius Paužas, General Manager of the company.
KLASCO, which employs 683 people, is the largest Klaipeda port stevedoring company, which transships one third of all cargo loaded at the port - 10.3 million tons.