0
https://www.lzinios.lt/lzinios/Lietuva/del-pensiju-reformos-kyla-i-nauja-musi/269131
Mykolas Majauskas: "We are changing the pension accumulation system, although it should be stable and reliable." Alina Ožič (LŽ) photo
A-A +
Foreclosure is proposed for the pension reform adopted at the last days of the parliamentary session - opposition representatives promise to appeal to the Constitutional Court (CC). He will be asked to clarify if the reorganization is in compliance with the country's basic law. The initiators of the changes, in turn, plan to conduct another parliamentary inquiry.
Representatives of the Seimas opposition this week expect to collect 29 parliamentarians' signatures following appeals to the CC on the reform of the pension system, which should come into force from next year, with the provisions of the Constitution. It is explained that the reorganization was adopted in a hurry, without detailed discussion, and certain aspects of it might be anti-constitutional.
The opposition also criticizes other reforms adopted at the last days of the parliamentary session - taxes, networks of health care institutions.
Conservatives promise to cancel everything
According to one MP Mykolas Majauskas, the initiator of the appeal to the CC, the Guardians of the Constitution will be asked to present conclusions on several aspects of the reform, the most important of which are the legitimate expectations of citizens. "We are changing the pension accumulation system, although it should be stable and reliable. If the law comes into force, it turns out that any thing is illegal, there will be serious damage to the entire accumulation system, which will further reduce the confidence of people in the second stage, "he said.
According to M. Majauskas, the CC should answer whether the intention of the compulsory population to be included in the private pension accumulation with the main law of the country and to allow Sodra to become the sole annuity payer is not compromised.
The opposition also criticizes other reforms adopted at the last days of the parliamentary session - taxes, networks of health care institutions. Gabriel Landsbergis, Senior Member of the Parliamentary Homeland Union-Lithuania Christian Democrats, assured that conservatives who came to power would revoke "peasant" reforms. Speaking about the adoption of tax reform, he said that, although from next year, everyone would earn more, but the state budget would lose EUR 320 million in 2019 and EUR 2 billion after three years.
"God forbid, the crisis, if someone breaks a ship of Lithuania or the world. We do not have a reserve, no pillows on which we could fall and which would protect us. Now we can say that we, having come to the leader, will cancel the "peasant" reforms because there is no other way ", - said G. Landsbergis.
The last changes
According to Stasys Jakeliūnas, chairman of the Seimas Budget and Finance Committee, the colleagues' intentions regarding the pension reform to apply to the TC show that they may not understand what changes are planned to be implemented. He was considering that the opposition wanted to draw attention to it. On the other hand, the parliamentarian also considered possible representation of the interests of the private sector.
S. Jakeliūnas did not predict whether the KT will take a pension reform. In his view, several years ago, changes in the second pillar of pension accumulation were not optimal, they needed to be improved. "The problems are all clear and clear to everyone, but not everyone wants to make or understand these changes. If it were the way it is now, sooner or later, current pensioners may have initiated an appeal to the CC or elsewhere, because their interests are vulnerable, with their funds being financed by the second stage. Another thing is that most of the people involved in the second pillar do not become pensioners. About 90 percent and the more they receive a lump sum payment. At that time, their "Sodra" pension decreases. Their interests are vulnerable. If the opposition does not know that this is a fundamental problem to be addressed, then it is only regrettable, "stressed the MP.
Gabriel Landsbergis: "Do not God, a crisis if someone breaks a ship of Lithuania or the world. We have no reserve, no pillows on which we can fall and which will protect us. "
In addition, S. Jakeliūnas mentioned that if a group of Seimas members approached the CC, he would initiate a parliamentary inquiry into the Seimas and explain how the second pillar of pension accumulation appeared and what influenced it for politicians from 2002 to the present. Focus on the 2012-2013 period. "If anyone believes that their rights have been violated, I will consider launching an investigation into how the pension fund business influenced the political system, media decisions, for example, bought the wire," he asserted.
Stop Sodra transfers
At the end of June, the Seimas blessed the changes in the pension accumulation system. They refuse to transfer the part of the Sodra contribution to pension funds, modify the private accumulation formula, and the pensioner annuity payer is expected to be appointed solely by Sodra. According to the reformers, innovations will help to organize the pension system by decoupling private accumulation in pension funds from accumulation in Sodra. Critics claim that restructuring will only aggravate the situation of future pensioners.The pension accumulation reform plan foresees that next year Sodra transfers to the second tier funds will be discontinued, but by 1%. reducing Sodra's contribution and the personal income tax (GPM) rate will give residents the opportunity to allocate these funds to private pension accumulation. 2% will be abandoned when changing the system. SODRA contributions to second pillar pension funds and a new accumulation formula (4 + 2). The contribution will be 4%. pension accumulation of the participant's income and 2% average wage (VMU) bonus from the state budget. After tax consolidation, when wages are rising on paper, accrual rates will change somewhat, and the accumulation formula will be as follows: 3%. personal remuneration and 1.5% state support from VMU size. According to the adopted changes from January 2019, all current accumulators and non-residents under 40 will be included in the accumulation of pensions, giving the right to say no.
NAME EL. PAPER (optional)
COMMENTARY
COMMENT
COMMENTS (3)
... • 2018-07-18 10:30
does not have any forced payouts to funds. The funds are private, to separate them entirely from the soda, budget.
Circus • 2018-07-17 21:31
Maybe you had a break in the beginning. by court decisions, for the sake of ignoring the laws .. It is important to imitate the activity. It is possible to be honest with the content of the discussion, but the vupa try to hide / conceal the interests of the lobbyists on the trial of politicians? ....
The above • 2018-07-17 15:40
Maybe you need a baby's maturity as much.