1
http://www.vzinios.lt/article/20150327/Article/303279974
Posted: 03-03-2015
Last updated 29/05/2015 11:52
Liucija Zubrutė "Business Knowledge"
The Board of the Klaipėda Stevedoring Company (KLASCO), owned by the Achema Group, has approved a dividend amount of 4,055 million EUR - 0.32 EUR per share in front of taxes, the company announces.
The main operating income of KLASCO last year amounted to 44.312 million euros, profit before taxes - 7.410 million euros. 2013 The company earned 8.312 million euros in profit. The largest port stevedoring company in 2014. 12.2 million tons of cargoes were reloaded, turnover was slightly behind from 2013, when it reached 12.4 million tons. "Maritime trade is developing in cycles. Last year, we planed a similar flow of cargo and revenue as in 2013, but the slowdown in trade between East and West due to the sanctions imposed has affected the work of our ro-ro terminal, and since the summer the indicators of this unit have fallen, "says Audrius Paužas, General Manager of KLASCO. - The turnover of fertilizers, cereals and general cargo remained the same as in previous years. According to him, the company modernizes the handling technique, designs new warehouse and site areas in the Vitesse quarter, will take new projects, and will be able to redefine the new shipments that we seek. However, it requires more time and investment. " Smelte peninsula, therefore, in the coming years, hopes to return to the previous level of loading and rise above. Last KLASCO opened a new bulk fertilizer warehouse. Investments in this object amounted to over 2 million euros. A new investment phase is scheduled for 2016-2018. 2014 At the end of the year, the company employed 720 people.
Follow the first experiences of car testing, news, share your opinion and experience on the Facebook page of VŽ Transportas
write a comment
Get your FREE TRANSPORT weekly in your email:
Choose the FREE weekly you are interested in:
Business management
Marketing
Finance and Accounting
Market
Sales
My business
Trade
Construction and NT
Industry
Agroversla
Transport
Technologies
Leisure time
Most important news for the day:
Please note that the laws of the Republic of Lithuania prohibit:
to call for the change of the constitutional order of the Republic of Lithuania;
to encourage the encroachment upon the sovereignty of the Republic of Lithuania, the integrity of its territory, and political independence;
to instigate war or hate, bully, dishonor, incite to discriminate, violate, physically cope with a group of people or a person belonging to it by reason of age, gender, sexual orientation, ethnicity, race, nationality, nationality, language, origin, social status, belief, convictions , attitudes or religion;
distribute, promote or promote pornography, as well as promote and / or promote sexual services, sexual distortions;
promote and / or promote harmful addictions and narcotic or psychotropic substances. It is forbidden to distribute misinformation and information that defames, offends a person humiliating his honor and dignity. It is prohibited to disseminate information that violates the presumption of innocence and impedes the impartiality of the judiciary.
The published comment is the responsibility of the reader who posted it, which may, because of its content, be prosecuted for criminal, administrative or civil liability. In the comment, we do not directly display the IP address of the author of the comment, but it may be transmitted to law enforcement agencies in accordance with the procedure established by the laws of the Republic of Lithuania.
All contents published on the website vz.lt are property of UAB Verslo Žinios unless otherwise specified. Reproduction, publicity or archiving of content on servers from other countries without the written consent of the company is prohibited.
When quoting, reference to the source is required. The volume of the cited text must not exceed 500 (five hundred) stamps.
You can use the following on your or your company's website without a separate agreement:
* article headline
* the first paragraph of the article (in articles of the vz.lt it is distinguished in the chosen font);
* Continue to follow the link to the full article on the website vz.lt.
The logo of a project or a sponsor / partner of the rubric at the heading of the article is the content created by journalists of the "Verslo žinios" usually. A sponsor / partner of a project or rubric does not contribute to the creation of this content.
Sponsored Content, Business Tribune, Business Workshop - Content Created by Advertiser. Journalists at "Business Knowledge" do not contribute to the creation of this content.
The anniversary of the event is the content created by the advertiser to mark the anniversary of the company. Journalists at "Business Knowledge" do not contribute to the creation of this content.
Expert Insight - The content created by the advertiser. Journalists at "Business Knowledge" do not contribute to the creation of this content.
On this site we use cookies. They help identify affiliated users, measure audience size and browsing habits; so we can change the site to make it more comfortable for you.
Read more
I Agree More