0
https://www.15min.lt/naujiena/aktualu/pasaulis/d-trumpas-sutinka-kad-rusija-kisosi-i-rinkimus-teigia-ne-taip-isreiskes-minti-57-1002626
"I thought I spoke very clearly, but I just reviewed the statement of statement ... I realized that something needs to be explained. The sentence was supposed to sound like this: I have no reason to think why this could not be Russia, "T. Trump said Tuesday at the White House.
At a press conference during a press conference on Monday, speaking about possible Moscow interference in the 2016 presidential election, Truman said: "Putin has just said that this is not Russia. I will say this: I have no reason to think that this could be Russia. "
On Tuesday, Truman also said that he "fully trusted and supported" the US intelligence community, said he was confident in its conclusions that Russia was attempting to influence the US elections. True, the president added that other countries could do it.
"I think that while Russia's actions have had no effect on the outcome of the elections, let me explain that I agree with the findings of our intelligence community that Russia intervened in the 2016 elections," said the White House Chief.
He added that "there could be other people, there are many people".
Vice President Mike Pence and Secretary of State Mike Pompeo privately met with the president and urged him to explain his comments during a press conference in Helsinki, NBC News said.
VIDEO: Politicians appreciate Trump and Putin's meeting: no major implications for international politics
In Helsinki, Democrats and Republicans have condemned him to D. Trumpe that he did not trust the findings of the intelligence community that Moscow tried to influence the election.
The president made this statement just days after the Special Investigator Robert Mueller had accused 12 Russian intelligence officers of interfering in the elections.
VIDEO: T. Trump meeting with V. Putin: "The world wants us to agree"
On Tuesday, Mr Trumpa said that the Russian intervention agency was seriously considering and promised to prevent attempts to affect the elections in the future.
Do not resign other statements
The President did not revoke other statements that clearly declared the belief in Putin's "extremely strong and condescending" denial, questioned the conclusions of his own intelligence agencies, and provided discredited conspiracy theories on interference with elections.
Moreover, due to the deterioration of relations between the two countries, he blamed the previous American leaders and not Russia's destabilizing actions in the United States and elsewhere in the world. D. Trumpa also did not speak about other problematic statements made during a week-long journey in Europe.
Reuters / Scanpix Photo / Mitch McConnell, Majority Republican Majority Senate
Formerly, the Senate majority leader, M. McConnell, thought it necessary to reassure America's allies in Europe, with whom Truman had leeches during his stormy journey last week, and stated straight: "European countries are our friends, and Russians are not."
Chuck Schummer, Senate Democrat, said Truman was trying to "squeeze out" after commenting on standing next to Putin.
"It's been late for 24 hours and (said) outside the place," said Ch.Schumer.
Reuters / Scanpix / Alyssa Milano near the White House
At the launch, hundreds of activists, led by lawyer Michael Avenatti and actress Alyssa Milano, protested near the White House and screamed "Traitor!".